{"question": "So tell me what makes you interested in this industry?", "answer": "Well, I've always wanted to be a product designer since I was a little girl. I, of course, didn't know what the job of a product designer was then, but I was fascinated by people like Steve Jobs and knew I wanted to make products that changed the world. I didn't focus on this so much in college. I priority was kind of having a college experience and I'm so lucky I got to do that. But now it's time to start adulting. And I really think this is the perfect place for me to grow my career. I know that if someone took a chance on me, I would succeed. Let's talk about what's working here. First of all, the candidate comes across as confident and someone who has genuine interest in the position. But she needs to be more specific. Her point about prioritizing a college experience could raise some flags.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0187}
{"question": "If she didn't study design in college, where has she learned it? And how does she know she'll be successful in the role?", "answer": "She should be explicit. Hiring managers want you to be concise and specific when talking about yourself. And let's see her redo that last part. While I didn't study product design in college, I am familiar with the relevant design tools used in this role. And I've taken online courses to learn more. I'm really excited about this opportunity. I'm a self-starter. And when I don't know the answer, I'm not afraid to ask. Hmm, much better. Now let's see how another applicant responds to a similar question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How has your experience prepared you for this role?", "answer": "I'm committed to working at a mission-driven organization like this one. I'm passionate about marketing. I haven't had any professional experience, though, which I hope is okay. Jumping in real quick to say, yes, it's okay if you don't have professional experience in the area you're applying for. You do have other relevant experiences and transferable skills that you can communicate during an interview. With that in mind, let's see this candidate kick off his answer a little differently.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0115}
{"question": "Are you using the Indeed mobile app?", "answer": "The app is free and makes it easy to apply right from your phone. Click the link below or just search Indeed in the app store. Well, first of all, I am committed to working at a mission-driven organization like this one. I'm passionate about marketing. My undergrad coursework focused on understanding digital culture and the importance of representation in advertising. And I'm eager to apply what I've learned to a professional setting. Also, your company values really resonate with me. They make you stand out from some of the other organizations I was considering. I was listening to a recent speech the CEO gave. And when she was talking about how we need to innovate faster and disrupt our own industry before others disrupt us, I thought to myself, this is a place I would be lucky to contribute to. Yes, there's a ton of good stuff in this response. First, referring to your academics is a great thing to do when you don't have professional experience in the area you're applying for. I also love that this candidate referenced his value alignment with the company. But what I really found impressive was how he read up on the CEO prior to the interview. He did his homework. It's a small detail that really goes the extra mile and differentiates you from other candidates.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0043}
{"question": "What was your biggest obstacle in college? And how did you overcome it?", "answer": "I'm a computer science major and prior to college, I had absolutely zero STEM experience. So when I was first learning to co-java, let's just say it was bumpy. Things just weren't clicking for me and I knew I needed to make a change. So I started a support group with some other students. I put in hours of extra work and practice time on my own. And I'm proud to say after a lot of hard work, not only did I become proficient in Java and Python, but I also was able to tutor some first-year students. I know that my career will be full of learning opportunities like this. I'm eager to face some head-on and continue to improve. Wow! This answer checked so many boxes. She was confident, concise, and kept the answer professional. You definitely don't want to talk about personal challenges in school. She showed that she has the skills to identify problems and create solutions, not to mention a willingness to pay it for it. If she has time to tutor and continue to do well in her classes, she must have some strong time management skills too. Well done! And now, here's a question that pretty much everyone is bound to hear at one point or another. So that's all I have. I'm asking all the questions. I really want to thank you for taking out the time to come in. And see you today. You're very well-versed.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0193}
{"question": "And before we wrap, do you have any questions for me?", "answer": "Um, yeah.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.5}
{"question": "What made you decide to go into sales?", "answer": "Oh, the interview isn't over. This is an essential moment. The hiring manager wants to see if you're a critical thinker and if you're curious about the organization. Asking, what did you go into sales? Helps build a relationship, but doesn't give you insight into the company. Here are some good questions to ask.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What's your favorite thing about working here? What are some of the qualities that would make an entry-level candidate most successful in this role? What advice would you give your younger self starting out in this industry?", "answer": "We've covered a lot here that will help you ace your first interview. Everyone starts with an entry-level job. We've all been there, including myself. The fact of the matter is that you have more relevant experience than you think. And the tools to tell a story that proves it.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Was this video helpful?", "answer": "It's so make sure to like and subscribe. You look like you're eager. I'm very good at being eager. You need to be willing. I can do work. I'm gonna do it. I've got to work before.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0714}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "My name is Richard and I have applied for this engineering manager position because the skills qualities and experience I have are a strong match for the job description. I have an excellent level of technical competence. I have a solid background in engineering and I have outstanding project management skills. In previous positions I always focused on helping my employer meet their commercial and financial objectives. Now as your engineering manager, I will achieve success through strong communication and interpersonal skills by making good decisions that are in the best interests of the business and by delegating to my team of engineers to ensure as much work gets completed as is achievable. If you hire me as your engineering manager, you will see a fast and immediate impact and I will always act as a loyal and hardworking member of the organisation. So that is a brilliant response that gives you something to work with when you create your answer to that first engineering manager interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.006}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Now you can either pause the video if you want to and take a note of the questions and answers as we work through them together or if you wait. I will soon tell you where you can download my full set of 21 engineering manager interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are covering today during this presentation.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Question number two, what makes a good engineering manager?", "answer": "Now there are several qualities that help make an engineering manager perform to a high standard being commercially aware is one of them being able to manage and lead a team of engineers is another. So let's look at the others in the following answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0217}
{"question": "What makes a good engineering manager?", "answer": "Four things make a good engineering manager. Experience within the industry you are working in technical competence being commercially aware and the ability to complete projects and tasks quickly and in line with predetermined specifications. A good engineering manager is an all-rounder and someone who has the relevant management and leadership capabilities to lead a team of engineers to achieve very specific goals within set time frames. Now it is essential that an engineering manager supports the senior management team and he or she works towards achieving the commercial and financial goals of the business. That's a very concise and confident answer that helps you to stand out during your engineering manager interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you but when you're ready if you click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video it will take you through to my website pacmaintovue.com and you can download my full set of 21 engineering manager interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones covered during this presentation today but here is the next question to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to work here as an engineering manager?", "answer": "So this might be posed as why do you want to work for us. Now this engineering manager interview question is assessing how much research you have carried out into their organization and whether your motivations for working there are genuine. So here's another great example answer to assist you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0392}
{"question": "Why do you want to work here as an engineering manager?", "answer": "I want to work for you as an engineering manager because I am seeking employment with a forward thinking innovative company that wants to continually grow and thrive within its industry. I am a passionate engineering manager and I want the time I do spend at work to be put to good use. I conducted lots of research into your company before applying for this position and three things stood out. Your track record of achievement, the way you are always pushing the boundaries and seeking to improve and the fact that you are a responsible organization that wants to build a sustainable and progressive business. Now I genuinely believe my passion and the enthusiasm and levels of commitment will be a good match for your organization. That's an have a really good stand out answer that helps you to pass your engineering manager interview. Here is the next question. Tell us about a time when your team members disagreed on a technical solution or implementation.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How did you handle the situation?", "answer": "Now this tough engineering manager interview question assesses your level of authority and whether you can turn a disagreement into a positive outcome for the engineering project you are leading. So here's another great answer to help you. Tell us about a time when your team members disagreed on a technical solution or implementation.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0182}
{"question": "How did you handle the situation?", "answer": "I was working in a previous engineering manager position managing a fast-paced product development project with a team of six people. Now during the initial project brief, two of the engineers disagreed on the best way to implement their particular element of the project. I took control of the discussion and I asked them individually to outline their proposal including the benefits of approaching things their way. I followed up with probing questions, asking them to provide real life examples of where it had worked previously. Now after listening to them I chose the one that I felt would give the best outcome based on the project's specification. As the engineering manager I will always listen to my team's suggestions to find the best way forward and I will never be afraid to take control and make decisive decisions that will help us to quickly achieve our objectives. It's a really good answer. You are using your team's experience to help you make the right decision based on the engineering project you are leading. Here is a difficult question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "If you were recruiting an engineer for your team, what would you look for?", "answer": "Now part of your responsibility as the engineering manager will be to recruit and hire engineers. Therefore, to do this competently you need to know what to look for in engineering applicants. So here's a really good model answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0233}
{"question": "If you were recruiting an engineer for your team, what would you look for?", "answer": "Here we go. There are several characteristics and traits I would look for when recruiting an engineer. Teamwork and technical competence are the first two. I would want someone who puts the needs of the team first, someone who can collaborate in a professional manner without conflict and someone who has the expertise and experience to perform their duties quickly and to the required standard. I would recruit an engineer who has a proven track record of problem solving, someone who can analyse data to develop real-life engineering solutions and someone who possesses excellent communication skills. The engineer is attitude to work, their attention to detail skills and their commitment to the organization would be other, crucial factors in deciding on the right candidate. Finally, I would want to hire someone who is passionate about engineering and who takes responsibility for their own continuous learning and development. So that shows you know what to look for in the right engineering applicant and you are not afraid to hire the right person.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0116}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "Now this question is guarantee to come up during your engineering manager interview, structure your response so that you give four or five strengths and then just one weakness that is not a match for the job description. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0426}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "My strengths include my project scheduling and completion skills. I am renowned for delivering time sensitive projects to high standards and within budget. I'm a confident engineering manager who makes difficult decisions and who holds his team accountable. Other important strengths include my communication skills and my levels of commercial awareness. I will work with the company directors and executives to ensure all commercial engineering objectives are met. My weakness includes the fact that I find it hard to say no to people and I don't like asking other people for help. Now since I can remember, I tend to say yes when people ask me for help or assistance even if I don't have the capacity to take on the extra work.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0079}
{"question": "However, when it comes to me asking for other people's help, I prefer to figure things out for myself which is not always the right approach to take.", "answer": "I am the type of engineering manager who believes there is always something new to learn and I will always be open to constructive feedback from my seniors and directors and from other people who I respect. That's a really good answer to that common but difficult interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "Now the next thing to do is please make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. It will take you through to my website here, passmaintoview.com and you can download my full set of 21 engineering manager interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones I have just worked through today. It's a brilliant guide you can see. I'm covering lots of questions here that come up often during all types of engineering manager interview. So make sure you check out that guide right now on the website passmaintoview.com by clicking that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Finally, don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. If you click the link in the description below the video you can connect with me directly on LinkedIn. It's always good to connect with like-minded professionals.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0129}
{"question": "Don't forget to subscribe to the channel as I said at the start.", "answer": "Lots of you are passing your interviews and please give the video a thumbs up. Thank you so much for your support. Finally, I wish you all the best for passing your engineering manager interview and have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.025}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake and also tell me about a time when you worked in a team.", "answer": "Those are really difficult interview questions to answer correctly.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, if you have a job interview coming up soon for any role or organization, you will have to answer them.", "answer": "So make sure you stay tuned. Watch the presentation from start to finish because I promise to help you be the standout candidate. And to achieve that goal, this is what I'm going to cover. So I will give you a list of tough behavioral interview questions. I strongly recommend you prepare for. I will then give you an example scripted answers to all of the questions to help you pass your job interview. I will also give you a perfect structure to use and easy to remember structure that you can use when answering any type of behavioral interview question. And I will then tell you how you can access further, downloadable resources, including the answers to help you be the standout candidate at your job interview. And just very quickly, if you are new to the channel, please make sure you hit that subscribe button. Literally thousands of you are passing your job interviews and I don't want you to miss out. I can only help you if you are subscribed and please give the video a like because that tells me you find these tutorials useful and also it motivates me to create more content for you. Thank you very much.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0146}
{"question": "So to begin with, how do you answer behavioral interview questions?", "answer": "Well my advice is to make sure you use the star technique. Take a note of this. Now star stands for situation, task, action and result. Now the star technique is recognized by all hiring managers. It's a brilliant format to use when answering any type of behavioral interview question. And it allows you to easily remember your scenarios and your answers. And also it will help you to get the highest scores possible for each answer to the behavioral interview questions. So we need to utilize this when responding to all of the questions in this tutorial. So just to recap, when using the star technique of situation, task, action and result, you start off your answer to the interview question and you tell the interviewer the situation you were faced with. You then move on and briefly explain the task you had to complete. You then give in-depth details, specific details about the action you took to achieve that task and you then finish off with the result following your actions. So whenever you are answering any type of behavioral interview question, whatever it is, make sure you use the star technique of situation, task, action and result. So let's now start working through some tough behavioral interview questions and top scoring answers that make really good use of the star technique. So I will give you the question. I will give you a really important tip for answering it. And I will then give you a powerful scripted answer that uses a star technique. Tough behavioral interview question number one is, tell me about a time when you received criticism that you thought was unfair.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0178}
{"question": "Now if you get asked this question during your interview, you're going to be sitting there thinking, how do I answer this?", "answer": "Well let me tell you how. First of all a tip, when responding to this tough behavioral interview question, demonstrate to the interview that you are a mature and professional employee who is willing to take on board feedback to improve, despite it appearing to be unfair. So here's a great example scripted answer that uses a star technique to help you pass your interview here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0145}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you received criticism that you thought was unfair.", "answer": "In a previous role my manager spoke to me about how long I was speaking to customers for on the telephone. Now I was trying to build up a positive rapport with our customers to help improve sales.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However my manager said I was taking too long.", "answer": "Now although I felt the criticism was unfair, simply because I was trying to help the company, it was my task to take on board his feedback to improve. Now I explained to my manager that I was trying to improve customer relations, but that I fully understood there was a need to act with speed because other customers were waiting on the line that also needed my assistance. Now after reflecting on my performance, I made changes as per my manager's instructions, and this improved the speed of my call handling rates, meaning I could help and assist more customers. That's a brilliant answer and it shows that you are prepared to take on board feedback and you also understand why it is so important. Now don't go anywhere because obviously I've still got many more behavioral interview questions and answers to give you, but when you're ready you can click that link in the top right and corner at the video head through to my website, passmainerveu.com and you can download my full set of 27 behavioral interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are covering today during this tutorial. Let's now take a look at top behavioral interview question number two. This is another really difficult question to answer correctly.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0045}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to do something differently and what was the outcome?", "answer": "Now this behavioral interview question is assessing how adaptable you are when difficult situations arise. Given answer that shows you managed to successfully overcome a difficult challenge in the workplace. Here's a great example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to do something differently and what was the outcome here we go.", "answer": "I was working in a previous role as part of a team project. Now it was our task to build a website for an important client.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, part way through the project we lost an important team member due to illness.", "answer": "He was our graphic designer and it was still plenty of graphic design work still to be done on the project. Now not being deterred by this setback. I decided to use my initiative and think of alternative ways of working to still get the website project completed on time. Now after assessing the options, I decided to place an advert on the website upwork.com for a graphic designer who could work remotely to create the artwork we needed. Now 10 High Quality graphic designers responded to the advert. And after I had chosen the most suitable one, I gave him a detailed and concise brief and he then set to work. Now by using a different method of working, I was able to overcome a challenge that had the potential to derail the project and get the website finished on time and to the client's specification. That's an other really good answer. And you can see how effective the star technique is situation, task, action and result. It enables you to give a thorough and concise answer to the most difficult of behavioral interview questions. Let's now take a look at tough behavioral interview question number three.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you worked in a team.", "answer": "This has to be the most common of behavioral interview questions. It comes up during virtually all job interviews. Make sure you have a really good answer prepared. Now this tough behavioral interview question is designed to assess whether you can collaborate with other people in an unselfish manner. Now when your answer demonstrates you understand the importance of always putting the needs of the team first in everything you do. Here's another great example answer to help you partial interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you worked in a team.", "answer": "Here we go. In a previous role I was part of a team whose responsibility it was to come up with innovative ways to promote a new company product that had just launched. Now I suggested we should hold a team meeting to brainstorm different ideas. Because by doing so we would have many different options at the end of the session and at least one of them would help us to achieve our objectives. During the team meeting there was no hierarchy I encouraged everyone to put forward ideas and no suggestion was off limits. Team members who were normally shy were given plenty of opportunity to contribute. At the end of the meeting we had five outstanding ideas for promoting the company product. Now these included online advertising through social media, running a contest for our loyal customers to win one of the new products and a targeted radio advertising campaign. A really good example answer that shows you thoroughly understand the importance of working effectively in a team. Toff be here over to interview question number four is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0055}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "This is another really difficult one but do not say in your answer that you've never made a mistake. When you respond to this question. Instead show you are the type of person who takes ownership of their mistakes and takes positive action to improve and develop. So here's a great example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0172}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "I am the type of person who tries to learn from every mistake. Now when I started working my last role I was eager to impress but I took on too many tasks and responsibilities without first considering how long each one would take. Now although it was my job to make sure everything was completed on time I ended up missing an important deadline due to the workload I had committed to which was entirely my mistake. After I had apologized to my manager for missing the deadline I started putting systems in place to make sure the same situation never happened again. I kept a priority list of tasks I was responsible for and the time it would take to complete each one and by using a moment of thoughticle and considered approach to task completion I could safely take on additional responsibilities knowing everything would be successfully completed on time and as requested. That's another really good answer that shows you are not afraid to own up to your mistakes. You apologize for them and you then put positive action in place to make sure they never happen Top behavioral interview question number five is tell me about a time when you multitasked. Now being able to successfully complete multiple tasks is a key workplace skill required in virtually all job roles. My advice is to make sure you give a specific answer that demonstrates you have the ability to prioritize and finish multiple tasks on time and to the expected standard so he is another great example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0038}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you multitasked here we go.", "answer": "My manager asked for a volunteer to cover the work of a co worker who was off sick for several weeks. I volunteered to be that person. Now it was my task to make sure my own work and the work of my co worker was completed on time. I started out by writing a priority list of the tasks that needed my attention and then he were not urgent I would leave until the end of the day. Now there were several of my co workers tasks that I was unsure how to complete so I carried out some research and found out the most efficient way to tackle them and by prioritising tasks correctly by remaining calm and by taking the initiative to learn the tasks I was unsure of I was able to successfully complete two people's work on time until the required standard. That's an really good example answer that's going to help you pass your interview. Toff behavioural interview question number six is tell me about a time when you failed to meet a deadline. Now this is another toff behavioural interview question to answer correctly.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0052}
{"question": "However in your response give a situation where you missed a deadline due to challenging circumstances but explain what you did to improve and learn from the experience.", "answer": "Here's a great example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you failed to meet a deadline.", "answer": "In my last role I was working as part of a team on a difficult time sensitive project. Now it was our task to get the project completed on time despite the many challenges that were present. Now seven days before the project deadline two members of staff went off sick with COVID. We tried our hardest to get the project finished. I and several other team members put in extra hours and we outsourced several tasks to online contractors.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However despite the team's best efforts we missed the deadline by 24 hours.", "answer": "Now I learned a lot from that situation. Now whenever I am part of a team project or task I always put contingency plans in place before starting work to compensate for problems whenever they occur. This includes making sure we have backup from other departments in the organisation if needed at sure notice. That's a great example answer to that behavioural interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you failed to meet a deadline.", "answer": "Now the next thing to do if you want to pass your interview is click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Head through to my website pastmaintavue.com and you can download my full set of 27 behavioural interview questions and top scoring answers including a ones we have worked through together today. It's a great resource. You can literally have it within your inbox within two minutes from now and it's going to put you ahead of the competition at your interview. Make sure you check out that page as I say click the link in the top right hand corner of the video. Thank you very much. Finally, don't forget to subscribe to the channel. It's really important because I can help you not just pass every job interview you ever attend. I can also help you to get promoted and also negotiate a pay rise or get the salary you deserve. Please give the video a like. That tells me you find these tutorials useful and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always good to connect with like minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your interview have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0129}
{"question": "Okay, so what is a 3060 and 90 day plan for Amazon job interviews?", "answer": "Please make sure you take notes. So a 3060 and 90 day plan is a pretty document you take with you to the Amazon interview that tells the hiring manager what you will do in the first 90 days of starting work for Amazon to give the organization a brilliant return on your salary. So during your Amazon interview, you will give the hiring manager a copy of your 3060 and 90 day plan. And this is a brilliant thing to do because it then tells the hiring manager you are organized and you have a plan for how you are going to have a positive impact in your work.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0182}
{"question": "But when should you give the hiring manager your 3060 and 90 day plan? Well, the best time to give it to them is during the interview when answering the question, why should we hire you? Now later on in this tutorial, I will give you a brilliant scripted answer to the question, why should we hire you that incorporates your 3060 and 90 day plan?", "answer": "But first of all, let me tell you what to include in your 3060 and 90 day plan for Amazon job interviews. Again, please make sure you take notes. So on page one of your 3060 and 90 day plan, you will have your commitment to Amazon. So across the top of this first page, you are going to write my commitment to Amazon. And you will then include the following statement. This will be the first thing the Amazon hiring manager is going to read on your document. This 3060 and 90 day plan highlights my commitment to continuous learning, effective collaboration and a customer obsessed approach. By dedicating time to mastering tools, building relationships and identifying opportunities, I will quickly integrate into Amazon's culture and contribute to the company's mission of being Earth's most customer-centric company. At the end of this plan, I have allocated space to record when I have demonstrated each of the 16 Amazon leadership principles in my work. My 3060 and 90 day plans are intended to complement the work instructions and guidance I will receive from my immediate line manager. Name date side. So at the end of this first page, you will insert your name, the date of the interview, and then you will sign that commitment to Amazon. So that is really powerful because it's the first thing the hiring manager will read on your 3060 and 90 day plan. We then move on to page 2 of your plan and this is your first 30 days and we will call this orientation and foundation building. So this is what you are going to do in the first 30 days of working at Amazon. And you will write this down. The goal is to learn the fundamentals of my role, Amazon Systems and its leadership principles and to achieve that goal, I will understand Amazon's culture and leadership principles. So I will meet with my immediate line manager to obtain a thorough brief and timeline for workplace familiarization and training. I will learn Amazon's safety procedures. I will dedicate time to reading internal resources about Amazon's 16 leadership principles and observe how these principles are reflected in day-to-day operations. And I will connect with colleagues to learn how these principles guide decision making. And number 2, I will master internal tools and processes and to achieve that. I will dedicate time to practicing and exploring Amazon's tools, systems and workflows and use tutorials, training modules and sandbox environments to gain confidence with essential software. And then moving on to number 3, I will network and build relationships. To achieve that, I will schedule one-to-one chats with team members, managers and cross-functional colleagues to understand their priorities and challenges. And I will actively participate in team meetings to absorb context and processes. And number 4, I'm going to learn about the customer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0121}
{"question": "Don't forget, Amazon is customer obsessed.", "answer": "So achieve this goal, you will read customer reviews, feedback and industry reports to understand customer pain points and expectations. And you will familiarize yourself with key Amazon products and services that are applicable to your role. And finally, the fifth thing during your first 30 days is self-development. So you will identify knowledge gaps and complete Amazon specific, e-learning courses to improve technical or operational expertise. And you will, at the end of the first 30 days, meet with your manager to obtain feedback on your work performance during that first 30 days while working at Amazon. So that is the 30-day plan complete. In a second, we will move on to the 60-day plan.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.025}
{"question": "What you will do in the next 30 days while working at Amazon.", "answer": "But don't forget, you can download my ready-made 30-60 and 90-day plans at the end of this tutorial so make sure you stick around. Let's move on to the 60-day plan and this will go on page 3. And we will call this integration and contribution. So here's what you write on your 60-day Amazon work plan. The goal is to begin contributing to projects while deepening my understanding of Amazon's business strategy. And to achieve that goal, you will do the following things. Number one, dive deeper into business goals. So you will use downtime to read and analyze team strategy documents, product road maps, and key performance indicators. You will study competitors and market trends to understand how Amazon differentiates itself. Number two, you will start to build technical expertise. So you will continue practicing with Amazon specific tools and technologies seeking advanced or role-specific training resources. And you will collaborate with team members to solve real world problems and refine your technical skills. And number three, you will develop problem-solving skills. So you will volunteer for small tasks or projects to apply what you have learned and identify areas for improvement. And you will practice the working backwards methodology. So for example, you will draft mock press releases for potential initiatives. Amazon has this working backwards methodology. So when it wants to launch or create a new product or service, it works backwards. So it starts with, for example, the press release. It writes the press release and what that will look like and then works backwards. And that's all about focusing on what the customer needs. And number four of your 60 day plan, you will start to expand your network and influence. So you will join employee resource groups and the 10 events to connect with diverse colleagues across Amazon. And you will engage in conversations with leaders to understand high level strategic priorities. And number five, you will start to focus on the customer. You will dive into customer use cases related to your role and brainstorm ways to improve customer satisfaction. And you will read leadership documents such as PRFAQs. And that stands for press release and frequently asked questions for ongoing projects. And number six, you will again focus on continuous improvement by meeting with your manager to identify skills and knowledge gaps and obtain feedback on your work performance during the first 60 days at Amazon. So that is the 60 day plan complete. It goes on page three. Let's now move on to the 90 day plan. The final 30 days of your 90 days of starting work at Amazon, this goes on page four and it is called ownership and impact. And here's what I recommend you write. The goal is to take ownership of responsibilities and deliver measurable results to achieve that you will do the following things. Number one, deliver tangible results. So you will complete meaningful projects or deliverables that align with team goals. You will use free time to refine deliverables by incorporating feedback and improving efficiency. Number two, you will start to innovate and propose improvements. You will identify inefficiencies or opportunities in existing workflows and propose solutions to improve processes. And you will develop a mechanism to track a measure progress for ongoing initiatives. Number three, is mentorship and knowledge sharing. You will begin sharing insights and best practices with new hires or colleagues and use personal downtime to draft knowledge sharing documents or training materials for your team. Number four, you will strengthen cross functional collaboration. You will use free time to learn about the work of other teams that intersect with your responsibilities and you will build relationships with stakeholders across different business units to create alignment. And number five, again, you will concentrate on continuous learning and development. You will participate in advanced training programs or certificates relevant to your role and long-term goals at Amazon. You will stay updated on Amazon news, industry developments and emerging technologies. And again, you will meet with your manager to request ongoing advice on how you can continue to develop your skills and contribute to Amazon's short medium and long-term goals. So that is the 90-day plan now complete. And at the end of this plan, I strongly recommend you include the following pages. My commitment to Amazon's 16 leadership principles. As you probably already know, the 16 leadership principles are crucial to the success of Amazon. In my opinion, Amazon is one of the best organizations in the world and it has achieved so much success because it has the 16 leadership principles. So I recommend you write this down. My commitment to Amazon's 16 leadership principles, I will integrate into Amazon's culture by providing examples of when I have demonstrated each of the 16 leadership principles. So you will write the leadership principles, for example, customer obsession, ownership, invent and simplify. And in the box provided, you will write the date when you have demonstrated each of the 16 leadership principles. So you will write down in the box how you demonstrated that particular leadership principle and include the date when you've actually done it. So that's your commitment to demonstrating the leadership principles in your work. Okay, now that the 3060 and 90-day plan is complete, let me teach you how to answer the Amazon interview question, why should we hire you incorporating your Amazon 3060 and 90-day plan. Once I have given you this scripted answer to that question, I will tell you where you can download these ready-made Amazon 3060 and 90-day plans for all job roles.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0197}
{"question": "So here is how I would answer the question, why should we hire you?", "answer": "You should hire me to work at Amazon because I am passionate about the leadership principles, will demonstrate them in my work and I understand they are crucial to the success of this organization. I am customer centric and understand that the Amazon would not be here without the customer. Therefore, I will obsess about customers' needs and encourage my co-workers to do the same. You should also hire me because I am passionate about this work. My skills, knowledge and experience match the job description and I will support my co-workers and other departments in achieving Amazon's commercial objectives. And finally, you should hire me to work at Amazon because I have created a 3060 and 90-day plan that details what I will do in the position to ensure you receive a positive return on my salary and I would like to give you a copy. So you then hand the hiring manager, your 3060 and 90-day plans at the end of your answer. Now in the unlikely event that the Amazon hiring manager does not say to you, during the interview, why should we hire you, you can still give them this document at the end of your interview just before you leave. So at the end of your Amazon interview, you could say, I just want to say thank you very much for giving me this opportunity today. Just before I go, I would like to give you a 3060 and 90-day plan that I have created that tells you what I will do in the position if you hire me, here is the copy and you then leave the interview. So you are leaving that document with the hiring manager and they have the time to read through it and understand what you are going to do in the role to impress during your first 90 days. Okay, so the next thing to do is click the link right now in the top right hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, passmainetavue.com and you can instantly download my ready-made 3060 and 90-day plans for Amazon job interviews. This document comes as an editable word document which means you can edit it if you want to to suit your needs. You can print it off and take it with you to your Amazon interview this. It's going to help you stand out from the other candidates. Click the link to download it straight away. For passing your Amazon interview, have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.014}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Here we go. Thank you for the opportunity to be interviewed for this position with Amazon today. I would describe myself as forward thinking. Customer centric, punctual and reliable, a calculated risk take and someone who is passionate about working for a company that thrives to be the best it can be. I researched the job description before applying for this role at Amazon and I'm confident I can not only hit the ground running in the position but also help the company achieve its long-term commercial goals. I have a track record of achievement. So for example, in previous roles I was often praised by my supervisors for my ability to provide exceptional service. The way I would encourage customers to become long-term advocates of the business by always going above and beyond and how I took ownership of difficult challenges. Now if you hire me to work at Amazon, I will demonstrate the leadership principles in my work. I will be creative and think of ways to help the business grow whilst saving money and I will take ownership of my ongoing professional development so my skills quad is knowledge are always relevant and useful to my team. That's a brilliant example answer to that first Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0093}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Let's move on to the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why Amazon? Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "Tip number one. So this next interview question comes up often during Amazon job interviews and it is assessing your motivations for joining this great organization. Now there is a lot of responsibility that comes with working for Amazon and it is important you are motivated by helping them to achieve their long-term vision. Tip number two. Talk about in your answer the opportunities you will have at Amazon to work on exciting projects with talented people who are all striving to achieve great things. Let me now give you my example answer to the second Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.01}
{"question": "Why Amazon?", "answer": "Here we go. I want to work for Amazon because you are genuinely the best at what you do. This means I will get to work on exciting tasks and projects that are at the cutting edge of innovation. I will get to work alongside some of the brightest minds in an environment where everyone has a can do attitude. I want to work for Amazon because you always put the customer first in everything you do and I understand how important this is to long-term success of any business. I want to work for Amazon because there will be continuous opportunities for me to learn, improve and grow professionally. I want to work for a company that values its staff that empowers them to be the best they can be and that creates an inclusive working environment where there is opportunity for all. Working for Amazon will give me all of these things. That's another brilliant example answer that will help you pass your Amazon interview at the first attempt. Now don't go anywhere because I still have five more questions and answers to work through review. But when you are ready click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video. You can head straight through to my website how to become.com and instantly download a copy of these slides and my full set of 57 Amazon interview questions and example answers in a PDF guide so you can literally have it in your inbox within two minutes. Here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0038}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you influence the change by only asking questions.", "answer": "This is a difficult Amazon interview question. Tip number one. This question is an example of an Amazon behavioral interview question. You will have to answer several of these questions during your Amazon interview. Now it is important to give a specific situation where you demonstrated the scenario being assessed.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tip number two, I also strongly recommend you use a star technique to structure your answer but what is the star technique?", "answer": "Let me quickly tell you what it is and I will then give you an example answer. So the star technique stands for situation task action and result. You start off your answer and tell the interview with a situation you were faced with. You then move on and briefly outline the task that needed doing. You then give in depth details about the action you took to achieve the task and then finally you finish off your answer and reveal the results following your actions and it's really important to make sure the results are positive following the action that you took. So let me now give you an example answer to that question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0172}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you influence to change by only asking questions that uses the star technique and you can see how effective it is at helping you to structure your answer to Amazon behavioral interview questions.", "answer": "Here we go. I was in a team meeting discussing the workflow for a new project which was for a client of the company. Now two team members suggested we should use a cheaper product part for the project that would save us considerable money on the project costs and make it more profitable. They argued the client would have no idea we were using a sub-standard product part so it wasn't an issue. Now I was not comfortable with this situation because it went against our company values and it was morally wrong. So it was my task to challenge them by asking questions. I asked a team members two questions to influence their proposal. I asked them if they felt their suggestion was in line with our company values and how we were expected to treat our clients with honesty and integrity. They agreed it wasn't. I then asked them what would we do if the project failed later on down the line because of the sub-standard product part and the client then found out. I explained that the situation could be immensely damaging to our reputation to which they agreed. After putting the two questions to them they agreed it was not a good idea and we should stick to the original agreed project specification. So that's a really good answer that will help you pass your Amazon interview and you can see how effective that start technique really is helping you to give a powerful answer. Let me give you another example, Amazon behavioral interview question that uses a start technique. And that question is tell me about a time when you had to overcome a difficult challenge in the workplace. Here's my example answer to help you. When I first started working my previous role I encountered a difficult coworker. He had been with the company for many years and because I was relatively young and enthusiastic I got the impression he didn't want to help. I'd asked for his assistance and guidance on a couple of issues but he wasn't forthcoming with information. So I saw this as a challenge and it was my task to break down his barriers and get to work with him closely so I could benefit from his knowledge and expertise which would then help me to do a good job for the team. I decided to change my approach and after I found out that we both supported the same football team I started to talk about our shared interest during a work break. Now this proved to be a good move because he spoke passionately about the team we both supported and this enabled me to build a positive rapport with him. Several days later when I next asked him for guidance on a project I was working on he was more receptive and happy to advise and from that day on we became close and productive work colleagues which I believe was down to my strong communication and interpersonal skills. So that's a really good in-depth answer to that Amazon behavioral interview question tell me about when you had to overcome a difficult challenge in the workplace and it uses a start technique to great effect you can see how by learning the start technique it will really help you to get an advantage at your Amazon interview. Here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0104}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "Now again this is a common Amazon interview question that I recommend you prepare for. Try to align your strengths to the key skills and qualities that are listed on the Amazon job description and tip number two for the weakness part of your answer is important to demonstrate self awareness so do not say you don't have any weaknesses because you might then fail your interview. Here's my example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0137}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "My strengths include my ability to work at pace to complete all work to exacting standards to organize and prioritize my work in line with my employers goals and in fact now I always take responsibility of my own professional development. Other strengths include my strong interpersonal skills, my desire to carry out tasks and duties outside of my job description because I am passionate about learning new things and my willingness to help train up new members of staff whenever they join the team. Now my weakness is the fact I find it difficult letting go of projects. I tend to spend too long checking over completed projects to see if improvements can be made but I need to learn to let finish to projects go and move on to the next one and this is definitely something I am working hard on to improve. That's a really good answer again that's going to help you. I'll share your Amazon interview at the first attempt. Here's an next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why should we hire you to work at Amazon?", "answer": "Tip number one this is another tough but common Amazon interview question that needs a confident answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't just give one reason why they should hire you to work at Amazon.", "answer": "Think of several reasons that demonstrate you can add value to the organization in the position you have applied for so here's my example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0385}
{"question": "Why should we hire you to work at Amazon?", "answer": "Here we go. You should hire me because I have the experience and knowledge to excel in this role. This means I will contribute positively to Amazon's long-term vision and I will be a positive role model for the organization whilst helping customers and interacting with co-workers clients and stakeholders. You should hire me because I have a good understanding of the 16 leadership principles and I will strive to demonstrate these in my work. You should hire me because I am a calculated risk taker and I will be creative and think of ways to help Amazon grow whilst at the same time helping you to save money by being frugal where possible. Finally you should hire me because I am very much open to learning and I am a big advocate of change. I know that Amazon must always change and respond to the needs of its customers if it is to continually be the market leader and I will always support you in that change. That's a really good answer another cracking answer that will help you pass your interview with confidence. Here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you demonstrated one of the leadership principles in the workplace.", "answer": "This is a difficult question to answer correctly. So it's one of the toughest Amazon interview questions in my opinion. My advice is to make sure you learn the 16 Amazon leadership principles before you attend your interview. Now I have placed links in the description below this video to several tutorials right here on YouTube where I teach you the leadership principles and also give you several additional leadership principles into view questions that I recommend you prepare. So make sure you check those out once I have given you the answer in a second. Tip number two at the start of your answer to this question. Tell the interviewer which leadership principles your answer relates to. Let me give you my example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0159}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you demonstrated one of the leadership principles in the workplace.", "answer": "Here we go. I recently demonstrated in my last job the leadership principle of have back-bone disagree and commit. A customer wanted a refund but their reason went against the company's refund policy. They were two days over the time limit to qualify for a refund but I felt the company should honor it anyway because the customer was not satisfied with the product and I felt it was more important to give exceptional service as they would then hopefully use the company's products again in the future.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, when I asked my manager for permission to give the refund, he said no.", "answer": "I disagreed with him and explained by reasons why but he still refused. So I then accepted his decision and informed the customer politely and professionally of the fact that I was not able to refund their order. I am not afraid to disagree with a manager. If I think something could be done better to the benefit of the company but I would always commit to their decision if they said no. So that's my example answer to that tough Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0235}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you demonstrated one of the leadership principles in the workplace.", "answer": "So the next thing to do is click that link in the top right hand corner of the video, head through to my website how to become.com and you can instantly download a copy of these slides in my full set of 57 Amazon interview questions and examples answers in a PDF guide. Also don't forget to check out those links in the description below the video. I have created several leadership principles, tutorials, make sure you check those out. It's really important that you learn and understand the leadership principles before you attend your Amazon interview. Also don't forget to hit the subscribe button literally thousands of you are passing your job interviews. I can only help you if you are subscribed. Please give the video a like because that motivates me to create more content for you. Thank you very much indeed and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always an honour and a pleasure to connect with light minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and wish you all the best for passing your interview have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0145}
{"question": "So to begin with what are structured interview questions?", "answer": "Well, structured interview questions are preset questions that assess how you have previously performed in specific situations. Now those situations will be wrong. You are going to likely encounter in the workplace and the hiring manager wants to be sure you can deal with them confidently and competently. Now each candidate will get asked the same structured interview questions to make the process fair and examples of structured interview questions include, tell me about a time when you had to overcome a difficult situation.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you experience conflict with a coworker and also tell me about a time when you received negative feedback.", "answer": "Now my advice when answering structured interview questions is to make sure you use the start technique, STAR. So start stands for situation, task, action and result. So you start off your answer and you tell the interviewer the situation you were faced with. You then move on and briefly outline the task that needed doing. You will then give in depth details about the action you took to complete the task before finishing off your answer and telling the interviewer the results following your actions. So let me now give you lots of brilliant example answers to difficult structured interview questions that you used to start technique. So the first structured interview question I want to give you an answer to is tell me about a time when you had to overcome a difficult situation. Here's my example response that uses a start technique. In my previous job I was tasked with organizing a large business meeting for the company owner. 50 people would you to attend. Now two days before the meeting the conference centre called me to tell me they had a flood at the night before and I could no longer use their venue. It was my task to remain calm, quickly find a suitable alternative venue and inform all attendees of the change of location. I immediately set to work, calling around various hotels and venues to find one suitable for the meeting to take place that had sufficient parking for the attendees and who could supply refreshments at short notice. After spending two hours on the phone I managed to find the perfect venue. I then spent the rest of the day drafting new meeting details, sending them out to all attendees and calling them individually to inform them about the change of venue. The end result was the meeting went ahead as planned and it was a huge success for the company owner who thanked me for my resilience while stealing with the challenging situation. The next structured interview question I recommend you prepare for is, describe a situation when you had to adjust to change in the workplace. This is a difficult one to answer but here's my example response to help you pass your interview. A new manager took over the running of our department and she wanted to make various changes to the way we worked. In particular, she wanted to streamline working practices, reduce office waste, and make people more accountable for the projects they were working on. I saw it as my responsibility to embrace the changes and support the new manager in her role. I went to see her and offered to answer any question she had about the current working practices and how I felt they could be changed to make improvements to the company. She asked me several questions before inviting me to help her write the new working practices to which I agreed. Now, some team members were skeptical about the proposed changes by encouraging them to give them a try. After my manager implemented the changes, productivity and standard started to improve and morale in the team increased significantly. The next structured interview question we need to cover comes up all the time during job interviews and that question is, tell me about a time when you experienced conflict with a coworker. Here's my example response that uses a start technique. I disagreed with a coworker on the best way to promote a new company product. They wanted to promote the product locally by using leaflets and posters where as I wanted to promote it online to reach a wider audience. It was my task to find a way through the conflict and reach an agreement that was in the best interests of the product launch. I asked my coworker questions to determine why they felt local advertising was best. I then explained why I felt online advertising would be more beneficial because we could reach a wider audience and also track sales and advertising spend. I suggested we should try both types of advertising for a one week period and which ever method yielded the best results would then be used for the rest of the campaign. My coworker agreed this was a good idea. After the one week trial, the online advertising gave very strong returns and we switched the full campaign to that method. By trialing both ideas, I was able to remove the conflict and put the needs of the business first. The next structured interview question I want to work through is, tell me about a time you received negative feedback.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0052}
{"question": "Do not answer this question by saying you've never received negative feedback.", "answer": "This question is assessing how will you react to feedback and how you use it to improve. Here's my example response to help you. My manager asked me to put together a PowerPoint presentation for an internal meeting she was holding the following day. Now the presentation was about the company's performance for the year to date and I needed to include all relevant sales data. Now when I delivered the presentation to my manager, she was disappointed in how it had been put together. She said the presentation was not adequately detailed for what she needed. I listened to her feedback and asked questions to determine exactly what she wanted before starting the presentation again. When I delivered the presentation a second time, she told me it was perfect. I learned a lot from that situation and I now asked plenty of questions whenever I am given an important task or project to ensure I completed to the required standard. So there you have it. Lots of examples, as two difficult structured interview questions. Now if you want to download those answers, are my full set of star technique interview questions and brilliant responses, click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, passmaintevue.com and you can instantly download the guide. You can have it in your inbox within two minutes from now and it's going to help you be the standout candidate at your forthcoming interview. Also don't forget to hit the subscribe button literally thousands of you are passing your job interviews. I can only help you if you are subscribed. Please give the video a like because that tells me you find these tutorials useful and it also motivates me to create more content for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0065}
{"question": "Don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn.", "answer": "I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below to video. It's always an honor and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your interview have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.04}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself here we go.", "answer": "My name is Richard and I have always been passionate about combining innovation with customer centricity and that's why I am excited about the opportunity to join Amazon. In my previous role at company X I worked on a team that successfully launched a game changing product by embodying the think big principle. We identified emerging market trends and created a product that gave the company a great return on investment. Throughout my career I have consistently exhibited ownership by taking responsibility for both successes and setbacks. For example when we lost two team members during a critical project deadline I stepped up, rallied the team and redistributed tasks to ensure we not only met the deadline but also delivered with uncompromising quality. My skills, qualifications and work ethic are a great match for the leadership principles and my work experience has given me a solid foundation which I believe will add value to the Amazon team. I am genuinely excited about the opportunity to contribute to Amazon's relentless pursuit of customer satisfaction and innovation and I believe my commitment to the leadership principles will enable me to thrive in this dynamic environment. So that is a really good answer to that first Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0048}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself you are referencing those leadership principles giving an example early on of where you demonstrated them in your previous role and the response shows you are a confident communicator.", "answer": "Now you can either pause the video if you want to and write down the questions and answers as we work through them together or if you wait I will sing tell you where you can download the slides plus my full set of 21. Brilliant answers to difficult Amazon interview questions. There is an next question I recommend you prepare for and that is why Amazon. Let me give you two important tips. Tip number one. So this next common question features during I would say 95% of Amazon interviews. It is assessing your motivations for wanting to work for this brilliant organisation. I think personally Amazon is the best organisation in the world and if you get to work for them your skills and experience will accelerate at a great speed. Tip number two. In your answer consider saying you have set your sights on working for Amazon for some time and you want to work there because you will be pushed and challenged in your role. You may also decide once again to reference the leadership principles in your response. So here is another great example answer to help you pass your Amazon interview. My Amazon. Getting hired and building a long-term career at Amazon has been my number one goal. Amazon has long been in the market leader in numerous industries which tells me it is an organisation that is continually progressing delivers world class products and services and provides customer service that outperforms its competitors. This means I will be pushed and challenged in my work. My ideas will be listened to and I will be supported to be the best I can be. I also want to work for Amazon because the leadership principles are a set of standards I genuinely believe in and the inclusive work culture means there is opportunity for everyone. That is another great answer that puts you across as someone who has researched the organisation and you have genuine reason for wanting to work for this brilliant organisation. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you. But when you are ready click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website to passmainetiveu.com and you can download these slides plus my full set of 21 Amazon interview questions and top scoring answers in a PDF guide. But here is the next question I want you to prepare for these are very difficult questions to answer. That question is tell me about a time when you gave a simple solution to a complex problem. Now during your Amazon interview you must answer several behavioral interview questions that assess your experience around those leadership principles. I will give you another training video based on the leadership principles at the end of this tutorial. So don't worry you are going to be fully prepared for your Amazon interview tip number too. This is important. Take note, I recommend you use the star method to structure your answer. The star method stands for situation task action and result. So you commend your answer and you briefly explain the situation you were in. You then outline the task that needed doing. You then give in depth details about the action you took and you finish your answer with the results of your actions. Now when responding to the behavioral interview questions make sure you give specific situations you have been in where you demonstrated the leadership principle that is being assessed. So here is another brilliant answer to help you pass your interview and this time it uses the star method. Situation task action and result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0081}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you gave a simple solution to a complex problem.", "answer": "Here we go. My previous job we had an ongoing problem with communication updates on projects and task delegation were becoming increasingly difficult as the company expanded. I decided to find a simple solution to this issue. After researching online for the best workplace communication and productivity tools, I put together a short presentation on a tool called Evernote which would empower managers and team members to keep everyone updated on task and project progression. After watching my presentation my manager agreed to its implementation and within several weeks Evernote became a fundamental part of our workplace productivity scheduling and task management. You can see how effective the answer is when you use the star method. Situation task action and result. There you are giving a specific situation you have been in where you found a simple solution to a complex problem that was causing the company issues. It's a really good answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "The next question, the next common Amazon interview question is what are your strengths and weaknesses tip number one?", "answer": "This next common but challenging Amazon interview question must be answered in a specific way. Again give strengths that match the leadership principles and an example to back up your claims because anybody can give certain strengths in their job interview answer but actually backing them up is another thing. Tip number two, now for the weakness give one that is not a match for the job description and do not say I don't have any weaknesses. If you do, I believe you will fail your Amazon interview. So here is another great example response to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0202}
{"question": "Don't forget if you are enjoying this video please hit that like button please make sure you subscribe. What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "My greatest strengths include my ability to take ownership of difficult problems and challenges, my cost conscious approach to work and my communication skills and confidence which empower me to professionally challenge key decisions to achieve the best outcomes. For example in my current job I disagreed with my manager on how to market a new product launch after providing data and information to back up my claim that we should focus on marketing efforts more online and offline. She agreed to change direction. My weakness is I find it difficult to say no to people. I automatically say yes when people ask me to get involved in additional tasks or projects when I should actually first assess my capacity for the extra work. You can see how these answers will help you beat the competition and pass your Amazon interview at the first attempt.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0069}
{"question": "Don't forget if you want to download them just click the link in the top right hand corner of the video at any time.", "answer": "Here is the next question. This is another behavioural interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to work with incomplete data or information.", "answer": "Tip number one so this is another behavioural interview question that is assessing those leadership principles. Once again use that star method when giving your answer situation task action and result. And tip number two in your response demonstrate your ability to achieve your objective despite their being missing information or data. So here's another brilliant example answer to help you pass your Amazon interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0303}
{"question": "Tell me about your time when you had to work with incomplete data or information.", "answer": "I was tasked with creating a presentation for my manager who was going to deliver a sales update to company bosses while collecting the sales data for the presentation. I noticed several months figures were unavailable due to a technical issue. I needed to find an alternative way to extract the sales data required to ensure the presentation was accurate. I analyzed stock levels at the beginning and end of each month where the sales data was missing and then calculated the total sales generated for each product and month which gave me an accurate income and profit calculation. Now although this approach took longer to complete, I was able to create a presentation that enabled my manager to present correct information to the company executives. So that is a really good answer because it shows you are using your initiative to get the information and data required and you still achieve your outcome. You are not the type of employee who goes back to their manager and says, I can't do this because I don't have the information available. You are taking ownership of the problem and achieving your outcome and that's how you need to respond to that difficult Amazon behavioral interview question. Here's an next interview question for Amazon. I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0045}
{"question": "Why do you want to leave your current job?", "answer": "Here's two great tips to help you tip number one. So this next common Amazon interview question is assessing your attitude towards your previous employer and why you want to leave.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0312}
{"question": "Do not be negative in any way about your boss coworkers or the work environment.", "answer": "So here is a short but positive answer to help you pass your Amazon interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0667}
{"question": "Why do you want to leave your current job?", "answer": "I want to leave my current job because I have set my sights on working for Amazon for some time. The skills knowledge and expertise I have gained in my job mean I am now ready to apply. My employer has been great to work for. They have been very supportive and I have enjoyed my time there.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, I am ready for the next chapter of my career where I can accelerate my growth even further while working for a forward thinking company such as Amazon that pushes the boundaries of innovation and provides a positive workplace culture where everyone has a can do attitude.", "answer": "You can see how that type of positive answer is going to help you pass your Amazon interview here is the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you influence the change by only asking questions.", "answer": "This is a really difficult Amazon interview question to answer correctly but let me give you two tips to help you. Tip number one so this Amazon behavioral interview question is assessing the leadership principle of learn and be curious which is your ability to be curious about new opportunities tip number two. In your answer say which questions you asked and explain the change that was influenced by them. So here's a great example answer to help you pass your Amazon job interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0235}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you influence the change by only asking questions here we go.", "answer": "I was attending a meeting at work discussing the environmental impact the company was having. I had several ideas for making improvements and it was my task to influence a change by asking three specific questions which I had prepared.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "The questions I asked were have we ever thought about how much waste we generate here? Do we think we could be more environmentally friendly in our office practices and have we ever considered implementing a recycling program?", "answer": "I then presented a recycling idea to my manager and he agreed it was a positive step forward in reducing our impact on the environment. After my suggestion was implemented we reduced our company waste by 75% and everyone in the company adopted a more responsible approach to waste. The idea also resulted in considerable cost savings for the company. So that's a really good example answer. You are saying the three questions that you asked in a team meeting and those questions influence a positive change for the organisation and people in the team adopted a more responsible approach to waste. So it's a really good example answer. Now the next thing to do is you want to accelerate your learning even further and make sure you are fully prepared for your Amazon interview is to click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video. Let's straight through to my website, passmaintevue.com and you can instantly download these slides plus my full set of 21. Amazon interview questions and top scoring example answers in a PDF guide which means you can have them in your inbox literally within two minutes from now. Make sure you check that link. So I click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video because it will also take you down at this page on YouTube to where I have put the link to another video that will teach you how to prepare your answers for those leadership principles. Make sure you watch that video.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0114}
{"question": "Don't forget to hit the like button.", "answer": "Please subscribe to the channel. It's really important. I'm very passionate about helping people like you to progress in your careers, partner interviews, get a pay rise and get promoted. I can only do those things if you are subscribed and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always an honor and a pleasure to connect with light-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching and for supporting my channel. I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0095}
{"question": "To begin with, what is the star method?", "answer": "Well, the star method is an easy to remember structure that is used by successful interview candidates to answer difficult, behavioral interview questions such as, given example of a time you worked under pressure.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you worked in a team, describe a time when you had a disagreement with a coworker, and tell me about a time you dealt with an ethical dilemma.", "answer": "Okay, so the star method is recognized by hiring managers as the best technique to use when answering behavioral interview questions. That is why it is so important to learn it and understand it.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0588}
{"question": "So what does star stand for?", "answer": "Well, star stands for situation, task, action, and result. So whenever answering difficult behavioral interview questions, you start your answer and tell the hiring manager the situation you were in. You then move on and briefly describe the task that needed doing. And this demonstrates your awareness of the situation. You then go into great detail about the action you took to achieve or complete the task before finishing off your answer and telling the hiring manager the result, following your actions. And it's really important to remember that the result should always be a positive outcome. Okay, let's start working through the most common behavioral interview questions with star method answers. Here's the first question. Given example of a time you worked under pressure, here's my top scoring response that uses a star method. In my last job, a new customer contacted the company and then quiet about placing a large order of goods. Now they needed the order to be ready in 48 hours. Now despite this order quantity usually taking five days to prepare, we didn't want to let the customer down, so we agreed to deliver it in the requested time frame of 48 hours. As a team, we allocated tasks based on each other's strengths and worked to strict deadlines. My job was to supervise everyone and quality check each order for accuracy. Throughout the two days, we supported each other and worked tirelessly without taking breaks. We managed to get the order ready, we've just one hour to spare, and the customer was delighted with our speed of service. That is a brilliant example answer. To that difficult behavioral interview question, given example of a time you worked under pressure that uses a star method. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you. But when you're ready, you can click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video, head through to my website, passmindervue.com, and you can download my full set of 23 star technique, interview questions and top scoring answers, including the ones we are working through together today in this tutorial. Here is an ex-question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0053}
{"question": "Describe a time when you had a disagreement with a coworker.", "answer": "Wow, this is a really difficult question to answer. Here's my top scoring response that uses a star method, here we go. My coworker and I disagreed on how to resolve a customer complaint. My coworker was refusing to meet the customer's demands. In contrast, I wanted to resolve their complaint amicably to keep the customer happy and learn from the situation. My goal was to explain to my coworker why my suggestion was the best way forward for the customer and our company. After hearing their argument for not meeting the customer's demands, I explained how excellent customer service was essential for the company's success. The company's reputation could be damaged if we didn't resolve the complaint successfully. After listening to my opinion, my coworker agreed, my method was the best way forward and we worked hard to resolve the customer's complaint to their satisfaction. That is such a good answer because you are putting the needs of the customer and your organization first and you are protecting the company's reputation. You can see how effective these answers are when you use a star method. It's really worth learning. Here's an ex-question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had to adapt to change.", "answer": "This behavioural interview question is coming up all the time during job interviews. Here's my top scoring response that uses a star method. In my last job, a coworker went on long-term sick leave. I volunteered to cover their work until a replacement could be found. It was my task to learn their role, reorganize my workload to ensure I met the company's objectives and adapt to a change in my daily work schedule. I created a list of my coworkers' duties and integrated them into my workload. I then prioritized my new list against the company's objectives and set to work. Whenever I was unsure how to complete one of my co-workers' tasks, I took the time to learn it using online trained videos and manuals. After several days of working with the change in my daily work, I felt comfortable with my responsibilities and settled into the new schedule. That's a really good answer because you volunteer to cover the work of your co-worker. And if you are unsure how to complete a task, you take the time to learn it yourself, using online training videos and manuals. So it's a really good answer that shows you are an efficient and effective employee. Here's an next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0046}
{"question": "What's the most difficult problem you've had to solve?", "answer": "Here's my top scoring response that uses that fantastic technique, the star method. Here we go. I arrived at work early Monday morning and quickly noticed the company website wasn't working. Monday was our busiest day of the week and it was important the website was back up and running quickly. This was a complex problem to solve because I had no IT skills and my manager wasn't doing it work until the following day. I felt it was my responsibility to investigate the website issue and get it back operational again quickly. So I researched online for common website problems and using a process of elimination, I determined the problem was with the server. Now because I was not qualified to work on the server, the best option was to hire a web developer online using upwork.com. After finding a suitably qualified web developer and giving them a thorough brief, they quickly resolved the issue and got the website back up and running within the hour. It's a really good example answer because you are taking ownership of a really difficult situation. You come across a problem because you can't fix the website yourself but you use your initiative and hire a web developer online. It's a really good answer. Here is the next behavioral interview question. I want you to prepare for. This is one of the most common questions.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0042}
{"question": "Tell me about the time you worked in 18.", "answer": "Here's my example answer, top scoring answer that uses a star method. Here we go. In my last job, my manager asked the team I was a part of to create a marketing plan for a new company product we were launching. Now the team was responsible for creating a plan that gave the business excellent value for money from its marketing budget and generated the most sales. We started by discussing our target audience.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Where and how we could reach them and our marketing message.", "answer": "We each put forward ideas about how we felt we could market the product to get the greatest return. While each team member was speaking, everyone listened and gave encouragement. Finally, we collated the best ideas into a marketing plan before presenting it to our manager. He then permitted us to market the product using the plan and we achieved the best sales for a new product in the company's history. That's a great answer. You're working as part of a team. You're taking it in turns to come up with ideas you are listening to each other and giving encouragement. And you're then achieving a brilliant outcome which is the best sales ever for a new product launch in the company's history. Top scoring answer. Okay, let's now move on to the next question. Wow, this is a really difficult one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a situation when you had to deal with an ethical dilemma.", "answer": "This has to be one of the hardest behavioral interview questions to answer. But here's my top scoring response that uses a star method. Here we go. In my last job, a problem occurred where I felt it necessary to inform my manager about inappropriate language being used by some of the more senior team members. I had asked them to stop using the language but they refused. This was a challenging dilemma because they were my colleagues and I had to work closely with them.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, I decided to speak out for the good of the organization.", "answer": "I spoke to my manager and explained what I had heard and the effort I had taken to try and stop it. I further explained that the organization was at risk because customers or clients might hear the comments and someone may take serious offense to them. After I reported the situation to my manager, she thanked me for doing the right thing and an investigation was launched which resulted in a changing company culture. It's a really good example answer. It shows that you have integrity and the confidence to deal with this challenging situation. It's a really good answer. So the next thing to do is click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video. I had straight through to my website, pass my interview.com and you can instantly download my full set of 23 star technique interview questions and top scoring answers include in the ones I have worked through with you in this tutorial today. Make sure you check out that website because these 23 questions I recommend you prepare for you can download the answers. Please make sure you subscribe to the channel. As you can see, literally thousands and thousands of you are passing your interviews at the first attempt, I can only help you if you are subscribed. Please give the video a like. It's a small ask but it really does motivate me to create more content for you. If I see you liking the video, it tells me that you want more content and as I said it motivates me to create more for you. Also, don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always a pleasure and an honour to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your job interview and using the star method. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0118}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for our company as a software engineer?", "answer": "So this is pretty much guaranteed to come up during your software engineer interview and my tip for answering this question positively is to show the interviewer you have conducted some research into their organization. My advice is to be complimentary in your answer and talk about what makes their company unique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0192}
{"question": "So let's take a look at a suggested answer to the interview question why do you want to work for our company as a software engineer?", "answer": "For me the company I work for is very important. I believe that to be able to perform your duties and responsibilities as a software engineer, competently you need the support of your employer and you also need to work with like minded people who are all working towards a common goal. During my research into your organization, it soon became apparent that you are not only a leader within this industry, but you also continually look for ways to grow and develop. You also clearly hide some of the best people available and this means I'll be working with other professionals who all genuinely care about the work they produce. I am someone who is ambitious. I don't like to sit back and just do the bare minimum and if you hire me, I feel confident you will be impressed with my work values, my ethics and my high standards. As a great answer, you are giving lots of valid reasons why you want to work for their company, you are being complementary and most importantly, it shows that you've conducted some research before applying for the position. Let's take a look at another software engineer interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0099}
{"question": "How would you deal with a member of your team who disagreed with the work you carried out as a software engineer?", "answer": "Now my tip for answering this question. This interview question is subtly assessing your team working capabilities.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Do you put the needs of your team and the organization first or are you more concerned about your own reputation and your competence?", "answer": "Here is my suggested answer to the interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How would you deal with a member of your team who disagreed with the work you carried out as a software engineer?", "answer": "I have a lot of experiences as a software engineer and I feel the work I produce is to a very high standard. Now having said that, I am also aware that when I do work as part of a team, it is important to listen to other people as they may have valid contributions to make. And on that basis, I would certainly be open to listening to why they felt the work I was carrying out could be altered or improved. At the end of the day, we are all working for the same organization. And if that means changing the way I do things for the benefit of the team goal, I will certainly do that. That is a really good answer and it shows that you are more concerned about the organization and the team objectives. Now I have got lots more questions to run through, but when you are ready, if you would like to download a copy of these slides to save you having to write things down, you can click the link in the top right hand corner of that video. It will take you through to my website where you can download a copy of these slides. Let's move on to the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0047}
{"question": "In your opinion, what other skills and qualities needed to be a software engineer?", "answer": "So this is a question that gets asked a number of times during software engineer interviews. So this question is clearly assessing your understanding of the role of a software engineer. And the best way to answer this is to give them a definitive list of the skills and qualities that are needed to excel in the position.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0345}
{"question": "So here is my suggested answer to the interview question in your opinion, what are the skills and qualities needed to be a software engineer?", "answer": "And there is a clever way of answering this. Here we go. Whilst they are on numerous skills and qualities needed, they are on nine in particular that are essential to becoming an effective software engineer. Now in no particular order, these are technical competence, communication and interpersonal skills whilst in and we clients and internal team members, exceptional organizational and planning capabilities, a level of commercial awareness. And also an understanding of how important it is to maintain competence in your role through professional development. You also need an ability to explain technical information in a simple and concise manner, so people understand it. An awareness of current issues impacting the industry or working in, and also strong analytical and attention to detail skills. Now what I like about that answer is you are starting up and saying there are numerous skills needed, but there are nine in particular that are essential. That shows that you really do know your role inside out and then you can list those nine skills and qualities. And if you want to add some yourself, feel free to do so. Next software engineer interview question that we want to prepare for is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0151}
{"question": "Tell me your time when you worked as part of a team to solve a complex task.", "answer": "So this is a behavioral type interview question and as such, my advice is to use a star technique to create your answer. So the question is tell me your time when you worked as part of a team to solve a complex task. You have to give a specific situation you have previously been in to score this answer highly. So use the star technique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0455}
{"question": "What is that?", "answer": "Well, it is situation task action results. So you start off with your answer and you describe briefly the situation you were in. You then move on and explain the task that needed to be done. You then detail the action you took to achieve the task and you finish off your answer by revealing the results following your actions. So it's situation task action result. Let's take a look at a sample answer using the star technique to that interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0238}
{"question": "Tell me a time when you worked as part of a team to solve a complex task.", "answer": "Here we go. I was part of a multi-agency project building a software application for an important client. Towards the end of the project, we encountered a number of bugs and problems with the software application and time was against us to get everything fixed before the official hand over date. I felt it was my responsibility to come up with a solution to get the issues fixed. I stayed behind late that evening with two other experienced team members to come up with a plan that would ensure the bugs were not only fully rectified, but that a support system was in place to respond to any future issues if they were to arise post-handover. We started off by creating a list of all bugs and issues with an attempted to recreate each bug so that we could assess what was causing the issue. We managed to recreate all of the bugs and it was then my task to create a time scale for rectifying and testing each issue. Once we had a planning place, we could then allocate tasks to team members based on their area of technical competence the following morning. Now by creating a plan of action and by working closely together as a team, we were able to tap into the combined team expertise and competence to not only provide a time sensitive solution to the problem, but to also implement a support mechanism for our client. That is an organized answer. It is concise and logic in the way you are answering it by using that star technique of situation task action result. And don't forget if you want to click the link in the top right and corner of the video, you can download these slides to save you the hassle of having to write everything down. Next interview question is, Tell me how you would handle the stress and pressure of being a software engineer. Now you and I know that being a software engineer can be a stressful role. So when you answer this software engineer and interview question, show you already have a planning place for dealing with the stress and pressure of the position. Here is my suggested answer. I think as a software engineer, you have to realise that stress and pressure is all part of the role. And in actual fact, I feel I tend to perform better when I am up against it and there is a definitive time frame to work towards. I manage stress in three ways. First and foremost, I ensure I plan my work well in advance, so I know what I need to do and buy what deadline. Now by having a planning place, it means I work more efficiently and I can decide which tasks need my attention first. The second way I handle stress and pressure is to make sure I work closely with other team members and that communication is a constant theme throughout the day. Finally, I handle stress and pressure by making sure I dedicate some time each week to keeping up to date with developments from within the industry. This gives me the confidence in my role as a software engineer and it also eliminates any unwelcome surprises when updates do come out or changes within the industry or released. So that shows that you know how to handle stress and pressure and you are essentially saying, it doesn't matter, I can handle this. It's all part and parcel of the role. I have a planning place, but I do tend to perform better when I am up against it.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0082}
{"question": "Next, software engineer interview question is, what's your biggest weakness?", "answer": "So if any software engineer interview question is going to catch you out, it is this one. Now the issue is, we have to give a weakness in our answer, but we do not want to give a weakness that is needed to be competent in the role of a professional software engineer. So here is a great answer to this question. We all have weaknesses and I know my own is the fact I find it really hard to strike a healthy work life balance. I love my job as a software engineer and even when I am not at work, I am usually spending time with compute systems or developing additional skills and qualities. So I continue to grow in the role much to the dissatisfaction of my partner. Now this is an area I have been working to approve a poll. And I am trying to spend more time relaxing with my family, so I can then maintain optimum energy levels when I am actually at work. Conversely, one of my strengths is the fact I am always prepared to listen to feedback, and I do genuinely want to improve and develop as a person on both a personal level and a professional level also. So that shows you are given a weakness that does not actually impact your chances of passing the interview and you are then saying what you are doing about it. But you will see that answer is actually quite clever because that weakness you give is actually a strength and it is attractive to any employer. Because you are saying you enjoy being at work, you are always working, you love your role and you are prepared to put the hours in necessary.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0309}
{"question": "Next interview questions, what are your salary expectations?", "answer": "Now again, this is a tricky interview question because on the one hand we don't want to go in with an unrealistic salary expectation, but on the other we don't want to devalue ourselves either. So your answer has to offer a win-win situation. One that is a benefit to you, but also to the hiring manager or the employer. So we can answer this in the following manner. I have conducted some research prior to attending the interview and what I feel would be a fair salary for this position. Now the average salary for a software engineer in this industry is 90,000 to $110,000. Now whilst I do feel I am worth the higher salary band, I understand you don't know me and I need to prove to you my worth. On that basis I would feel comfortable with a salary of $120,000 and I feel you will see a positive return on your investment at this level if you hire me. So you are not going in there over confidence, but you are not devaluing yourself either. So that is a win-win situation. So do your own research and look at what the average salary for a software engineer is within your industry and then look at the band and then go slightly above the middle of that average salary range. Okay, three questions to ask in your software engineer interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0207}
{"question": "So you get to the end of the interview and they say to you, do you have any questions you would like to ask?", "answer": "My advice is to ask three questions. Now these questions are designed to show that you are keen, you are enthusiastic and you have the success of their organization at the forefront of your mind.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "So the first question is, what is frustrated you about software engineers you have employed in the past?", "answer": "It's quite clever question because it shows that you want to go in there, you want to do a good job and you are putting their needs first above your own.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Second question is, what are the plans for the company over the next five to ten years and how could I help you to achieve them?", "answer": "Again, you are looking to the future.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "These tells me that you are considering staying with my organization for many years to come and you want to help me achieve my goals and then finally, what's the first thing you would like me to concentrate on in this role?", "answer": "So those three questions are great because they put you across as a positive person and somebody who is interested more in the success of their company as opposed to the success of yourself. So don't forget download a copy of these slides by clicking the link in the top right and corner of the video. You can connect with me on LinkedIn if you want to. My LinkedIn description is, sorry, my LinkedIn link is in the description below the video. So go through to that, click it and connect with me on LinkedIn. It's always good to connect with like-minded professionals. Thank you for watching.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0364}
{"question": "Don't forget to subscribe and hit the like button.", "answer": "Thank you very much. And I wish you all the best to pass in your software, engineer, interview, have a brilliant day. Thank you very much.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Now one of the first most common behavioral interview questions is, can you describe a time when you worked well in a team?", "answer": "Now you have to give a specific situation when you collaborated as part of a team to achieve a common goal. So let me now give you a brilliant example answer that uses the star method, situation, task, action, and result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0244}
{"question": "Can you describe a time when you worked well in a team?", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous role, I worked as part of a team to launch a new company product. My task was to collaborate with my team and different company departments to ensure the company's new product sales were strong. I initiated a team meeting to brainstorm ideas. After the meeting, we had a list of five great ideas ranging from targeting new customers on social media to offering previous customers a discount code, and also prominently displaying the new product on the company's website homepage. We then allocated tasks to team members based on their strengths with a clear brief. Those with marketing skills took care of social media, advertising, and the IT department arranged for a homepage upgrade. By having a plan, ensuring everyone new, or combined objectives, and setting a timeline for implementation, the product was launched with great success yielding a 17% increase in sales compared to previous launches. So that is a brilliant example answer that uses a star method that is guaranteed to score highly with any hiring manager during a job interview. Let's now move on to the second most common behavioral interview question. And that is, tell me about a time you faced a challenging problem at work.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0048}
{"question": "How did you solve it?", "answer": "So let me give you another brilliant example answer again that uses the fantastic star method.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0625}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you faced a challenging problem at work. How did you solve it?", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous job, I noticed that we had received several negative online reviews, which were starting to impact sales. My task was to investigate the cause of the negative reviews to ensure the company succeeded. After reading all of the negative reviews and speaking to customers on the telephone, I established that there had been unacceptable delays in them receiving their orders. Further investigation revealed that a supplier was failing to meet their contract requirements to deliver all goods directly to customers within 48 hours. After contacting the supplier, they could not provide adequate reasons for the delay. With the permission of my manager, I sourced a new supplier with a reputation for quality and speed of delivery. After signing a contract with the new supplier, that included penalties for late delivery, customer satisfaction and online reviews improved significantly. So that is another really good example answer again that uses the star method of situation task action and result. It's a brilliant example of when you have took action to solve a difficult problem at work. Now don't go anywhere because I still have many more behavioral interview questions and top scoring answers to give you. But when you are ready, click the link in the top right hand corner of the video and you can head straight through to my website, passmain to view.com, where you can instantly download these slides plus my full set of 17 top scoring scripted answers to behavioral interview questions. But here is the next question that comes up all the time in job interviews.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0037}
{"question": "Describe a situation where you have to make a quick decision under pressure.", "answer": "So this example answer is also useful for the question, tell me about the time when you have to work under pressure. Here is my brilliant example star method answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0333}
{"question": "Describe a situation where you have to make a quick decision under pressure.", "answer": "In a previous role, I gave a presentation to my team on improving customer service standards, part way through the presentation the project has stopped working. Now my task was to continue delivering the presentation using a different format. Now I remained calm and quickly assessed my options. There was a flip chart in the room, so I delivered my presentation from memory using a more engaging presentation style. I asked the team during the presentation, how they felt we could improve customer service standards while also incorporating what I could remember from my presentation slides. At the end of the presentation, my manager praised my quick thinking and everyone on the team felt a presentation was more effective due to the increased audience engagement. So that is a really good example answer. When you are thinking on your feet, you are under pressure, but you make a quick decision that enables you to achieve your objective. It is a brilliant example answer again that uses our star method. Behavioral interview question number four, tell me about the time you had a conflict with a coworker.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0108}
{"question": "How did you handle it?", "answer": "Now this is a really difficult question to answer, but let me give you another top scoring response that uses the star method.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time you had a conflict with a coworker. How did you handle it?", "answer": "I overheard a colleague making inappropriate comments towards a new team member in a previous role. My task was to challenge their behavior and also educate them on why their actions were hurtful and how they went against company policy. I calmly challenged them while they were making the comments. They became defensive. I asked to speak to them privately. During the meeting, I outlined the company's policy on inappropriate behavior before explaining how their comments were upsetting to the new team member who needed our support while integrating into the team. After listening, they agreed not to repeat their comments before apologizing to the new team member. Now, at the next team meeting, I reinforced to all team members the importance of mutual respect in the workplace. That is a really good answer because you are not afraid to challenge inappropriate behavior. You have a conflict, but you are able to resolve it for the team's benefit. It's another really good top scoring answer that will definitely impress any hiring manager. Behavioral Interview Question Number Five.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Can you give an example of when you made a mistake at work? How did you handle it?", "answer": "Now, do not say, I never make mistakes. If you do, you will probably fail your interview. This question, this behavioral question, is assessing your willingness to take ownership of your mistakes and also improve. So, let me give you my star method answer to this difficult behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.02}
{"question": "Can you give an example of when you made a mistake at work? How did you handle it?", "answer": "Here we go. I accidentally gave a customer incorrect pricing information on the telephone for a product they wanted to purchase. As soon as I got off the phone, I realized the information I had provided was inaccurate. I needed to take responsibility for the mistake and contact the customer to explain what had happened. Before calling the customer, I planned what I would say and the solution I would offer them. I called the customer to apologize. I was honest, sincere, and empathetic before telling them the correct price. Now, because the actual price was outside of their budget, I gave them several alternative products that I felt would better suit their needs. I also provided a 10% discount on the price due to my mistake and the inconvenience it had caused. Now, the customer thanked me for my honesty and they took up the offer of a 10% discount. To ensure the same mistake was not made again, I created a product pricing list sheet and placed it next to my phone, so that I had the correct pricing information directly in front of me when talking to customers. That is a really good answer. It shows that you take ownership of any mistake you make, you apologise, you are honest. You also take action to help deliver excellent customer service because you are offering a 10% discount, but you are then taking steps to make sure the same mistake never happens again. And that is crucial when answering that common behavioral interview question. Let's now move on to question number six.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0038}
{"question": "Describe a time when you took the lead on a project or task without being asked.", "answer": "Now, this is a really difficult answer, but let me give you another top scoring star method response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a time when you took the lead on a project or task without being asked, here we go.", "answer": "In my previous role, I noticed a recurring issue. Many customers were struggling to use one of our products. This led to a surging complaints and an increased workload for customer service agents who spent at least five minutes per call, explaining basic product functions. Now, despite this being a persistent issue, no proactive steps had been taken to resolve it. I decided to take the lead and find a solution to improve customer service standards. I initiated a solution by designing clear step-by-step instructions to be included in every product package. To ensure these instructions were used, I collaborated with colleagues to test them and refine the wording. Additionally, I proposed creating a short instructional video with a QR code printed on the packaging, allowing customers to scan and watch a demonstration. Now, the implementation of the solution led to a significant reduction in customer complaints and customer service agents were able to redirect their time to more complex inquiries. Now, ultimately, this improved overall customer satisfaction and brand perception. That, I am sure you will agree, is a brilliant, top scoring answer that's going to help you pass your interview. Behavioral interview question number seven, give me an example of when you had to collaborate with a difficult colleague. Wow, this is a really top one to answer, but let me give you a great response again that uses our star method situation task action and result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Give me an example of when you had to collaborate with a difficult colleague.", "answer": "Here we go. In a previous role, a long-serving team member was constantly late with task completion and they often spread this information to other team members about the direction of the company creating dissatisfaction and low morale. Now, because I cared about the company, I decided to speak to them about their words and actions to increase productivity and also improve team morale. Now, I asked to speak to them privately away from the other team members. I explained that their timekeeping was setting a poor example to the rest of the team and also asked them what they hoped to gain from spreading disinformation. I gave them several examples of false information they had given to the team and it also raised concerns about how their words were starting to affect team morale. Once I reinforced how important their experience and expertise were to the team and how they had a duty to help create a positive work environment, they agreed to change their ways. Now, several weeks later, I noticed a marked improvement in their work output and attitude. So that's a really good example where you are not afraid to deal with a difficult colleague to achieve a successful outcome. It's great because you are saying you care about the company and you want the team to be effective. So you are being calm and professional in your actions. It's a really good example response. Let's now move on to behavioral interview question number eight.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0079}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you have to act quickly to solve a difficult problem.", "answer": "Here is a fantastic top scoring answer that uses the star method this will definitely impress every hiring manager. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to act quickly to solve a difficult problem.", "answer": "At my last job, I received a call from a local hotel informing me that the company scheduled meeting the following day could not be held due to a flood that had occurred at the hotel overnight. Now, 20 people were due to attend the meeting. I decided to show leadership skills and act quickly to source a new venue for the meeting. I called around suitable alternative venues in the local area and chose one that was cost effective close to transport links and could provide refreshments during the meeting. Once the venue had been confirmed, I informed my manager about the situation and my actions. He thanked me for my quick thinking actions before permitting me to contact all meeting attendees with the updated venue change. Now, that is another great response. Now you will see that we have covered eight behavioral interview questions. Now here is a list of the other behavioral interview questions that come up all the time during job interviews question number nine.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you received constructive criticism. How did you respond?", "answer": "Question number 10.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a situation where you have to persuade others to see things your way.", "answer": "Question 11.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when your actions had a positive impact on a team.", "answer": "Behavioral interview question 12.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you went above and beyond at work.", "answer": "Number 13.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a time in your work when you dealt with ambiguity.", "answer": "Wow, that is a really tricky one to answer. Question 14.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to make an important decision with limited information.", "answer": "Number 15.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you helped to co-worker learn a new skill or develop an existing one.", "answer": "Number 16.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to adapt to significant changes at work.", "answer": "Finally, question number 17.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a situation where you had multiple deadlines to meet. How did you prioritize your work?", "answer": "So there's 17 most common behavioral interview questions. Now if you want to download the answers I have just given you plus brilliant star method answers to those other questions. I mean, you get brilliant responses to all 17 click that link right now in the top right and corner of the video. You can head straight through to my website to passmain interview.com and you can instantly download these slides with those eight behavioral interview questions and answers plus you get top scoring responses. To the remainder of those questions, I just showed you on the previous slide. Click the link to get them right now. Also, don't forget to hit that subscribe button. I am serious. Thousands of you literally thousands and thousands of you are passing your job interviews at the first attempt. I am very passionate about helping you achieve your career goals. I can only help you when you are subscribed. Please hit the like button because a lot of time and effort goes into making these videos. And if I see you liking the content that motivates me to create more for you and also don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. I am always an absolute honor and a pleasure to connect with like my professional such as yourself. Thank you very much for watching and I wish you the very best for passing your job interview. Have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0157}
{"question": "So question number one, why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "Answer option A, say you want to work for Amazon because it is a place you will get decent pay and benefits while working alongside happy and positive people.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Answer option B, say you want to work for Amazon because it is an innovative company that is always moving forward and you will get to put your skills, qualities and experience to good use while working alongside other like minded professionals or answer options C, say you want to work for Amazon because it is the next stage in your career development and you only want to work for the best company, which answer will you choose for question number one? Tell me in the comments section below the video, here's your timer.", "answer": "Okay question number two of our Amazon mock interview, give me an example of a time when you couldn't find a solution to a problem.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Would you choose answer option A? Tell the interviewer you have never been in a situation where you couldn't find a solution to a problem, would you choose answer option B?", "answer": "Give the interviewer a specific situation where you genuinely couldn't find a solution to a problem and what you learned from the experience or answer option C give the interviewer a specific situation where you genuinely couldn't find a solution to a problem and to overcome this challenge you utilize the skills knowledge and experience of the people in your team and then tell the interviewer what you learned from the experience, which would you choose A, B or C, here is your timer. Amazon mock interview question number three.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had a conflict with a work colleague. Would you choose answer option A? Tell the interviewer about a time you experienced conflict with a work colleague and how you quickly took steps to resolve it amicably for the benefit of the wider team or would you choose answer option B? Tell the interviewer you've never experienced conflict with a work colleague and that you tend to get on with everyone or answer option C?", "answer": "Tell the interviewer about a time when you experience conflict with a work colleague and how you asked your manager for guidance on how to resolve it. Answer option A, B or C, which would you choose, here's a time. Amazon mock interview question number four.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you were going to be late to with a deadline. Would you choose A, B or C?", "answer": "A, tell the interviewer you've never been late with a deadline and that you always make sure you complete all tasks and projects on time.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Answer option B, tell the interviewer about a time when you did fail to meet a deadline and what you learned from the situation or answer option C?", "answer": "Tell the interviewer about a time when you thought you were going to be late with a deadline but you turned things around by working late and putting in the extra hours needed here's a time. Amazon mock interview question number five.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What will you do if you get offered a great job from another company with a better salary after 12 months of starting worker Amazon? Would you tell the interviewer you are committed to working at Amazon and the money is not a motivating factor so you would turn down the job offer. Answer option B, tell the interviewer you want to stay working at Amazon and that you would discuss your salary with your manager to see if a rise was available or answer option C, tell the interviewer it is perfectly normal for you to move jobs after 12 months and you would seriously consider the job offer if it was from a reputable company which would you choose?", "answer": "Here's a timer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Amazon mock interview question number six if we asked you to complete a task you'd never done before how would you react?", "answer": "Answer option A, tell the interviewer you would agree to do the task quickly find out how to do it before then completing it on time and to a high standard. Option B, tell the interviewer you would suggest they see if anyone else in the team could do it because they may have the experience needed or answer option C, tell the interviewer you would ask them for help or guidance on how to complete the task and then do it to the best of your ability. A, B, or C in the comments section below here's a timer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Amazon mock interview question number seven tell me about a time when you took a calculated risk how would you answer this Amazon interview question?", "answer": "Option A, tell the interviewer you do not take risks because it would be wrong to put an organization in unnecessary danger. Answer option B, tell the interviewer about a time when you took a risk at work after you'd carefully weighed up the options and realize the benefits to the organization of taking the risk far outweigh the consequences or options C, tell the interviewer about a time when you considered taking a risk at work but after careful consideration you decided not to proceed with it. A, B, or C, here is a timer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Amazon mock interview question number eight, how would you deal with a rude customer?", "answer": "Answer option A, tell the interviewer you would inform the customer that you would not tolerate rude language or behavior from them and that they must stop before you proceeded to help them. Option B, tell the interviewer you would not take their comments or actions personally, you would listen to the establish what the problem was and then go all out to try and resolve any issues for them or C, tell the interviewer you would listen to the customer carefully, inform them that you would not tolerate rude behavior before then taking steps to resolve any issues for them. A, B, or C. A, B, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, or C, Amazon mock interview question number nine, given an example of a time when you asked a customer for feedback, would you answer it A, tell the interviewer about a time when you asked a customer for feedback, then explaining detail how you used the feedback to improve the efficiency and performance of the business or answer option B, tell the interviewer about a time when you asked a customer for feedback, and then passed on the information to your manager or supervisor for them to implement, or answer option C, tell the interviewer you've never been in a position where you've had to ask a customer for feedback. A, B, or C in the comments section below, here is a time.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Amazon mock interview question ten, how would you build trust with your work colleagues at Amazon? Would you say A?", "answer": "Say you would build trust by taking steps to get to know your work colleagues, by offering to support them in their work, and by making sure the work you do is to a high standard and on time, answer option B, say you would build trust by meeting up with your work colleagues outside of work to socialise. This is the best way to get to know your work colleagues on a personal level, which will then help to build trust quicker than any other method you know, or answer option C, say you will build trust by keeping your head down, carrying out your work to a high standard and on time. And if your work colleagues see that you are reliable, they will trust you. A, B, or C, here is a timer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0074}
{"question": "And finally, question eleven before we start working through the answers together, how would you deal with a work colleague who was resisting to help you?", "answer": "Answer option A, say you would ignore them and seek help from someone else. You are a resilient person and you will always find a way around a problem. Answer option B, say you would inform your supervisor that they were not being helpful. So they could take the necessary action, or C, say you would take steps to build a better relationship with them and try and find out why they were resisting to help you. To achieve your goals at work, you will need the assistance of your work colleagues. A, B, or C, which one would you choose in the comment section below, here's a timer. Okay, well done for reaching the end. Now, we are going to work through the answers to the mock interview in a second. But it's important you tell me how many you got correct out of 11 in the comment section below the video. And just quickly before we work through those answers, when you're ready, if you click that link in the top right hand corner of the video, head over to my website, passmaintovie.com and you can download my full set of 22. Great answers to top Amazon interview questions. So if you want model exam pal answers to help you prepare for your Amazon interview, make sure you check that out once we've worked through these answers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0085}
{"question": "So question one was, why do you want to work for Amazon A, B, or C?", "answer": "I would choose B. Say you want to work for Amazon because it is an innovative company that is always moving forward and you will get to put your skills, quality and experience to good use while working alongside other like-minded professionals. Question number two, give me an example of a time when you couldn't find a solution to a problem, I would choose answer options C. Give the interviewer a specific situation where you genuinely couldn't find a solution and to overcome it, you utilize the skills and knowledge and experience of the people in your team and then say what you learn from the experience. That's the best way to answer that Amazon interview question. Question three, tell me about a time you had a conflict with a colleague, choose A, tell the interviewer about a time you experience conflict with a work colleague and how you quickly took steps to resolve it amicably for the benefit of the wider team. We don't want to be informing our manager or supervisor, we need to sort out the conflict ourselves for the benefit of the team. Question four, tell me about a time when you were going to be late with a deadline, I would choose C, tell the interviewer about a time when you thought you were going to be late, but you turned things around by working late and putting in the extra hours needed. That's what I would want to hear from you, joining that Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0039}
{"question": "Question five, what will you do if you get offered a great job from another company with a better salary after 12 months of starting worker Amazon these only one answer option?", "answer": "I would choose A, okay because I'm committed to Amazon I've already agreed to salary so I would turn it down because I believe Amazon is the best company anyway.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0312}
{"question": "Question six, if we asked you to complete a task you'd never done before, how would you react?", "answer": "Again I'd choose A, tell the interviewer you would agree to do the task, find out yourself how to do it and then complete it on time into a high standard. Question seven, tell me about a time when you took a calculated risk, this is a difficult one but I would go for B. Tell the interviewer about a time when you took a risk at work after you'd carefully weighed up the options and realised the benefits to the organisation of taking a risk that it far outweigh the consequences. Amazon takes calculated risks, it would not be as successful as it is if it had never taken a risk.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Question eight, how would you deal with a rude customer?", "answer": "Amazon always puts customers first so I would choose B. Tell the interviewer you wouldn't take their comments or actions personally. You would listen to the customer, establish what the problem was and then go all out to try and resolve any issues for them. Question nine, given an example of a time when you asked a customer for feedback, again Amazon always puts the customer first so I would say, tell the interviewer about a time when you did ask a customer for feedback and you used the feedback to improve the efficiency and performance of the business.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.02}
{"question": "Number ten, how would you build trust with your work colleagues at Amazon? 100% A, say you would build trust by taking steps to get to know them, by offering to support them, by making sure the work you do is to a high standard on time and 11, how would you deal with a work colleague who was resisting you?", "answer": "To help you, C, say you would take steps to build a better relationship, find out why they were resisting you, because to achieve your goals, you have to work with work colleague, you need their assistance so that's the one I would choose. So tell me in the comments section below how many you got right out of 11.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0328}
{"question": "Did you get 11 out of 11?", "answer": "And the next thing of course, if you want example answers to all Amazon interview questions, click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video and head over to my website, passmaintevue.com. I hope you've enjoyed that tutorial and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon interview and have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What if I said the wrong thing?", "answer": "Wow, they both look really professional.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Am I dressed correctly?", "answer": "If a job you've applied to has a lot of other applicants, chances are you might find yourself starting the interview process in a group setting. But don't be alarmed. Group interviews are a great way for employers to get an initial read on you and your work ethic. And above all, they want to see how you communicate and how you work with a team. While they might seem daunting at first, they don't have to be if you go in with the right mindset. Today, we're going to highlight some best practices for a group interview. With them in mind, securing a one-on-one interview after the group interview should be no problem. Morning, everyone. I'm Ann. Good morning. Nice to meet you. Chloe. I'll Chloe.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What's great here is that all three candidates are early to the interview.", "answer": "That's a must. But notice how the first two weren't speaking when Ann walked in. Avoid the urge to check your phone or sit silently while waiting for the interviewer to arrive. Like Ann did, start the conversation right away and get to know the other candidates. This will only help during the actual interview. Speaking of, the interviewer has now arrived. So let's get into it.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0286}
{"question": "Chloe, how would you describe yourself?", "answer": "Let's see. I've worked in customer service for the last six years, starting in the restaurant industry and then eventually making my way to retail. When asked during a group interview about yourself, don't just recite what can be found on your resume. Share a personal story. Something that the interviewer will remember. I am extremely passionate about working with people. I was named Employee of the Month two times in my current role because of my problem solving nature in those situations. And I'm excited to hopefully do that soon here as well. That was a great finish.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't be afraid to brag a little during a group interview when asked about yourself.", "answer": "Be confident and bring up your accomplishments, especially if it pertains to the job you're applying for. This will help differentiate you from the other candidates. Let's continue. Michael, tell me about a time you work through a challenging situation. I thrive in challenges. There was this one time that the computer's going down in the middle of the holiday rush and my co-workers started to panic. So I told them, I'll handle it. I briefly close the store until I was able to get the computers back up and running. While Michael shows initiative in his response, there's a glaring problem with his answer. He only focuses on himself. Employers ask questions about past challenges because they want to see if you're a team player. You can show your leadership capabilities, but also recognize it takes more than just you to get a job done. Moving along.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0065}
{"question": "And how will your strength benefit our company?", "answer": "Great question. Above all, I think my team focus mentality makes me a great fit for this role. Team dynamic is so... Oh, wait, sorry. One final thing I wanted to add to what I said before is that I feel very comfortable leading a team. Stop right there. One of the biggest mistakes you can make during a group interview is cutting another candidate off or trying to speak over them. All group interviews can kick up our competitive nature. Trying to make yourself the loudest in the room will only raise red flags with the employer. Wait until a candidate is done speaking before asking the interviewer if you can chime in. Let's go back to Anne and this time without the interruption.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0079}
{"question": "Anne, how will your strength benefit our company?", "answer": "That's a great question. Above all, I think my team focus mentality makes me a great fit for this role. Team dynamic is so important to me and I know that when we're in sync as a unit, we'll have the best outcomes with our customers. I'm also very patient in stressful situations. I love a Chloe said earlier about working through issues with customers. Often my coworkers will come to me in those situations, especially when they get a little bit heated, because I'm able to diffuse them and come up with a solution. That was brilliant. There's so much to like in this answer. Anne made teamwork one of her core strengths, which will be a good sign to any employer. Not only that, but she specifically referenced another candidate's answer in her response and added to it. This shows that she is listening to the room and also moving the conversation forward. Well done. While a group interview might be out of your comfort zone, there's no need to fear heading into one. Be yourself, speak confidently, listen to what the other candidates are saying and don't speak over them. You'll be on your way to that next round of a solo interview in no time. For more interview help, make sure to like and subscribe. Oh, that's funny.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0172}
{"question": "Are you going to keep us in?", "answer": "Hello, Charlie. Money.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "So to all the end of your Amazon phone interview, the hiring manager will likely say to you, do you have any questions for me?", "answer": "I recommend you ask three smart questions. Here's three brilliant ones that you can write down on your paper and having front of you at your Amazon phone interview question number one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What opportunities are there for professional growth in this role?", "answer": "That's a brilliant question because one of the leadership principles is higher and develop the best. Now you can only be the best you can possibly be if you are open to continuous improvement and professional growth.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "The second question to ask is, what are some of the biggest challenges that team faces in consistently exceeding customer expectations and how could I contribute to solving them?", "answer": "That's a brilliant question. Now the number one, the first Amazon leadership principle is customer obsession. Now you and I know having used Amazon services many, many times in the past that they have outstanding customer service. And they have outstanding customer service because they are obsessive with their customers and that question shows you understand how important customer obsession is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "And the final question to ask is, can you describe the team's culture and working style?", "answer": "So that shows that you are a close collaborator and you understand how important team culture is. So those are three great questions to ask at the end of your Amazon phone interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0606}
{"question": "Don't forget to write them down and ask those questions and any other ones you want to ask at the end of your phone interview.", "answer": "Okay, let's now start working through the Amazon phone interview questions. My tips and example answers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget very soon.", "answer": "I will tell you where you can download my 17 brilliant Amazon phone interview questions and answers. Question number one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Now obviously this will come at the start of your phone interview. Let me give you two tips for giving a great response tip number one. So this will likely be the first question you must answer at your Amazon phone interview. Make sure you practice your answer several times before your interview because that will help demonstrate good communication skills.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0164}
{"question": "Don't forget if you are on your phone they can't see you.", "answer": "So I recommend you have your answers prepared printed out in front of you. And you can refer to them as a when you need to during the Amazon phone interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0323}
{"question": "Don't forget soon.", "answer": "I will tell you where you can download my example responses and tip number two. I will answer to this first Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "You can talk about the skills you have that match the Amazon job description. The experience you can bring to Amazon. Details of any achievements you have gained in your life so far and also don't forget to reference those 16 leadership principles. So here is a brilliant example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.037}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Here we go. Thank you for the opportunity to undertake a phone interview to work at Amazon. I am a diligent collaborative loyal and self motivated employee with experience to match the job description and Amazon's 16 leadership principles. I have held several job roles that have prepared me well for the role of insert the job role you are applying for at Amazon. My experiences diverse and includes working on small and large teams helping streamline company processes and reducing costs and delivering on time sensitive projects. I am a high achiever. In my last position I won employee of the month and was praised by my manager for how I constantly asked customers for feedback based on their experience with the company to help drive improvements and sales. I have completed training courses in health and safety, Microsoft office applications, manual handling and customer service. My experience, obsession with customer service, knowledge, passion for this industry and unwavering commitment to continuous improvement mean. I will be a great asset to the Amazon team and I look forward to sharing additional details in the phone interview regarding my suitability for this position and how I commit the requirements of the 16 leadership principles. I love that response. It's a great in depth answer to that first question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Here is the next question that comes up all the time during Amazon phone interviews.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why Amazon? Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "Here's two great tips. Tip number one. So this next common Amazon phone interview question assesses your motivations for wanting to work at this brilliant organization. In my opinion, Amazon is the greatest organization in the world. I don't say that lightly. I think they are fantastic. Now lots of people want to work for Amazon but this question is assessing your motivations for choosing this brilliant organization. Make sure you demonstrate passion for wanting to work at Amazon and also give more than one reason for wanting to work there and tip number two. Good things to include in your answer are the fact that their Amazon tries to be the earth's best employer. The positive workplace culture at Amazon, the work life balance and also how those 16 leadership principles align with your values and your strong work ethic. So here is another brilliant example answer to help you share your Amazon phone interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0126}
{"question": "Why Amazon?", "answer": "Here we go. I want to work at Amazon for four reasons. The first is that Amazon strives to be the earth's best employer. That means I will get to collaborate on exciting projects at the cutting edge of technology and innovation. The second reason is that Amazon is a safe workplace and my ideas and suggestions will be valued and trialed. My research tells me that Amazon offers a workplace culture where there is the opportunity for everyone to contribute to the company's success. The third reason I want to work at Amazon is that having used your products and services for several years, I have been impressed with how you treat your customers. Outstanding customer service is rare in business today and your obsession with customers has convinced me that you push the boundaries of innovation. I will get to work alongside some of the brightest and most talented people out there. And finally, I want to work at Amazon because I genuinely believe in your 16 leadership principles. Having studied these, I am confident my professional values and strong work ethic will empower me to have a successful career at Amazon. That is another brilliant answer that will help you pass your Amazon phone interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions tips and answers to give you. But when you are ready, click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, plus main to view.com and you can download my full set of 17 Amazon phone interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are working through together today. Here is an next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What do you know about Amazon?", "answer": "Tip number one. Now I strongly recommend you research Amazon before your phone interview. If the hiring manager asks you this question and you then struggle to give an answer, you will not get hired. Tip number two, I strongly recommend you read Amazon's latest new stories and find out what their plans are. You are all of this by going to the website about Amazon.com. That should be your number one website to visit to research Amazon before your phone interview. But here is my brilliant example answer for you to use.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What do you know about Amazon?", "answer": "Amazon is one of the world's largest and most influential companies known for its customer centric approach, innovation and operational excellence. It was founded by Jeff Bezos in 1994 as an online bookstore and has since evolved into a global technology and the commerce giant offering a vast range of products and services including cloud computing artificial intelligence digital streaming and smart devices. Another Amazon's key strengths is its relentless focus on customer obsession which is the first of its 16 leadership principles. This commitment drives Amazon's innovation such as Prime which offers fast shipping and exclusive entertainment and Amazon web services, the leading cloud computing platform used by businesses worldwide. Amazon also prioritizes efficiency and continuous improvement evident in its advanced logistics network automation and AI driven innovation such as Alexa and Amazon go stores. Additionally the company is committed to sustainability with its climate pledge aiming to reach net zero carbon emissions by 2040. Amazon's workplace culture is built around high standards, ownership and a bias for action encouraging employees to take initiative and think big. These principles have helped Amazon maintain its leadership position across industries from e-commerce to cloud computing. For all, Amazon is not just a retailer, it's a technology driven company that constantly evolves to meet customer needs while promoting a culture of innovation and leadership. I am particularly excited about the opportunity to contribute to Amazon's ongoing success. So that is a brilliant comprehensive answer that shows you know a lot about Amazon don't forget you can print that answer off by clicking the link in the top right hand corner of the video and having it in front of you during your Amazon phone interview. So this is a common Amazon phone interview question that assesses the leadership principles of our right a lot bias for action and ownership. Tip number two don't forget to use the star method to structure your answer situation task action and results. So here is my star method example answer to help you pass your Amazon phone interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0114}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you faced a difficult problem that had several possible solutions here we go.", "answer": "In my previous role one of our suppliers kept letting the company down their inconsistency resulted in delays to customer orders which was unacceptable. The delays also started to impact the company's online reviews so I decided to take action. It was my task to analyze the possible solutions to this problem and decide on a course of action that benefited our valued customers and the company's reputation. During my investigation I spoke directly to the company supplier they informed me that the delays were due to a supply chain issue and that this would be resolved soon. At the end of my investigation I had several options. Give the supplier the opportunity to put things right or choose a new supplier. After weighing the pros and cons and consulting other team members I decided to find a new supplier. The current suppliers unreliability had gone on too long and our valued customers had suffered enough which was unacceptable. After spending several days researching new suppliers I found one with an excellent track record of delivery times. I insisted that they sign a contract that included penalties for late deliveries and normal service for our customers quickly resumed. My manager praised my leadership skills and customer obsession. That is a brilliant example response to that common Amazon phone interview question and you can see how effective the star method is. And that response demonstrates lots of the leadership principles you are taking responsibility for a difficult situation. You are consulting your team members and then you are taking action that improves the customer service standards and improves the reputation of your employer. Here is the next question. This one comes up all the time during Amazon phone interviews.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0034}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "Tip number one. Now this next common Amazon phone interview question is assessing three things. Self awareness and the desire to improve.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Do not say you have never made a mistake.", "answer": "Tip number two again. Make sure you use the star method to structure your answer. Situation task action and result. Here is a brilliant example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "In my previous role, while handling multiple tasks, I sent an important email to a client without thoroughly reviewing it. After sending it, I realized it contained several spelling and grammar errors. Since this email reflected both my professionalism and the company standards I knew I had made a mistake. It was my responsibility to ensure all client communications work clear, professional and error-free. I needed to address the situation immediately to maintain the client's confidence in our company. As soon as I realized the mistake, I took ownership of it. I promptly sent a follow-up email to the client, apologising for the errors and attaching a corrected version of the message. Additionally, I called the client to acknowledge the mistake personally, reassure them of my commitment to high communications standards, and ensure they had the correct information. To prevent this from happening again, I installed the Grammally Chrome extension for Gmail, which helped me catch spelling and grammatical errors before sending any future emails. The client appreciated my prompt response and professionalism in handling the situation and our business relationship remains strong. Implementing Grammally significantly improved the accuracy and professionalism of my emails, ensuring that such mistakes did not happen again. So that is another really good example answer, and it shows that you take ownership for your mistakes, you are honest about them, but more importantly, you take steps to learn and improve so they don't happen again. Okay, now the next thing to do, to accelerate your learning even further, is click the link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, passmaintivue.com, and you can instantly download these slides of all the tips and sample answers plus my full set of 17 great answers to difficult Amazon phone interview questions. This guide comes as a PDF guide, which means you can have it in your inbox literally within two minutes from now by clicking that link. Also, please make sure you hit the subscribe button. Please give the video a like because that motivates me and make sure you connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an honor and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professional such as yourself. Thank you very much for watching and I wish you the very best for passing your Amazon phone interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0097}
{"question": "Interview question number two is why do you want this job?", "answer": "He is a great quick answer. I want this job because it is a role that I am very passionate about and I see my long-term career in this position. I also want this job because having researched your company, you are clearly innovative. You support your employees in their work and you are always striving to move forward and develop.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number three of our top 21 quick answers to interview questions is how did you hear about this position?", "answer": "Here's a great answer. I have held a keen interest in your company for several months now and I've been on the lookout for this role to be advertised to make sure I was notified as soon as the position was advertised, I kept a daily check on the local job boards. That's the best way to answer that common interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number four is what are your strengths?", "answer": "Now, this question is going to come up during your interview. Here's a great answer. My strengths include my ability to learn things very quickly. The fact that I am a people person, which means I will always be a positive role model for your company while stealing with your customers. And the fact that I see change as a positive thing and I will always embrace it for the better good of the company. That's a brilliant answer to that common interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are your strengths?", "answer": "Question number five is a difficult one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What's your biggest weakness?", "answer": "Here's a quick answer to it. My biggest weakness is the fact that I don't yet have much experience in talking to large groups of people. This is something I'm very keen to improve on. So if any opportunities were to arise in this position to gain experience in this area, I would certainly want to take advantage of that. That's a great answer to that question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0141}
{"question": "What's your biggest weakness? Interview question number six is how would you deal with conflict with a co worker?", "answer": "Here's a quick answer to help you. I would deal with the conflict by seeing if I was doing anything to contribute to the conflict before speaking to my co worker in private to find an amicable way forward that we were both comfortable with. I would always put the needs of my team first and try to overcome the conflict so we could quickly move forward. That's a great answer, a professional answer to that question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0127}
{"question": "How would you deal with conflict with a co worker? Question number seven of our 21 quick answers to common interview questions is where do you see yourself in five years?", "answer": "Here we go. I see myself hopefully working for your company, either in the same role or having gained advancement to a higher level. In five years, I would have also developed significantly and be seen as a trusted, reliable and productive member of the company.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number eight, what's your ideal work environment?", "answer": "This is a tricky one, but here's a great quick answer to help you. My ideal work environment is positive. Is one where everyone in the team seeks to continually grow and improve and where I would get to use my creative side to help the business grow and develop. That's a cracking answer to that interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What's your ideal work environment?", "answer": "Question number nine is one that's definitely going to come up during your job interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What experience do you have relevant to this role?", "answer": "Here's a quick answer. I have experience of dealing with clients and customers in a manner that is representative of a company's vision. I have experience of collaborating with other people in a team to achieve a common objective. And I also have experience of solving problems independently and completing time sensitive tasks under pressure. That's another great answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number 10 is how would other people describe you?", "answer": "Here's a great answer. My friends and previous co-workers have often described me as someone who is driven, enthusiastic and upbeat. I believe they would also describe me as someone they could turn to whenever they need an assistance. Someone they could rely on to help them out at short notice and someone who has a can-do attitude and that takes ownership of difficult situations. Interview question number 11 is a really difficult one and that is describe yourself in three words. Here's a great answer. I would describe myself as productive, commercially aware and self-multiply motivated. I am productive, which means you will always see me achieving good things for the business. I am commercially aware, which means I understand the importance of always doing a good job on time to help the business thrive. And I'm also self-motivated, which means I will take it by myself to quickly and diligently work through all tasks and duties to help the team achieve its objectives. Interview question number 12.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What's been your greatest achievement?", "answer": "Here we go. My greatest achievement was in my previous role where I helped the company increase sales. This was achieved by improving customer service standards and by thinking of different ways to help the business market its products via social media. That's a great answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number 13 is what do you do outside of work or they might say to you what are your hobbies and interests?", "answer": "Here's a quick answer. Outside of work, I like to keep myself fit and active and I visit the gym a few times a week. This keeps me motivated and it also helps to boost my concentration levels whilst I am at work. I am also a family person and I often spend time at weekends with those closest to me. Finally, I like to read self-development books and I always have a good book on the go at any one time. That's a great answer, a smart answer to that interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0208}
{"question": "What do you do outside of work? Interview question number 14 of our 21 quick answers to interview questions is what can you do for us that other candidates can't?", "answer": "Now you need to answer this question carefully. Here's a great quick answer. I can bring a diverse set of skills, qualities and experience to the team that I believe will help your business grow. I am a strong communicator and I will always try to solve problems without troubling my manager. I will always take care of your customers which in turn will increase sales. I can also bring a level of knowledge to the role that I believe is unrivaled and I will always work hard to ensure you see a positive return on your investment by hiring me. That's a cracking answer to that difficult interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number 15 is why do you want to work for us?", "answer": "Here we go. I want to work for your company because you are socially responsible. You have a strong set of workplace values that align with my own ambitions and aspirations and you have a brilliant track record of achievement. If I am successful, I can genuinely see myself working for your company for many years to come.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number 16 is how would you deal with a difficult customer?", "answer": "Here's a great answer. I would listen to the customer. I would ask them questions to establish their needs and I would try to establish a connection with them. At all times I would be professional and I would try to find a solution to their problem quickly and calmly. It would be my goal to keep the customer on board and to ensure they had a good experience with the company. That's a great answer that shows you are a smart employee. Interview question number 17 is a really difficult one and that is tell me about a time when you failed. Here's a really smart answer to help you pass your interview. In my last job, I was working as part of a team that failed to finish a project on time. Now we simply failed because we had not listened to the brief fully at the start of the project and things got missed. As soon as we realised we had made a mistake, we informed our manager, we apologised and we discussed what we had learned from the experience to make sure it never happened again. That's a smart answer because it shows the interviewer that you are honest and more importantly, you take responsibility for your mistakes and your failures.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Interview question number 18 is why do you want to leave your current job?", "answer": "Now you need to give a really short answer to this question. Here it is. I want to leave my job because I'm seeking a fresh challenge with an exciting and innovative company such as yours that has ambitious plans for the future. That's a great answer. Interview question number 19 is again definitely going to come up during your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "And that is why should we hire you?", "answer": "Now you need to be the stand out candidate in your response. Here's a quick short answer that's going to help you to post your interview. I believe you should hire me because I am a very fast learner and I need little supervision moving forward. I also believe you should hire me because I will represent your business positively and I will treat your customers well. I will also ensure I find ways to help the business grow whilst also helping you to save money by using resources in a frugal and responsible manner. That is a cracking answer to that question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why should we hire you?", "answer": "Interview question number 20.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What did you dislike about your previous job?", "answer": "This is a tough one. Here we go. There was only one thing that frustrated me slightly about my last job. And that was the fact that I felt we could have achieved so much more as a company. There were lots of opportunities in the market for us to expand and grow, but the company owners seemed satisfied with where the company was at. Interview question number 21.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0145}
{"question": "Do you have any questions for us?", "answer": "So at the end of the interview, they will say that to you. Here's a quick answer. Thank you. Yes, I have just three questions to ask, please.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0345}
{"question": "Question number one, what would you need me to concentrate on in the first 30 days of starting? Question number two, what are the plans for the company over the next five years? And finally, question number three, how has the position evolved over the years?", "answer": "So there's three smart questions to ask at the end of your interview. Now, if you would like to download all of these quick, short answers to common interview questions, click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video, head through to my website, pass my interview.com. And you can download my 21 short and quick answers to common interview questions. You can literally have this resource in your inbox within two minutes from now. So make sure you check out that link. Also, don't forget to subscribe to the channel. It's really important because I want to help you throughout your career. I could only do that if you were subscribed.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0248}
{"question": "Don't forget to hit the like button and you can also connect with me on LinkedIn.", "answer": "I put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always good to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0488}
{"question": "Don't forget to subscribe to the channel lots of you are passing your interviews as a result of the content I don't want you to miss out.", "answer": "And please just give the video a like because that tells me you find the content useful. And to make your life easier I have also placed the timestamps to each question in the description below the video. So if you want to jump to a particular question you can do that with ease by checking out the links in the description below the video. Let's get started. So the first Amazon behavioral interview question I recommend you prepare for is tell me about a time when you asked a customer for feedback. Now Amazon has been successful over the years because it fully understands the importance of the customer. It's what sets them apart from other online organizations. Now in your answer to this first behavioral interview question give a specific example of a situation when you sort feedback from a customer and then use it to the company's advantage. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0245}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you asked a customer for feedback here we go.", "answer": "I was dealing with a customer in a previous role on the telephone and they didn't sound particularly happy with our service. Now although they weren't making a direct complaint I could detect in their voice that they weren't entirely satisfied. I asked them how their experience had been whilst ordering from us and I found their response in lightning. They said our website was not easy to navigate and they were disappointed there was no option for a faster delivery time other than the standard postal service. I asked them a few questions about the issues they were experiencing online and I took notes as they spoke. Now after they had finished placing their order over the telephone I thanked them for their feedback. I then spoke to my manager to explain what the customer had said and I gave my opinion about how offering a faster delivery service.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Could increase revenue and customer satisfaction levels to which he agreed.", "answer": "Now two weeks later the navigation issues had been resolved and we had added a new next day service to the website which helped to increase sales and customer satisfaction levels moving forward. So that's a brilliant example of how you have detected that a customer is not happy. You have asked for feedback and you have then implemented their recommendations to the advantage of the company so it's a really good response. Here is the next Amazon behavioral interview question that I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0225}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you found a simple solution to a challenging problem.", "answer": "Now your ability to use your initiative in difficult situations will help you to stand out from the other candidates during your Amazon interview. My advice is to give an example when you considered your options carefully and then took decisive action to solve a problem at work. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0175}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you found a simple solution to a challenging problem.", "answer": "I was working on a technical project and it was late on a Friday afternoon. To finish my element of the project before the end of the working day I needed advice from another team member who was off on annual leave. Now this was really frustrating because he wasn't back at work until Monday but I needed to get my part of the project finished by the end of the day to ensure we stayed on track. Now I considered my options and I came up with a simple solution. I went on to the website StackOverflow.com to ask the question I needed the answer to and within a few minutes I had a response but I needed to double check the answer to make sure it was accurate. Now we always worked to very high standards in the team so it was vital I sought a second opinion. I then went on to the website Upwork.com and posted a job for a developer. I paid a developer for one hour of work to answer the same question. Now he confirmed the initial answer I'd received was correct and then went on and finished my element of the project by the clothes of office that day. That's a really good answer you have found a simple solution to a problem that could hinder the progress of your project. So you have found a way forward and that is what somebody would do who works for Amazon. They would find a way forward to solve their problem. Now don't go anywhere because I still have many more questions and answers to give you. But when you're ready click that link in the top right and corner of the video. It will take you through to my website PassMainTV.com and you can download my full set of 21 Amazon Behavioral Interview Questions and Top Scoring Answer including the ones we are working through together today. But here's the next question to help you prepare.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0058}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to make a quick decision that was going to have a significant impact on the business.", "answer": "Now this is a very difficult interview question to answer correctly. My advice is to demonstrate to the Amazon hiring manager that you are not afraid to make quick decisions and you always weigh up the options before deciding on the best course of action to take. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to make a quick decision that was going to have a significant impact on the business.", "answer": "Here we go. I was working in a previous role deputizing for my manager who was away on annual leave. Now a problem occurred with one of our suppliers who informed us that they were not able to deliver the products we had ordered for another 14 days. Now this delay would impact negatively on our customers. So I needed to make a quick decision. I had the option of either contacting all customers to apologize for the delay which was out of our control or I could quickly source an alternative supplier which would then eat into the company's profits. But the customers would still receive their orders on time. Now in total 48 customers will be affected by the delay. So I decided to quickly source a new supplier and write off the profits for those sales. Now in this situation I felt the potential negative impact on our business far outweigh the profit we would have made from those 48 sales. So that shows that you're not afraid to make a decision that's in the best interests of the organization. And because there's so many orders you believe it's the best course of action to take to protect your customers and don't forget Amazon is very customer focused. Here is the next example. Amazon behavioral interview question that I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0172}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to say no to a customer or client.", "answer": "Now saying no to a customer or client is a really difficult thing to do especially if you're like Amazon and you always focusing tentally on the customers. But it must be done with professionalism and attack now although customer services crucial to the success of Amazon. It also has a responsibility to be frugal and to ensure it maintains profitability. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0282}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to say no to a customer or client.", "answer": "In my previous role I was working as part of a project team that was responsible for creating and building a team. And building a time sensitive website for an important client. Now the client was difficult to deal with and very demanding. But I enjoyed working with him because he tested my skills, my knowledge, my project management capabilities. Now the client started to ask for additions to the website specification early on that were outside of the initial agreed scope. I assessed his requests and I wasn't comfortable agreeing to them because they were too expensive. And I felt this would set a precedent for further additions to be requested. I called him on the telephone and I was totally honest and transparent when refusing his requests. Now although he was disappointed because of the amount of money he was spending with us, he respected my decision. Now whenever I work on projects I have a responsibility to balance going above and beyond for a customer or client with the profitability of the business I'm working for. So that shows that you are not afraid to say no, you are totally transparent with the customer or the client when speaking to them and you are professional in doing so.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0094}
{"question": "Don't forget customer service is very, very important but you also have that responsibility to make sure that the business is successful and profitable.", "answer": "Here is the next Amazon Behavioral Interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you were able to influence change in an organisation by only asking questions.", "answer": "Wow, this is a tough question to answer correctly. In your response, demonstrate you always put the company you are working for first and you ask questions in the right way to achieve the desired outcome. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What I'm talking about a time when you were able to influence change in an organisation by only asking questions.", "answer": "Here we go. I was attending a meeting with other team members and we were discussing the action plan for the creation of a new company product that was going to be built. Now part way through the meeting, one of the team members suggested that we could save considerable sums of money if we used a cheaper product part. Now most people in the meeting felt this was a good idea but I wasn't comfortable. So I asked him three questions.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.012}
{"question": "The first question was, could we be sure that by using the cheaper part the product would be entirely safe? The second question was, how would product reviews and customer trust be impacted if someone found out the part we had used was cheap, especially when we were planning on charging a premium for that product?", "answer": "Finally the third question I asked was, were we satisfied that by using a cheaper product part, this was in line with the company's customer service charter and values. Now just by asking those three simple questions, I managed to convince everyone that using a cheaper product part was not a good idea. That's a clever answer to that very difficult Amazon interview question. Here is the next Amazon behavioral interview question I want you to prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to work with incomplete data or missing information.", "answer": "Now this is a common Amazon behavioral interview question. The question is clearly assessing your ability to find a way around a problem when you have incomplete or missing information. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0256}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to work with incomplete data or missing information.", "answer": "I'd been given a task by my manager that required me to create a risk assessment for a new piece of machinery we were going to be using at work. Now the machinery was used to help men's of staff get boxes down from height in the warehouse and I was required to ensure a full risk assessment was completed and disseminated amongst the staff. Now whilst checking over the machinery, I noticed the manufacturers operating instructions were not complete, regarding the level of personal protective equipment that must be worn while operating the machinery. So I tried to contact the manufacturer but they were not available. Now because the risk assessment needed to be completed that same day, I went ahead with the task anyway, but I put in additional precautions in respect of the PPE that must be worn during the machinery's operation. Now this included the wearing of a hard hat, safety goggles, a high visibility jacket and steel tow cap to shoes. Now despite having missing information, I was still able to carry out a suitable assessment to complete that task. I determined the risk from injury to be high after carrying out a careful analysis of the use of the machinery. Here is the next question to help you prepare for your Amazon interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0045}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had no choice but to work with limited resources.", "answer": "Now most people will not work with limited resources. They will wait until they have the right level of resources and support available.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, someone who works at Amazon will find a solution to this issue and they will still get the task or project completed on time.", "answer": "And this again is one of the reasons why Amazon has been so successful in what it does. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0385}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had no choice but to work with limited resources here we go.", "answer": "I was working as part of a team developing a new software tool for one of the company's clients. It was a big client and one that was extremely valuable to the business. Now halfway through the project two members of Starfell ill and they were going to be off work for a couple of weeks. Now this situation put the project in danger of not being completed on time. So I assessed our options. Now no other members of Starfell were available to help from other departments and there was no way I was going to extend the deadline. We simply had to get the project finished. So I decided to assess which tasks could be outsourced. I then hired a freelancer from the website freelancer.com after getting approval from my manager. And this proved to be a great decision. The freelancer worked in a different time zone towards. So as soon as we came into work each morning he had finished the task we had set him the day before. Now by being creative and by exploring our options I was able to get the project finished and delivered to the client on time. So that's a really good example answer where you have no choice but to work with limited resources. But you find a way around the problem. You come up with a really good innovative solution to the issue. Now the next thing to do is please make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. Head over to my website, passmaintoview.com and you can take a look at my full set of 21 Amazon behavioral interview questions and you also have the opportunity to download all of the answers. Including the ones I have covered today during this presentation. You can literally have them all in a handy PDF guide within your inbox within two minutes from now. So make sure you check that out. That resource will make a big difference to your preparation during your Amazon interview. Finally, don't forget to subscribe to the channel. As I said at the start lots of you are passing your interviews. We have about 700,000 people now within the career of its community. I love helping you guys but I can only do that if you are subscribed.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0126}
{"question": "Don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn.", "answer": "I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always good to connect with like minded professionals such as yourself and just give the video a quick thumbs up to say that you find this content useful because that always motivates me to create more for you. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon interview. Have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.027}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Thank you for giving me the opportunity to be interviewed for this software engineer position with your organization today. After graduating from university with a degree in computer science, I worked for several organizations in various positions where I gained experience working on team projects, individual software engineering tasks, end user testing and new software applications. I would describe myself as an industrious, diligent, reliable and forward thinking software engineer who possesses the skills and qualities to match the job description. I have a track record of achievement and can be trusted to use critical thinking skills to solve complex problems, to complete projects whilst adhering to strict organizational timeframes and I always take ownership of my ongoing professional development. If you hire me as a software engineer, I will collaborate closely with other departmental members and I will share my knowledge with the rest of my team to help the organization quickly achieve its strategic goals and maintain its position as an industry leader. So that's a brilliant example answer that you can use to answer that first software engineer interview question tell me about yourself. You are demonstrating good manners, you are using positive keywords and phrases and you are also telling them what you will do in the role if they hire you. So it's a really good answer. Now you can either pause the video if you want to and write down the questions and answers as we work through them together or if you wait, I will soon tell you where you can download instantly my full set of 25 software engineer interview questions and brilliant example answers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0073}
{"question": "But here's the next question I recommend you prepare for and that is, why did you decide to become a software engineer?", "answer": "Tip number one. Now this next interview question comes up often during software engineer job interviews and it is assessing your motivations for choosing this career. Now it takes as you know a unique person with special skills and qualities to be a software engineer and the role is not suited to everyone. Tip number two talk about how you are passionate for this type of work goes back many years and how you thrive in situations where you must solve complex problems to achieve a positive outcome. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0104}
{"question": "Why did you decide to become a software engineer?", "answer": "Here we go. I decided to become a software engineer because from a very early age I always had a passion and a genuine interest in all things computers, software applications and technical concepts. My favourite subjects at school involved computers and I have a particular interest in the latest technological advancements. I also decided to become a software engineer because I thrive in situations where I have to solve problems and use critical thinking skills to achieve a specific outcome. I believe work is far easier and more enjoyable if you are genuinely passionate about what you do and I hope my passion for software engineering is evident in my answers today during this interview and also in what I included on my resume. That's a really good answer, great answer to that common software engineer interview question. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you but when you're ready you can click that link in the top right hand corner of the video and straight through to my website, my interview.com and you can instantly download my full set of 25 software engineer interview questions and brilliant examples answers in a PDF guide including all of the responses I'm giving you today during this tutorial. But here's the next question for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a project you completed successfully tip number one.", "answer": "Now this question is assessing your ability to complete software engineering projects successfully as you know you need project management skills as a software engineer. So my advice is to give a specific situation where you have to overcome an unexpected problem to complete a project on time. Tip number two, this is a good tip. Make sure you use a star technique to structure your answer to this behavioral interview question. So this type of question where they say to you, tell me about a time or describe a situation is called a behavioral interview question. Now before I give you my example answer let me explain what the star technique is. So the star technique stands for situation task action and result. So you start off your answer and you outline the situation you were faced with. You then move on and talk briefly about the task that needed doing. This shows awareness of what you are supposed to do during the situation. You then give specific details about the action you took to complete the task before finishing off with your results.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.027}
{"question": "What was the result following your action?", "answer": "So you finish off your answer with the results following the action that you took. So it's a great technique to use when answering software engineer behavioral interview questions. Let me now give you my example answer to that question using the star technique so you can see how effective it is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0566}
{"question": "Tell me about a project you completed successfully.", "answer": "I was working on a challenging time sensitive software engineering project for my previous employer. There were six of us in the team and each one of us had different skills that we brought to the project. Unfortunately two weeks before the project deadline two team members went off sick including the project leader. There were no other software engineers available in the organization and I wasn't prepared to extend the deadline. Therefore it was my task to come up with a new plan of action to get things finished. So the remaining four of us got together to discuss our options. I suggested we should absorb whatever tasks we could amongst ourselves and then outsource the remaining technical tasks to a competent software engineer using the website upwork.com. Now this proved to be a smart move because after hiring the replacement software engineer online the project was still completed on time and to the expected standard. That's a brilliant example answer that uses the star technique to answer that behavioral interview question. Here's the next interview question I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0053}
{"question": "What are the most important skills and qualities needed to be a great software engineer?", "answer": "Now the question is assessing whether you have read the job description. If you haven't read the job description you can't answer this question confidently. Now my advice is to really make sure you read the job description carefully before your interview because it outlines the skills and qualities the employer is looking for. TIT number two I also recommend referencing technical interpersonal and soft skills in your answer. Here's my example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are the most important skills and qualities needed to be a great software engineer?", "answer": "Here we go. To be effective as a software engineer, various technical, interpersonal and soft skills are a must. You need excellent computer programming and coding skills, software testing and debugging competence, problem solving capabilities and critical and logical thinking skills. You need excellent team working and collaborating abilities, strong communication and listening skills and the ability to explain complex information in simple terms to non-technical individuals. As a software engineer you need to take responsibility for your ongoing professional development, possess emotional intelligence, be self-aware and open-minded and have outstanding time management capabilities. To excel as a software engineer you must be commercially aware, be self-motivated and disciplined and be able to work both independently and as part of a team. That is a brilliant example answer to that common question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are the most important skills and qualities needed to be a great software engineer?", "answer": "You can see how all of these answers are going to help you to be the standout candidate at your interview. Here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why should we hire you as a software engineer?", "answer": "This is another common software engineer interview question that requires a confident answer because your response could be the difference between a past or fail. I recommend referencing their organizational values in your answer. And how you will share your expertise and knowledge with other people in the team. Here's my example response to help you be the standout candidate.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why should we hire you as a software engineer?", "answer": "Here we go. You should hire me as a software engineer because I'm motivated by your organizational values. I am commercially aware which means everything I do will be geared towards helping you achieve your commercial objectives and I will share my knowledge and expertise willingly with other people in the team. You should also hire me because I am passionate about self development and ongoing learning. So this means you will be hiring a software engineer whose skills and competencies will always be relevant and up to date and whose knowledge will enhance and complement the team that I will be a part of. That is a brilliant example answer to that common question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0086}
{"question": "Why should we hire you?", "answer": "There's going to help you be the standout candidate. Here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How would you explain something technical to a non-technical person?", "answer": "This is a difficult one. Now this common software engineer interview question is assessing your communication skills. I strongly recommend preparing an answer to this question. In advance of your interview simply because you can't sit there and think for long about your answer you should know quickly how you would explain technical concepts to non-technical people in the role. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0141}
{"question": "How would you explain something technical to a non-technical person?", "answer": "Here we go. To begin with I would assess their knowledge by asking them questions to gauge where they were from a technical perspective. I would make sure I avoided technical jargon when describing anything technical. I would use visual drawings and diagrams to explain technical concepts and I would use familiar objects, scenarios and terminology to explain what it was. I was trying to describe. I would explain everything to them more than once and I would ask quiz-based questions to ensure they fully understood my explanations. Finally, I would leave ample time for the individual to ask me questions and I would make sure I answered them clearly and concisely. So if you give that answer quickly straight away after that question is asked, it shows that you have the communication skills and the style of communication, the adaptable style to tailor for everyone's needs, especially people who have limited technical knowledge. Here's an next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0062}
{"question": "What's your biggest weakness now?", "answer": "This question catches a lot of candidates out. Tip number one, again this question is going to come up at some stage during your software engineer interview. Now some people think it's right to say they don't have any weaknesses, but that answer will score zero points. Conversely, if you give a weakness there is a match for the job description and you can see why it's so important to read it, you will not get hired.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0125}
{"question": "Tip number two, instead give a weakness that is not a requirement of the software engineering role you have applied for, but which weakness do you give?", "answer": "Well, let me give you some example weakness is so good weaknesses you can use. Now we'll then give you my preferred answer. So here's some example weaknesses for software engineer interviews. Number one, you could say you find it hard letting go of projects. Number two, you could say you don't like giving people on a speedback simply because you are non-confrontational. Number three, you could say you don't like asking people for help or advice. You prefer to figure things out for yourself, which can take more time and that's the reason why it's a weakness or number four, you could say you are too self critical or too hard on yourself at times. So let me now give you my preferred example weakness to this tough interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0362}
{"question": "What's your biggest weakness here we go?", "answer": "My biggest weakness is the fact I'm not yet very good at public speaking or giving presentations to large groups of people. Although my weakness will not affect my ability to perform competently as a software engineer. If there are any opportunities in your organization to develop my public speaking skills then I would like to give it a try. That's a brilliant answer. You are giving a weakness that will not affect your ability to perform your duties as a software engineer competently, but you are saying you do want to improve. So if there are any opportunities you would like to give it a try and that shows confidence and a willingness to learn, improve and develop, which is important in the role. So the next thing to do is please make sure you click that link right now in the top right end corner of the video. Head straight through to my website pastmaintvu.com and you can instantly download my full set of 25 software engineer interview questions and brilliant answers in a PDF guide. So you get all of the answers I've given you today. Plus further questions and answers in total these 25 also. Make sure you do go through to that page because on there I have given you four questions I recommend you ask at the end of your interview. So at the end of your software engineer interview the hiring manager will say to you that's the end of the interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0236}
{"question": "Do you have any questions for us now?", "answer": "A lot of the time candidate say it's okay. I don't have any questions you covered everything during the interview. That's not the way to respond to that question. You should ask three or four smart questions that show that you can make a difference in the wrong.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Which questions should you ask?", "answer": "Well I've listed those questions on that page. Click the link in the top right time corner of the video.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn.", "answer": "So I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below to video. It's always great to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Also don't forget to hit the subscribe button. Literally we have about two and a half million subscribers. Thousands and thousands of you are passing your interviews. I can only help you if you are subscribed.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0317}
{"question": "Don't forget I can also help you to negotiate to salary on this channel and also progress throughout your career.", "answer": "So if you want to get promoted I do promotional job interviews and please just give the video a like a lot of time and effort. Goes into making these tutorials. All of the answers are unique. You can't find them anywhere else. I have created them specifically for you. Just by liking the video it tells me you find the tutorials useful and it obviously motivates me to create more content for you. Thank you so much. All that's left for me to say is that I wish you all the best for passing your software engineer interview and have a great day. Thank you very much.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0273}
{"question": "Module number one, what are behavioral interview questions? Don't forget, you need to know what they are and why they are being asked to give the perfect answer.", "answer": "Well, behavioral interview questions are designed to assess your ability to perform specific tasks and respond to situations in the workplace. Now the idea being that if you have previous experience of workplace situations and more importantly you handled them correctly, you will be a great fit for their team. But what if this is your first job and you don't have any previous experience, you're then sat in the interview and they said you, tell me about the time when you worked in a team and you would respond by saying, but I've never had to work in a team yet. If you say that in response to a behavioral interview question, you will fail, but please don't worry. Because if this is your first interview and you have no previous experience of the situations being asked, I will tell you what to say in module five of this training course. So behavioral interview questions start in any of the following three ways. So look out for these during your interview. The first way that the questions are asked is by the interviewer saying, tell me about a time when you and they would give the situation. They might also say, describe a situation when you had to and again give you the situation or they might say, give us an example of when you. So as soon as you hear the interviewer starts and interview question in any of those three ways, you can say to yourself, I am being asked a behavioral interview question and I need to answer it using the structure Richard is about to give me. So a quick recap on module number one of this training course. Behavioral interview questions assess how you have performed or acted in previous workplace situations. Now to partial interview, you have to give an answer that demonstrates competence in the area being assessed and behavioral interview questions start by describing a situation, tell me about a time or give us an example. So that is module number one complete.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0145}
{"question": "What are behavioral interview questions?", "answer": "Let's now move on to module number two. Now during this module, we are going to cover the top 10 most common behavioral interview questions. The idea being that if you understand what the top 10 most common behavioral interview questions are, you can prepare top scoring answers for them. So behavioral interview question number one the most common one is tell me about a time when you had to work in a team. The second question is tell me about a time when you had to solve a challenging problem. Behavioral interview question number three is give us an example of when you delivered excellent customer service. Question four, describe a situation when you had a conflict with a coworker. Now that is one of the behavioral interview questions where the majority of candidates fail to let interviews on because they say, well, if I did have conflict with a coworker, I will tell my manager about it. That is not the way to answer that difficult behavioral interview question. I will give you an example answer very soon. Behavioral interview question five, tell me about a time when you had to work under pressure. Number six is describe a situation when you disagreed with your boss. That is another behavioral question where people fail their interviews on. They say, I've never disagreed with my boss and I never would do either. That is not the way to answer it again. I will give you a top scoring answer very soon. Behavioral interview question seven is give us an example of a mistake you made. That is another tricky one. Number eight, explain a time when you took the initiative on a project. Number nine, describe a time when you went above and beyond what was required at work. Number ten is describe a time when you had to work with a difficult coworker. So you can see all of these questions are really difficult to answer. Those are the top ten most common asked behavioral interview questions during all types of job interviews. So that is module number two now complete. You are now aware of the top ten most common behavioral interview questions. Let's now move on to the all important module number three. And I will teach you how to answer behavioral interview questions using what is called the star technique. Now the star technique is recognized by all hiring managers and employers as the correct way to answer behavioral interview questions. You have to learn the star technique and use it during your answers. If you are going to pass your interview with the highest scores achievable.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0067}
{"question": "So what is the star technique?", "answer": "Well let's assume you are sat down in the interview chair and the interview says to you, tell me about a time when you worked in a team. As soon as you hear them say, tell me about a time or describe a situation or explain to me a previous scenario where you were. And then they give you the situation you should automatically think to yourself, start technique. I need to now use the star technique to answer this difficult behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "But what does the star technique mean?", "answer": "Well it means situation, task, action and result. And I recommend you learn those four words before you attend your interview. That's the star technique situation, task, action and result. So when you answer the interview questions, the behavioral interview questions you would. Start your answer and outline the situation you were faced with. You then move on and briefly explain the task that needed doing. This is a task that needs your attention. You then give in-depth details about the action you took. And I would suggest that the action part of your answer is the most detailed and in-depth. And then finally you finish off and talk about the results of your action. So that's the star technique situation, task, action and result. Let me now give you an example of the star technique in action when answering one of the most common behavioral interview questions.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0132}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you worked in a team here we go.", "answer": "In a previous job, my manager asked the team I was in to find ways to help the company save money. It was our task to brainstorm ideas and then present them to our manager. So we arranged a team meeting and agreed the structure. Everyone would have the opportunity to put forward their ideas. We would all listen and then shortlist the best ones. I suggested we should seek a new supplier for our office resources because they were too expensive. I also suggested we should turn off the heating system in the afternoon because people often complained. It was too hot. Other people in the team suggested we could use free software instead of the expensive ones. We were currently using. Now at the end of the meeting we had seven great ideas for saving money. I presented these to our manager and she implemented them all which resulted in significant savings for the business. That's a brilliant answer that uses a star technique. It's a great answer when you're working in a team because you're also coming up with ideas. You're saying, I implemented I put forward an idea which was to seek a new supply for our office resources. I also suggested we should turn off the heating system so you are contributing to the team. Other people are putting ideas forward and then more importantly, there is a positive outcome. At the end of the meeting we had seven great ideas. So make sure the result when you give your answers to all of the behavioral interview questions is a positive one. Make sure the result is positive following your actions. Okay, so that's module three of our training course now complete. You know how to answer behavioral interview questions using that all important star technique. Let's move on to module four. But before we do that, so I've still got two more modules to give you. But when you're ready if you want to download these slides plus my 100 brilliant answers to difficult interview questions, you can click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video at any point. Let's move on to module four. Now during module four, I'm going to give you some more sample answers to difficult behavioral interview questions. Let's have a look at those difficult ones. The first one is describe a situation when you disagreed with your boss.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0144}
{"question": "Do not say in response to this.", "answer": "I've never disagreed with my boss and I never would do either.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget, in module five, I'm going to tell you how to answer these questions if you have no previous experience of them.", "answer": "Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "describe a situation when you disagreed with your boss.", "answer": "A customer had made a complaint about how difficult it was to order from our company website. When I dealt with the complaint, they made several suggestions as to how we could improve. I presented these suggestions to my manager, but it wasn't interested in taking them forward. I felt this was a missed opportunity for us to increase sales, so it's my task to change his mind. I explained that I had noticed a drop in our online sales, despite there being record numbers of website visitors. I suggested we could potentially increase sales easily if we under-toker review of our website shopping cart. I asked for permission to hire a freelancer to look at this for us to which he agreed. After hiring a suitably qualified freelancer from the website upwork.com, they suggested four areas of improvement. After these were implemented, our website sales increased significantly. That's a great answer you are disagreeing with your boss. There's a benefit to the company involved in the answer too, which I really like because you're increasing sales because of your actions and there's a positive outcome at the end. You can see how these answers are going to be brilliant to help you pass your interview is the next one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0092}
{"question": "Describe a time when you had a conflict with a coworker.", "answer": "Wow, don't forget, do not answer this question by saying, if I did have conflict with a coworker, I would tell my boss about it for them to deal with. That is not the way to answer it. Here is, when I started working my previous job, I was attending a team meeting. Whenever I put forward ideas, another member of the team kept dismissing them. It was my task to calmly and professionally challenge my new coworker in private to express my concerns about his actions during the meeting. My goal was to build good working relationships with everyone in my team. I considered carefully what I wanted to say. I then spoke to my coworker in private and expressed my concerns before giving examples of when he had repeatedly dismissed my ideas. He immediately apologized and stated it was not his intention to be dismissive. From that moment on, we became friends and great co-workers. Now, by challenging him confidently, professionally and calmly, I was able to stop the conflict before it progressed and damaged the output of the team. That's another really good answer to a difficult, behavioral interview question and more importantly, there is a positive outcome.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget, make sure there is a positive outcome.", "answer": "Okay, that's module 4 now complete. We've had a look at some sample answers to behavioral interview questions. Let me now move on to module 5, which is, how to answer behavioral interview questions when you have no previous experience. Now you remember, previously I said, you might be in your interview. You've not been in these situations before they say to you, tell me about the time when you worked in a team. You say, I've never had to work in a team.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "You will fail your interview, but how should you answer it?", "answer": "Here's an example of what to do.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you worked in a team.", "answer": "Here we go. Although I haven't yet worked in a team, I do know what I would do in that situation. I would listen to the team brief and write down any instructions. I would then discuss the team's goal with my co-workers and generate a plan of action for us all to work towards. Next, I would suggest we allocate tasks to team members, based on each other's strengths, get to work and support each other throughout the process. Communication, motivation and a clear focus on the end goal are vital in any team situation. So the trick is, if you have no previous work experience of the behavioral situation being assessed, tell them what you would do in that type of situation and you'll be far more likely to partial interview. Okay, so that's module 5. Now complete. You know how to answer behavioral interview questions we've no experience.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.019}
{"question": "What should you do next?", "answer": "Well, if you want to download a copy of these exact slides that contains the answers I've given you plus another 100 brilliant responses to difficult interview questions, click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintevue.com and you can download these slides and 100 brilliant answers to difficult interview questions in a PDF guide so you can have it in your inbox literally within two minutes from now. In that guide, I have given you answers to many other behavioral interview questions including all of the top 10 that I mentioned earlier on during this training course. Also, please make sure you hit the subscribe button as you can imagine, literally 1000 of you and I mean 1000 of you are passing your interviews as a result of the training videos I'm providing you with if you are subscribed, I can help you not just pass every job interview, I can also help you negotiate to salary and progress throughout your career. Please make sure you subscribe, give the video like, it's a small ask, it motivates me to create more content for you. Thank you very much and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below this video. It's always a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching and wish you all the best. For passing your job interview, have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0154}
{"question": "Want to know the step-by-step process on how to rock behavioral interview questions?", "answer": "Well, fantastic. Because that's what this whole video is about. To keep getting interview and career tips from the person who has seen it all from the recruiting side, subscribe to this channel and hit the bell to get a new video every Thursday. I'll be teaching you my story toolbox strategy that gets exceptional results. I get the most testimonials of fabulous results from this tip, including this fellow who got the job from this advice and being a loyal watcher of my videos. Heck yes, thank you so much. So I'll give you the steps. You'll need to answer behavioral interview questions and I'll give you an example of this in action and stay to the end because I will tell you my trick for remembering all of this information. A behavioral interview is a question that starts with something like, tell me about a time when. They are asking for examples of things you have done in your past. And at the core, they are asking you to tell them a story. Stories aren't just for bedtime folks. You need to tell stories to be memorable and help them to see themselves working with you. This is my favorite type of question to ask when I'm the interviewer because I can better understand the way you think in a probe situation.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.013}
{"question": "When I ask something like, how do you handle stress?", "answer": "I get a very generic answer. But if I ask, tell me about a time you had to complete several projects within a tight deadline. I can hear a story and better understand the way that you respond to the world.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What you need to do first is get notable career moments all written down, which is what I call a story toolbox.", "answer": "This will be the basis of all of your answers to behavioral interview questions. And when they ask you a question, that's behavioral. It will keep you from doing the all. Um, um, um.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0857}
{"question": "What was the question?", "answer": "So take the time to write this all down in a document. Such as a time you saved the day or solved a big problem. A time when you worked with a difficult person and how you handled it. A time you messed up or failed. Put this all down in your story toolbox. Now I have a lot more prompts for you and it's kind of boring for me to list them all out verbally here. So I will put a link in the description with a full document of prompts. But by the end of this worksheet, you'll have about 10 or even more stories locked and loaded. So you need to get that story toolbox filled out before moving onto the next steps. And I want to emphasize, you're creating that story toolbox just 10x. Your potential to rock the interview. Only a video that walks through how to use this story toolbox for essentially every interview question. Yeah, it's super impactful. So you can get that full edge of the location on this. I will link in the description. Okay, now we need to answer the question. They may ask something like, tell me about a time you had to deliver a piece of tough feedback. If we were to look in the toolbox, I provided you. You might start sweating and say, oh god, Madeline, you didn't tell me to write a story about giving feedback what a curve ball. Nope, thank for a minute. Feedback absolutely played a role in one of your stories. Think for a minute and pick one. For example, I said that you should have a story or two about a time when you worked with a difficult person and how you handled it. I bet there's a great chance you had to deliver some sort of feedback in that story. So tell it. You will be so pleasantly surprised at how many behavioral questions your preconceived stories will fit. Then you answer this in the par method, which is also similar to the star method, but I'd prefer par because it's three steps instead of four concise it's key in the interview. So, P stands for problem.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0212}
{"question": "What is the problem or challenge that was put before you?", "answer": "A is for action.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What action did you take to attempt to resolve it?", "answer": "And R is the result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What were the outcomes of those actions?", "answer": "Let's say we wrote down a story about how we worked with a coworker who was flaky and didn't do things when they said they were going to. Here's an example, problem. I had a coworker who I was depending on for reports, but he would constantly tell me that he wouldn't be able to get it to me in time right when the deadline was about to hit, which impacted my ability to do my job in time. Action. I respected him, so I took the concern straight to him to talk it through. I first showed empathy and said, I can imagine you have so much that you're working on right now, and I can tell that you're working hard. Then I was direct about how he was affecting me. So, I said, and I wanted to discuss the past three deadlines that we said that you weren't able to meet. When you don't get me the reports on time, it delays the entire production process and leads the rest of us to take several hours to readjust the schedule.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0158}
{"question": "How can we ensure this doesn't happen in the future?", "answer": "And then finally, you explain the result. I was nervous about the conversation, but he opened up to me about how he has always trying to chase down the information for the report. And so we came up with a streamlined solution where we now submit a form with every report request, and he now he stopped putting off the task. And from then on, we have been getting the report on time. And that's it. The same exact story works for those two prompts, but it could also fit a lot of different other questions, like tell me about a time that you had an interpersonal conflict you had to deal with, or tell me about a time when there was a communication breakdown.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0159}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you took charge when your boss was unavailable.", "answer": "Once you have your story toolbox, you can fit these answers every which way. And what I do before every interview is if it's a phone or video interview, I have the title of every story to trickle my memory on the computer screen or paper on the table. If it's an in-person interview, I always read all the stories right before I go into the interview to stay fresh. And I bring a notebook in and I bring notes that I sent in front of me. Now I'm smooth about it. I'm not like sitting there reading the answers while talking. But no one does this. And I have notes out and I'm taking notes while I'm in the interview. And it actually comes off as me being prepared and just giving way more of a hoot than everyone else. If you want every single job search email template, you'll need in your job search. I've had it for you. I have an ebook called Fill in the blank job hunt essential email templates for the job search. And it tells you what to say to recruiter or hiring manager right after you submit an application online.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0097}
{"question": "How to follow up with a company. How to negotiate your salary over email.", "answer": "It has everything. So I will link that book in the description for you to check out. Make sure you like this video and subscribe to this channel. Thanks so much everyone. Wifi High Fives!", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0857}
{"question": "Behavioral interview question number two, describe a time when you disagreed with a team member, how did you resolve the situation?", "answer": "Here's my example answer. A coworker and I were tasked with updating the company's website. We both disagreed on the best way to update it. I suggested we keep the website professional looking simple and easy to navigate, whereas my coworker wanted to make it more colorful with lots of pages and blog focused. My task was to find an amicable way forward that was in the company's best interest on one that enabled us to collaborate on the project without conflict. After listening to my coworker's ideas and putting forward my own, I suggested we create two versions of the website and run a test to see which one had the most visitors, engagement and sales conversions. By using this approach, we could test both ideas and the company would get the best results possible. My coworker agreed this was a great idea. After creating two versions of the website and running comprehensive testing, my idea yielded the most substantial returns for the company. Behavioral interview question number three, describe a situation when you delivered excellent customer service. Here's my example answer that uses a start technique. A customer came into the store one morning to pay for a product they had seen listed on our website. When I went to retrieve the product from our store, it had sold out. Understandably, the customer was Irate. It was my responsibility to resolve the situation and put things right for the customer. I immediately apologized. I would feel the same if the situation had happened to me and then investigated or online inventory system to see what had gone wrong. The system had incorrectly allocated the product to our shop. In fact, it was located at our main distribution center. I contacted the distribution manager and requested he dispatch the product immediately to the customer's home address on a 24-hour urgent delivery notice. I then asked my store manager for permission to give the customer a 50% refund due to the inconvenience caused to which he agreed. After apologizing to the customer again and informing her of my actions, she thanked me for my prompt action and excellent customer service skills. Finally, I contacted our IT department and asked them to ensure the same system error never happened again. Behavioral interview question number four.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you worked under pressure.", "answer": "Here's my example answer. In my last role, my manager asked me to take up the duties of a coworker who had to take a leave of absence due to personal reasons. I was already working on a time-sensitive task of my own, but I agreed to do the additional work requested. It was my task to reprioritize my workload to include the additional tasks and get everything finished on time. I created a new list of all my responsibilities and used a colour coded system to determine which tasks should be completed first. Hip-tasked were urgent and the tasks came second and green tasks last. I then blocked out my diary, rescheduled several appointments and set to work. By being highly organised, methodical when prioritizing tasks and utilizing my time carefully, I was able to get all my duties completed to an exceptional standard. Behavioral interview question number five.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you disagreed with a supervisor.", "answer": "This is a really difficult question to answer correctly. Here's my example response that uses a start technique. My supervisor wanted to launch a new company product by advertising in local stores and supermarkets. I didn't feel this was the best way to get the greatest return from the launch. I felt it was important to disagree with my supervisor and explain in a professional manner the reasons why. I spoke to my supervisor in private and said that my research showed we could potentially get a greater return from our product launch by allocating all of the budget to online adverts including Facebook and Instagram. By using this method we could target a specific audience based on age, gender and interests. I supervise it was intrigued by my suggestion and she agreed to trial 50% of the budget to online advertising for one week. Now after the one week trial was over, the online advertising had yielded a far greater return and my supervisor decided to allocate 100% of the budget to this new method. Behavioral interview question number six.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "Here's my example answer. When I started working my first job, my supervisor asked for a volunteer to go and work the following week in a different department because one of their key workers was off sick. I volunteered. I saw this as an opportunity for me to learn more about the company and diversify my skills. Unfortunately, I failed to write down the change of department in my diary and when the following week arrived, the head of department complained to my manager that I had not turned up. I felt awful and embarrassed because I had let my manager and the other department down. I immediately apologized and rushed over to the new department to commence my work. I learned a lot from that mistake. I now make sure I place all appointments and responsibilities in my paper diary, are my smart phone too, so they are never missed. Now the next thing to do is you want to accelerate your learning even further. Please click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, passmaintoview.com and you can instantly download those six answers I just gave you. Plus, an additional 27 tell me about a time, behavioral interview questions and top scoring example answers. This guide will help you be the competition at your forthcoming interview. Make sure you check it out. Also, please make sure you hit that subscribe button. Literally thousands of you are passing your interviews at the very first attempt. I can only help you if you are subscribed please give the video a like because that really does motivate me to create more content for you and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your job interview have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0116}
{"question": "What do I mean by that?", "answer": "Well, the interviewer wants to hear about a specific situation you have been in that demonstrates your competence in the scenario being assessed. The next important element of this tip is in your response, make sure you give details about what you actually did. Now, some people complain that they've never been in the situation before and they therefore cannot answer the question. So if you haven't been in the situation before, my advice is to describe a scenario where you witness someone else doing it, because this shows observational skills.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0215}
{"question": "What do I mean by that?", "answer": "Well, let me give you an example answer to a common behavioral interview question. So the question is, tell me about the time you provided excellent customer service. Let's assume you've never been in that situation before. Here's what to say. Although I haven't yet been in that situation, I do know how to provide excellent customer service because I have witnessed others give it. For example, I recently stayed at a hotel with my partner and the service was outstanding. We were immediately welcomed by the hotel reception team or bags were taken to our room. We were given complimentary drinks and refreshments and they contacted us 30 minutes after our arrival to check everything was to our satisfaction. Now, whenever we contacted reception, they answered the phone promptly, politely and professionally, and nothing was too much trouble. I understand how important great customer services to your business and I'm confident I can provide it to your customers in this role and make them feel special. So they use the business again in the future. That is the way to answer behavioral interview questions if you've never been in the scenario before. So let's now move on to tip number two before I give you those 21 brilliant quick answers to difficult behavioral interview questions. Tip number two is, make sure you use the start technique to structure your answers to the behavioral interview questions. Let me quickly tell you what the start technique is. So start stands for situation, task action and result and it's an easy thing to remember when you are answering any type of behavioral interview questions. So you start off your answer and you tell the interviewer the situation you were faced with, you then move on and briefly outline the task that needed doing the task that needed your attention. You then give in-depth details about the action you took to achieve the task and this is where you tell the interviewer what you did and then you finish off and you tell the interviewer the results following your actions. An another important tip is to make sure the result is always a positive one following your action. And you will notice in a second when I give it these 21 quick answers to behavioral interview questions that all of the responses finish on a positive note that is really important. Okay, let's now start working through these quick answers, these easy to remember answers to the 21 most common behavioral interview questions. And the first one is tell me about the time you provided excellent customer service. Here's my example answer that uses a star technique. A customer called our business to inquire about a product we had available. They arranged to come to the company the following day to view the product. My task was to provide them with excellent service when they arrived. As soon as I got off the phone I learned as much about the product as possible so I could answer any questions they had. When the customer arrived the following day I made them feel welcome asked questions to establish their needs and explained everything on you about the product and its benefits. I then answered any questions they had in detail. Now the customer thanked me for my patience and the information I provided before buying the product. So that's a really good easy to remember answer that shows a situation where you provided excellent customer service. Let me now give you the answer, the quick answer, to behavioral interview question number two.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0115}
{"question": "Tell me about the time you worked in a team.", "answer": "This is a common question that comes up all the time during all types of job interviews. Here's my example answer. My manager asked the team I was a part of to come up with ideas to help promote a new company product. It was our task to work closely as part of a team to create a list of solid ideas to ensure the product launch was successful. We decided to hold a team meeting and each took turns to put forward ideas while the rest of the team listened and took notes. I suggested we market the product online and others in the group suggested promoting it to our customer database offering a discount. At the end of the meeting we had five great ideas which we presented to our manager. He agreed to implement all the ideas resulting in record sales for the new product launch. That's another really good answer. A quick answer to one of the most common behavioral interview questions. Now don't go anywhere because I still have 19 more behavioral interview questions and answers to give you. But when you're ready you can click that link in the top right hand corner of the video and you can head through to my website pastmaintovue.com and you can instantly download these slides in my full set of 21 quick top scoring answers to the most common behavioral interview questions as a PDF guide. Here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a challenge you had to overcome.", "answer": "Here's my example answer that uses a start technique. Here we go. I worked on a critical time sensitive team project in my previous role. A technical team member went off six, three days before the project deadline. It was my task to find a way to still get the project finished despite being one team member down. I assessed the outstanding workload and allocated some tasks to the remaining team members based on their strengths. Now for the technical related functions I found an online contract to qualify to do the work remotely. By thinking outside the box and acting quickly I overcame this challenge and completed the project on time and to the required standard. You can see how these answers are going to impress any hardening manager. They're really good answers. Here's question four.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you failed.", "answer": "This is a difficult one because the majority of candidates respond by saying, I've never failed. That is not the way to answer this question. This is about how you react to failure.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Are you positive? Do you take it upon yourself to improve?", "answer": "Here's my example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you failed.", "answer": "When I started my first job I undertook an internal training course, including an exam. Now my task was to partake in the course and achieve a pass mark of 75%. Now unfortunately because I thought I knew the subject very well, I did not study hard enough for the exam and I ended up just failing. I was very disappointed in myself and after apologizing to my supervisor, I studied hard and gained a 97% pass on the retake. I learned a tremendous amount from that experience and I now prepare thoroughly for every situation, task or project I am responsible for. You can see that that ends on a really positive note. You take responsibility for your failure and you improve. That's the most important thing I'm answering that common behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you failed.", "answer": "Question number five out of all 21. Quick answers to behavioral interview questions is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you went above and beyond what was expected here's my example response.", "answer": "In my current job by manager Arstra of Volunteer to cover the work of a colleague who was going to be off sick for three weeks. I volunteered to be that person. It was my task to complete my own and my colleagues worked to the expected standard. I quickly learned my colleagues' duties and responsibilities and prioritise my workload based on the company's needs. By being methodically my task completion, I could go above and beyond what was expected for my manager to help the company while my colleague was off work. That's a really good answer another great answer that will help you be to stand out Canada at your interview is question six.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you took a calculated risk at work.", "answer": "Well, this is a difficult one. Again, most people say I never take risks. The important thing when answering this common behavioral interview question is to show that you do take risks at times but they are calculated and you assess the pros and cons. Here's my example answer. My manager was off on holiday when I encountered a difficult problem at work. I needed to order a new computer for the office because the old one was broken.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, strict company rules stated managerial permission was required for purchase over $100.", "answer": "I had to decide whether to take the risk and order the computer without the necessary permission. I wrote down a list of the pros and cons of ordering the computer and decided it was the right thing to do. We needed the computer to meet customer demand and to maintain operational efficiency. I took the risk and ordered the computer and when my manager returned to work she agreed I'd made the right decision. That's a great answer because it shows that you are assessing your options, you are writing down a list of the pros and cons and you are acting in the best interest of your employer. Question seven, tell me about the time when you made an unpopular decision. Here's my example answer. I attended a team meeting discussing the project for an important customer. Two team members wanted to cut corners on the project to save money. I disagreed with their suggestion and even though my decision was going to be unpopular I needed to speak out. I explained calmly that cutting corners was unethical and it went against company values. Now if the client found out we had cut corners they would be extremely dissatisfied. Although the team members who wanted to cut corners disagreed with me the rest of the team backed my decision. That's a really good answer because it shows you are not afraid to say something that is unpopular when it's in the best interest of the company. Question number eight, out of our 21 questions and answers don't forget if you are enjoying this tutorial please do hit the like button as you can imagine many many days of preparation goes into making these videos and coming up with a unique answer. All I ask is that you hit the subscribe button and give the video like. Thank you. Question eight, tell me about a situation when you received negative feedback and how you handled it here we go. During a performance review in my previous role my manager criticized me for how long I talked to customers on the telephone. Although I was trying to build positive relationships with our customers it was my task to listen to my manager's feedback and then take steps to improve. Now once we had finished the performance review I enrolled in an online customer service training course to learn additional communication skills to speed up my dealing with customers. Now once the course was finished and I put what I had learned to practice my customer call handling rates improved significantly. That shows that you are a mature and professional employee who responds well to feedback. You don't soak, you're not immature, you take it on board, you listen and then you take the step yourself to improve and there is again that positive outcome. Which is really important when answering behavioral interview questions, question nine.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.004}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you had a conflict with a coworker.", "answer": "Here we go. My colleague and I were working on a project but disagreed on the best approach. I felt it was my task to find a way around the conflict for the sake of the project. I suggested we should compromise by taking the positive aspects of each of our suggested methods of working and combining them together. I also suggested we review our progress more regularly to ensure we were still meeting project expectations and time scales. My colleague agreed. This was a great way forward that suited both of us and as soon as we set to work the conflict disappeared immediately. I'm sure you will agree that that puts you across as the professional work colleague who puts the needs of the project first. You come up with a brilliant idea to get around the conflict again a successful resolution question 10.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you disagreed with your boss.", "answer": "Now most people say I've never disagreed with my boss and I would never do that's not the way to answer this question. Here's my example response. Here we go. A customer contacted me requesting a refund because they were dissatisfied with their purchase. Now because the customer was one day outside of the permitted refund period, my manager declined their request. I felt this was the wrong decision and so I tried to persuade my manager to allow the refund to go ahead. I explained that the customer was a long standing visitor of the business and we should relax the rules on this occasion because we didn't want to lose their custom in the future. Now after listening to my reasons he decided it was the right thing to do when I was then able to issue the refund to the customer's satisfaction. And I'm sure you will agree that that is a great way to disagree with your boss because it's in the benefits of the customer and the business to do so. Question 11 of our quick answers to the most common 21 behavioral interview questions.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0102}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you improved a process.", "answer": "Here we go. I had concerns in my previous role that our customers had no facility to make suggestions to as for improvement. Being passionate about customer service, I felt it was my responsibility to develop a new way for customers to provide feedback after researching different options. I found a website plugin that we could install on our website that allowed customers to fill in a feedback form once they had made a purchase. Customers had the opportunity to rate their shopping experience and provide written feedback on what they felt we could do to improve. Now after my manager agreed to install the plugin, we started receiving valuable feedback that enabled us to increase customer service standards. This in turn helped to increase sales and customer retention. As another cracking answer, don't forget if you want to download all of these responses. The slides and the PDF guide click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Question 12.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you had to adapt to change.", "answer": "Here's my example answer. In my last job, a new manager took over the running of our department. She was enthusiastic and wanted to make numerous changes to our working practices. Now some team members fought against the changes. But I saw it as my responsibility to embrace them and support the new manager. I listened to the new managers brief and what she wanted us to do. I then learned all the new methods of working and encouraged others in the team to do the same. After four weeks of implementing the new changes, things started to improve and the team was far more productive and efficient than before. Question 13.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you challenged someone's behaviour.", "answer": "Wow, this is a difficult one. Here's my example answer. I overheard a member of another department making inappropriate comments about a coworker during a break in the campaign. My task was to challenge the person calmly and explain why their comments were unacceptable. I asked them not to use that type of language and that they should show more respect to their coworkers. I also explained that their comments went against company policy and values. And if they use that language again, I would report them to the manager. Now my actions had a positive effect because they apologized and assured me they would never do it again as another top scoring answer. Behavioral interview question number 14.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you helped to co-worker, learn a new skill or develop an existing one.", "answer": "Here's my example response. A co-worker wanted to apply for a promotion but they needed to learn about my job to increase their chances of success. I was happy to help them. And saw it as my duty to teach them what they needed to know. I first assessed their level of knowledge and then put a plan of action in place to teach them. They spent an hour a day with me for a week where I taught them my role and how to carry out each duty to a competent standard. At the end of the week they thanked me for helping them and when they applied for a promotion they were successful. That shows that you are a team player who can coach other people and you are selfless in your duties and have a great answer. Question 15 out of our 21 behavioral interview questions and quick answers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had to deal with a difficult customer here we go.", "answer": "A customer came into the store requesting a refund but they didn't have a receipt when I informed them that I could not issue the refund they started shouting at me. It was my task to listen to the customer and take action to diffuse a situation. I let the customer vent their frustrations and while they were talking I listened. I then explained that company policy prevented me from issuing a refund without a receipt.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, I stated that if they reviewed their bank statement when they got home it would probably prove that they purchased the goods from our store which would be a suitable replacement for a receipt.", "answer": "The customer thanked me for this alternative solution and when they returned the next day with their bank statement I was able to issue a refund. That's a really good answer because it shows you are providing excellent customer service. You are sticking to the company rules but you are also providing them with an alternative solution. That's why they're answering so good question 16.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0147}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you missed a deadline.", "answer": "Again, most people say I've never missed a deadline but we all missed deadlines. Here's the way to answer it. In my last job my manager gave me a task to work on that included gathering data and information from the previous five years company sales. He stated the task needed to be completed within four to eight hours and despite knowing that deadline would be tight I was eager to meet it. I started gathering the information and data but soon realized the magnitude of the task. Not being deterred. I took some work home with me that evening and spent three hours trying as hard as possible to make good progress. Now despite working additional hours I just missed the deadline. If I had the same task again I would do things slightly differently and delegate tasks to ensure that deadline was met.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, I have no regrets because I gave it my all and I learned a lot about gathering company data and information.", "answer": "Again, a positive end to that situation you are being positive. You are admitting to missing the deadline you were saying I could have done things differently but I gave it my all and that's the most important thing. Question 17.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time you've demonstrated leadership skills.", "answer": "Now this question comes out all the time during all types of job interviews not necessarily leadership roles. You can still demonstrate leadership skills even if you do not hold a leadership position here's how.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you demonstrated leadership skills.", "answer": "In my last job I received a call from a local hotel informing me that the company scheduled meeting the following day could not be held due to a flood that had taken place overnight at the hotel. 20 people were due to attend the meeting. I decided to show leadership skills and source a new venue for the meeting. I called around suitable alternative venues in the local area and chose one that was cost effective close to transport links and could provide refreshments during the meeting. Once the venue had been confirmed I informed my manager about the situation and the action I had taken. He thanked me for showing leadership initiative before permitting me to contact all meeting attendees with the updated venue change. That's a great answer because the majority of employees wouldn't do that. They would just go and tell their manager that the hotel had called an ameater than cancelled but you're taking the initiative you're showing leadership skills and sorting out the problem before informing your manager. That's an example of a brilliant top performing employee. Question 18.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a mistake here's my example answer.", "answer": "When I first started studying for my exams I spent many hours reading from textbooks. This proved a mistake because my mock exam results were not what I expected to achieve. It was my task to learn from this mistake to improve for my real exams. Immediately following my mock results I analyzed the best way for me to learn and it ended up being through visual infographics and being tested with flashcards. By being positive about my mistake and not dwelling on it I changed how I studied and my exam results improved significantly. That answer speaks for itself. It's a positive way of dealing with a mistake you made a simple mistake. Question 19. Two more to go after this.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you used your initiative to solve a problem here we go.", "answer": "A supplier contacted our company to explain that a product they had been supplying as with was no longer available. This was a problem because we'd sold several of these products to customers overnight. My task was to use my initiative to find an alternative supplier to supply the product moving forward. I researched alternative suppliers and drew a assured list of three suitable companies and then contacted all three companies to obtain quotes and to ascertain delivery times. After speaking to all three companies I chose the one that could provide the best value for money and speed of delivery for our customers. That shows you. You know, resolved to a difficult challenge by showing initiative again you are taking the lead. Question 20.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0079}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you saved a company money.", "answer": "This type of question behavioral interview questions coming up more and more during job interviews because companies want to save money. Here we go. One Friday afternoon I completed my work for the day so I decided to see if I could help the company save money. I was concerned for some time about how much we were paying for office resources so I decided to source a new supplier. I assessed how much we spent each month on resources and contacted several new office suppliers to obtain quotes. Now one of them quoted a saving of more than $300 each month, equating to $3600 per year. I then presented my findings to my manager and he thanked me for my work and then switched to the new supplier. That's another great example.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0149}
{"question": "Where you took initiative you'd finish your work one Friday afternoon.", "answer": "Instead of saying I've got no more work you take it upon yourself to look for ways to help save your company money. So I'm about to give you the 21st question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0294}
{"question": "Don't forget if you want to download the answers click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video.", "answer": "Question 21.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you gave feedback to someone here we go.", "answer": "This is a difficult question. While working in a previous role I noticed a work colleague was making numerous mistakes with their work as their coworker. I felt it was my responsibility for saying something. I needed to use tact and diplomacy to encourage them to improve. I spoke to my work colleague in private and asked them if they were okay to which they said they were. I'd mention their mistakes and asked them why they felt they were making so many. Initially they were defensive but I persevered diplomatically. I encouraged them to change and offered to help them if they were struggling with their work. Now having the confidence to give feedback to my colleague made a massive difference to their work. They never made the same mistakes again and I'm glad that I intervened. That's a great answer because it shows that you are prepared to talk to your colleague given feedback which then resulted in them taking it upon themselves to improve. It's a great result, a great outcome. So the next thing to do is click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video right now. Had straight through to my website post main to view.com and you can instantly download my full set of 21 quick answers to the most common behavioral interview questions. You get all of those answers that I've just given you. It's a great resource to help you pass your job interview at the first attempt.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0078}
{"question": "Don't forget to hit the subscribe button.", "answer": "It's so important. I want you to subscribe because I can help you not just pass every job interview but progress throughout your career. Get promoted, get a pay rise, negotiate to salary, you name it. I am here to help you throughout your career and with thousands of you. Passing your job interviews and getting the jobs of your dreams. It makes sense for you to subscribe. Please give the video like it's a small ask but it really does motivate me to create more content for you and exam palancers. Oh and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below to video. It's always an honor and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching. I wish you all the best for passing your interview have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.026}
{"question": "Don't forget very soon, I'm going to give you a brilliant example personal statement for engineers.", "answer": "It's a brilliant one. I can't wait to give it to you. So your name and contact details at the top of page one and then your personal statement. And then we move on to the second page of your engineering CV or resume. Section two is your education history and qualifications. Here you will detail the schools, colleges or universities you attended, the subjects you studied and the qualifications and grades you attained. So just list them in chronological order and put them in list, strong bullet point format because it's then easy for them to read. And then section three is your relevant experience and work history. So this is details of the places you have worked as an engineer or otherwise. The main duties you had at each company and the key achievements at each place. So we put down the key achievements because we want to demonstrate to the hiring manager that we have a track record of success. So that's the second page of our engineering CV or resume. Then we move on to page three. This is section four which is training courses you have completed and then he continuous professional development activities you have undertaken. So in section four, list of training courses you have completed accreditation achieved as an engineer and also details of any CPD activities. CPD is continuous professional development and then section five is hobbies and interests. So just give a brief outline of your interest and activities outside of work. If you can give anything that shows that you focus on self development, that's a good thing. Playing team sports, keeping yourself fit and active, those are good things to include also. So be very careful with the hobbies and the interest you include on your engineering CV and resume and then finally page three. And finally page four, we're going to put down two references. Now references are the names and contact details of two people who will vouch for your competence as an engineer and your suitability for the position. Some people on their CV or resume put down references available upon request. That's weak. It's lazy. Get two people ask them for permission to put them down as references and then include their names and contact details.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0205}
{"question": "Because the hiring manager might ring them up and say, what do you think of this person as an engineer for my company?", "answer": "And if the references say, yep, they're really good. They're efficient, they're competent and they are effective as an engineer. Then they're more likely to invite you along to and interview. And then finally, again, include your contact details. We include them on the first page of the CV or resume and then we include them at the bottom again. So we're making it super easy for the hiring manager to contact you. So at the bottom again, include your direct contact number and your email address. Okay, so that's how to structure your engineering CV and resume. Very soon, I'm going to actually show you. I'm going to walk through a template with you. An engineering CV and resume template. I will then tell you where you can download it. But first of all, let me give you those 13 powerful words you can use on your engineering CV or resume. Now, these are also great words to use at your interview. So once you get invited along to your engineering interview, you can use these 13 words during the interview too. So take note of them. Now, I have left the 13th word until last, the best one. That's the one in the middle. It's the most important. But these are all fantastic ones too. Here we go. You can say that you're commercially driven. This means that you understand how your work as an engineer impacts the organisation. You can say I am a commercially driven engineer. I understand how my work has to positively impact the organisation's mission and vision. The second word is innovation. You can say that you are an innovative engineer. So this means as an engineer, you have the ability to make things easier, more efficient or faster. You can use the word critical thinking. This means you analyze data and information to make the right engineering decisions. You can also use the word decisive. This means that you make effective decisions as an engineer that are in the best interests of safety and the organisation as a whole. You can say that you have the right technical knowledge. You possess the knowledge needed to be effective as an engineer. And you take control of your ongoing professional development so that your qualifications, your knowledge and your expertise are at the cutting edge of the industry. You can also use the word communicator. Now engineers need to be good communicators. You can say you are able to communicate your engineering ideas and concepts in easy to understand language. The other word you can use is cost conscious. This is a really good one. When creating an engineering CV or resume, you can say your engineering work is focused on delivering value for money. Industrialists are great word for engineering CVs and resumes. This means you work hard or diligent and focused. You can say your results driven. This means your work as an engineer is focused on achieving results for the company team or department. Attention to detail is another really important word to use on an engineering CV or resume. So you can say your work as an engineer is accurate, concise and error free. Resilient is another really strong word to use on your engineering CV or resume. This means that you are able to overcome challenges on a daily basis to achieve your engineering goals. Or 12 word is interpersonal skills. Interpersonal skills are needed as engineers. This means that you can collaborate with anyone and easily fit into an engineering team. And the top word that you should always use both on your engineering CV and resume and also at your interview is safety focused. So everything you do as an engineer has safety as the primary focus. Okay, so there's 13 words you can use on your engineering CV or resume and also at your forthcoming interview. So let me now give you a 200 word engineering CV and resume personal statement.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0177}
{"question": "Don't forget the personal statement goes on section one right at the very start of your CV or resume.", "answer": "The first thing that the hiring manager is going to read. And approximately 200 word brief introduction summarizes your skills. Experience and suitability for the engineering position you have applied for. Here it is. I am a knowledgeable, competent, decisive and innovative engineer who understands the importance of safety, leadership and collaborative working in this position. I possess the relevant skills, knowledge, qualifications and experience to help drive the company forward and achieve its engineering goals. In recent years, I developed a diverse set of skills and qualities that will enable me to have an immediate and positive impact in this engineering position. And assist the management team in achieving their commercial and operational objectives. In addition to being a higher cheever and strong collaborator who can fit seamlessly into any team, I am renowned for my analytical, critical and problem solving capabilities. Notable achievements in my engineering career to date include, successfully completing time-sensitive engineering projects with strict budgetary requirements, assisting organizations in the development of engineering operational procedures and safety protocols, collaborating with internal departments to assess company engineering needs and improving efficiency and effectiveness of engineering related machinery and resources. Further details of my engineering experience, work history, education, qualifications and references are provided within this CV stroke resume for your kind consideration. That is a powerful impactful personal statement for engineers to go right at the very start of your CV and resume.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget, soon I will tell you where you can download this and my seven ready-made templates.", "answer": "But first of all, let me teach you how to structure your engineering CV or resume in a word document. Here we go. Okay, so let's now work through my ready-made engineering CV and resume template in a word document. So right at the very top of your CV or resume include your name, your contact number and your email address. And to make it really easy for the hiring manager to contact us. And then sexual one is the personal statement. You can see that I have put the personal statement right across the first page is the first thing they are going to read. And it is impactful. It uses lots of those 13 powerful words. I just gave you in the tutorial and I've also put it in a box to make it easier for them to read. Let me quickly read that personal statement again for you. I am a knowledgeable, competent, decisive and innovative engineer who understands the importance of safety, leadership and collaborative working in this position. I possess the relevant skills, knowledge, qualifications and experience to help drive the company forward and achieve its engineering goals. For recent years, I have developed a diverse set of skills and qualities that will enable me to have an immediate and positive impact in this engineering position. And assist the management team and achieving their commercial and operational objectives. In addition to being a higher cheever and strong collaborator who can fit seamlessly into any team, I am renowned for my analytical, critical and problem solving capabilities. I have a great experience in my engineering career to date include successfully completing time, sensitive engineering projects with strict budgetary requirements, assisting organisations in the development of engineering operational procedures and safety protocols, collaborating with internal departments to assess company engineering needs and improving efficiency and effectiveness of engineering related machinery and resources. For the details of my engineering experience, work history, education, qualifications and references are provided within this CV, stroke, resume for your kind consideration. So you can see there that I again in the box I have put the notable achievements you can put these in bullet point format because they can scan through them read them to see how you are going to add value to their organisation as an engineer. Now, we come on to the second page and here you will put your education history, name of the school, college or university you attended under dates, the subjects that you studied under qualifications and grades attained. Work experience, name of the company that you worked at, the date to and from put them in chronological order with the most recent first, a brief outline of your main responsibilities and duties as an engineer in each position and the key achievements you have gained are you gained while working for the company. And another box, the training courses completed and CPD activities continuous professional development this tells the hiring manager that you are passionate about your continuous development and your skills and knowledge, your kept up to date. Then your hobbies and interests, good ones to include on studying self development courses, reading self development books, physical fitness activities, charity work or volunteering and then again the references, the name, the position and contact details of two people and finally your own contact details at the end. Now, this is two pages, this engineering CV and resume template in a word document is two pages but as you include your details in the education, work experience and the other sections it will expand to three maybe four pages.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0049}
{"question": "Don't forget, don't go any more than four pages.", "answer": "Let me now tell you where you can download everything. So the next thing to do is click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video head straight through to my website, passmaintevue.com and you can download these slides plus my seven resume and CV ready made templates in word documents that you can use for your engineering job application. Make sure you check out that link. It's a fantastic resource. You can have it in your inbox literally within two minutes from now. Also, don't forget to hit that subscribe button. Please give the video a like. I really do appreciate your support and you can also connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always a pleasure and on a to connect with like minded professional such as yourself. Thank you for watching and wish you all the very best in your pursuit to getting hired as an engineer. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0172}
{"question": "Okay to start with what are behavioral interview questions?", "answer": "Well, behavioral interview questions assess how you have dealt with previous workplace situations. Now, behavioral interview questions start off by any of the following three ways. The interviewer will say to you either, tell me about a time when you or describe a situation or given example of when you. So when you hear them start an interview question in any of those three methods you know you are being asked a behavioral interview question. So they might say, tell me about a time when you deliver excellent customer service or they might say, describe a situation when you were responsible for numerous tasks. And you can see these questions appear to be very difficult to answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0256}
{"question": "So how do you answer behavioral interview questions to get the highest scores achievable?", "answer": "Well, I strongly recommend you use what is called the star technique ST-A-R. Let me teach you the star technique and I will then give you those questions and answers. So the star technique is recognized by all employers and hiring managers as the number one correct way to answer behavioral interview questions. So let's assume you are sat down in the interview chair. The hiring manager says to you, tell me about a time when you worked in 18, you should immediately think, okay, this is a behavioral interview question. I need to use a star technique. So star stands for it's very easy to remember. Situation, task, action, and result. And I recommend you write that down. Take a note of the star technique because you are going to learn it and use it when answering their behavioral interview questions.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0205}
{"question": "So what does it mean? What does the star technique mean?", "answer": "Well, you begin your answer to the behavioral interview question and you outline the situation you were faced with. You then give brief details about the task that need you doing.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What did you need to do?", "answer": "During that situation, you then give in-depth details about the action you took to achieve the task and then you finish off and talk about the results of your actions. Now the result should always be positive. And that's something else to write down. Make sure that the result following your actions is positive. You need to make it positive to pass your job interview. Okay, let me now give you those top scoring behavioral interview questions and answers that use the star technique. And I will also tell you at some stage where you can download my full set of 27 behavioral interview questions and top scoring responses. So the questions I am about to give you are the ones that come up the most during job interviews. And in no particular order, here is the first one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0071}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you delivered excellent customer service.", "answer": "Here's my top scoring example response that uses the star technique. Here we go. I was speaking to a customer on the telephone. They wanted to buy a product but unfortunately, it was out of stock. They thanked me for my time and said they would look elsewhere. Now it was my task to keep the customer on the call and find a workaround that resulted in them getting the products they needed. I asked them several questions about their needs and soon realized we had an alternative product that was more suited to their needs and considerably cheaper. After explaining the benefits of our alternative products, they agreed to purchase it. Now to thank them for being open to my alternative products suggestion, I gave them free shipping. They thanked me for my excellent customer service and left a five star review online. That's a really good answer. You have delivered excellent customer service. You haven't given up on the customer and allowed them to leave the call. You have found a workaround. So it works for the customer and it also works for the company too. Here is my next behavioral interview question to help you pass your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0049}
{"question": "Describe a situation when you were responsible for numerous tasks.", "answer": "This is a difficult one but this answer is perfect. It's a brilliant example and the majority of us have been in this type of situation before. My supervisor asked for a volunteer to cover the work of a coworker who was off sick. I agreed to volunteer because I saw it as an opportunity to diversify my skills and assist the company. My task was to take responsibility for their work in addition to my own and complete everything on time and to the expected standard. I created a list of my and my coworker's tasks placed them in order of priority based on the company's goals and then set to work. I blocked out my diary limited distractions and when I was unsure of a particular task I researched it. I completed all tasks successfully by prioritising and organizing my work effectively remaining calm and demonstrating efficient time management capabilities. That's another really good answer. It's a concise response and you can see how by using that start-to-meat situation task action result it enables you to give perfect top scoring answers. This is another tip for you to take down.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't remember your answers word for word.", "answer": "Remember the scenario. Just remember the story based on the interview question and then remember the start technique and that will prompt you of what you need to talk about in your answer. Here is the next question. Oh by the way, before we move on to the next question, if at any time during this tutorial you want to download these slides and my full set of 27 brilliant answers to difficult behavioral interview questions. You can click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about your time when you had to work with someone you didn't get on with.", "answer": "Wow, this is a really difficult one. Here's my top scoring response that uses the powerful start technique of situation task action and result. Here we go. I was tasked with working in a different team from my usual one. Now despite my best efforts, a long-serving team member in that department was unhelpful and dismissive of my ideas during team meetings. Now, although I felt uncomfortable, I would determine to build a good relationship with her. I found out that we both supported the same sports team and during a work break, I started talking to her about our common interest. She spoke freely and I could tell she was pleased we had a shared love of the team. The next time I put forward ideas during meetings or asked her for assistance on tasks, she was really helpful and we're able to strong working relationship from that point forward. That is a clever smart answer to that difficult interview question because you are trying to find a common interest outside of work which means then she is more amenable to helping you moving forward. So you build a relationship based on your common interest outside of work. That's a very smart answer. And you can see how all of these responses are going to help you be the top candidate at your next interview. Here's an next question. This is another really difficult behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0041}
{"question": "Describe a time when you had a disagreement with your boss or manager.", "answer": "Now most people respond by saying, I've never had a disagreement with them. They are always right and I would do what they say. That's not the way to answer this question. It's not a trick question. They are asking you this behavioral interview question to assess your confidence and how you deal with your disagreement. You need to become and professional. Here's the perfect answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a time when you had a disagreement with your boss.", "answer": "My manager set aside a large budget to market a new product we would soon launch. Now 100% of the budget had been allocated to offline marketing campaigns, such as magazines, trade shows and radio commercials. I felt this wasn't an effective use of the budget. My task was to convince my manager that the budget could be better utilized with a focus on online advertising. I researched to establish the best online platforms where we could easily reach our target audience and presented my idea to my manager. Now after answering her questions and providing facts and evidence of how we could test the results of our marketing online, she agreed to switch 50% of the budget over to my recommendations. Now four weeks after the product launch, we had evidence to prove my online marketing suggestions gave a more significant return and then the entire budget was switched over. So that's a really good response and it shows that you put the interests of the company first. You are not afraid to disagree with your manager and you do it by presenting them with facts and evidence. It's a really strong answer. Here's an ex-behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0049}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you encountered an unexpected problem.", "answer": "This is another really difficult question to answer. Here's my top scoring response to help you. My work colleague and I were hard at work preparing customer orders following the weekend sales. Now unexpectedly one of our key suppliers went out of business and couldn't no longer supply one of our popular products and to make matters more difficult our manager was on annual leave for the week. Our task was to create a solution to this problem to maintain operational efficiency and customer satisfaction. I suggested my colleague should source an alternative product supplier while I contacted all customers to pre-warm them of the slight delay in product dispatch. Now after an hour my colleague's source an alternative supplier at the same cost as the previous one and who could deliver the products to us the following morning. I convinced all customers to wait an additional 24 hours for delivery and to thank them for their patience we gave them a 10% discount voucher of any future orders. Now when our manager returned to work the following week we briefed her on our actions and she praised us for dealing officially with the unexpected problem. That's a cracking answer because it shows that you can deal with a situation while your manager is away it's unexpected and you come up with the perfect solution. It shows that you are professional, you can think on your feet and create the right solution for the company. It shows that you are self-sufficient basically which is what this question is assessing. Here is the next behavioral interview question we need to tackle.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0036}
{"question": "Describe a time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "Again don't say I never make mistakes at work I'm a perfectionist.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't say that.", "answer": "Here's how to respond to it.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "When I started working my previous job my manager asked me to give a presentation to my team. My task was to deliver a presentation on my background, work experience and what I could bring to the team. Now unfortunately I miss heard his instructions and instead of giving a 5 minute presentation I prepared one 15 minutes long after the presentation my manager pointed out my mistake. I apologized for my error and assured him I would write down concise notes and adhere to all instructions moving forward. Following that initial mistake I never made one again and my manager often praised me for my strong work ethic ability to accept feedback and my desire to continually improve. It's never really good answer. These are powerful responses. You can't find these answers anywhere else. Here is an next question tell me about your proudest professional accomplishment. This question is assessing whether or not you are a high achiever. Here's my example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about your proudest professional accomplishment.", "answer": "In my previous job I worked on a team responsible for redesigning and upgrading the company's website. Our task was to work with graphic designers and web developers to create a dynamic user friendly mobile compatible and sales driven website. We established our brief set tasks based on our strengths and set to work. My job was to create search engine friendly blog content for all the pages so they ranked well on Google. My work would help save the company money on advertising costs. Now once the website launched it was a huge success and sales conversions increased by 27% on the previous website design. It was my proudest professional achievement because it was a combined team effort and we surpassed our managers expectations. It's a really good answer because you are saying it's your proudest accomplishment because you are doing something positive for the company. That's a really clever answer and you're saying it was my proudest achievement because it was a combined team effort. It shows you are a team player and you surpassed your managers expectations and that's why it's your proudest accomplishment. That's a smart answer. Now this is a difficult question that is starting to come up more often during job interviews. The behavioural interview question is about change and your ability to adapt to change. The question is, describe a time when your team or company was going through change.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0041}
{"question": "How did the change impact you and what did you do to adapt?", "answer": "Here we go. My previous company had new owners and they wanted to change working practices, hours and systems. The majority of people in the company opposed the new changes. But I saw this as an opportunity to try something new. It was my responsibility to embrace the change because change ensures a business is competitive and it helps maintain its position as a market leader. I listened to the new company owners' proposals, asked questions to determine the reasons for the changes and determine what we could do as a team to support them. I encouraged my work colleagues to try the changes as they may find them positive. Now three months after the changes were implemented, working processes improved and output in the office increased significantly. That shows that you are supportive of change. You understand why it is so important to a company and you are prepared to embrace it and encourage your work colleagues to do the same. Here is the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.006}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you set yourself a goal to achieve. What did you do to ensure you would meet your objective?", "answer": "This is another difficult book common behavioral interview question. Here's my example response that uses that start technique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you set yourself a goal to achieve. What did you do to ensure you would meet your objective?", "answer": "Here we go. After reflecting on my performance in my previous job, I wanted to improve my sales skills. Although competent in my work, I wanted to improve in a skill that would help the company thrive. I set myself the goal of studying and completing an online sales technique course within four weeks. After finding a suitable course on the website udemy.com, I dedicated one hour each evening to learning and studying. After one month, I successfully completed the end of course examination and passed. That's another great answer. The show you reflect on your performance. You set yourself a goal and you work hard to achieve it. At the end you can say my sales skills improved significantly as a result of the course which helped me increase sales for my employer. That's clever at the end because you are giving reasons why your goal had a positive impact on the organization. Nobody's telling you to set that goal. At the beginning, if you remember, we said, after reflecting on my performance in my previous job, I wanted to improve my sales skills. That's the powerful part of that answer. It's a really good response and it shows you are a forward thinking employee. Now, the next thing to do, make sure you click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, passmaintoview.com and you can immediately download these slides plus my full set of unique top scoring answers to behavioral interview questions. You will get 27. Brilliant answers to comment behavioral interview questions at the very least. Go through to that page and have a look at all the questions on those are the ones that come up the majority of time during job interviews, check them out because I want you to be fully prepared for your job interview. Also, I said at the start of this training video, make sure you subscribe to the channel as you can see. I am committed to creating brilliant content for you free content that helps you. Not only pass every job interview, but also negotiate to celebrate and progress throughout your career. I can only help you if you're are subscribed. It's really important. Lots of you are literally earning more money. You are getting promoted and as I said, progress in throughout your career as I can only help you. If you are subscribed, also don't forget to give the video a like. I did ask that at the start. If you haven't liked it, please hit the like button. I do appreciate that support series. There are a lot of work goes into this and if I see you liking the videos, it encourages me to create more for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0042}
{"question": "Don't forget to connect with me on the website linkedin.", "answer": "I have a linkedin profile. I like to connect with like my professional such as yourself. Check the description below the video and you will see my linkedin link. Go across that website, connect with me on linkedin, say hi. It's always good to connect with like my new professional such as yourself. Thank you for watching. I hope you found those answers to difficult behavioral interview questions useful. Have a wonderful day and I wish you all the best for passing your job interview. Thank you for watching.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0333}
{"question": "What does this mean?", "answer": "Well people who work for Amazon start with the customer and they work backward. They always prioritize customer satisfaction over competitors and they focus on earning and keeping their trust. Because that then means the customer will return to Amazon time and time again in the future. So what is an example question that comes up all the time during Amazon interviews that assesses the leadership principle of customer obsession. Here it is right this down. When we about a time when you went above and beyond to meet the needs of a customer. So let me now give you a brilliant example answer to this question that uses that star method situation, task action and result. Here it is. In my previous job, a customer call to discuss a product they needed. They initially showed interest in one of our high ticket price products which presented a significant sales opportunity.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0132}
{"question": "However, I was more concerned with ensuring the product was suitable for their needs than making a quick sale.", "answer": "My task was to ask the customer relevant questions to establish their requirements. I asked the customer what they needed the product for and what was important to them regarding price and quality. If they are listening to the customer's answers, I determined that a cheaper product would be more suitable. I explained how the alternative product worked and why I felt it would be better for their needs. After explaining everything to the customer and answering their questions, they agreed to buy the alternative product. They thanked me for helping them save money and left a positive online review following their experience. For days later, I called the customer to follow up and to ensure the product still met their needs. So you can see how effective the star method is for answering the Amazon leadership principles interview questions. Let's move on to Amazon Leadership Principle number two. And that is, ownership.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0065}
{"question": "What does this mean? What this means that people who work at Amazon act on behalf of the company and they take responsibility and always think long term.", "answer": "They will never say that's not my job or that's not my responsibility. They always take ownership of situations. So here is a common example ownership interview question that comes up all the time at Amazon interviews. And that question is, describe a time when you took ownership of a project or task and saw it through to completion despite challenges. So here is another brilliant example answer again that uses a star method. In my last job, I collaborated on a time sensitive project. Unfortunately, with just ten days to go before the project deadline, two team members fell sick with COVID and they could not work. This situation presented a significant challenge because the absent team members had specialized technical skills. Some people on the team suggested we try to extend the project deadline but I was not prepared to do this. My task was to take control of the project and ensure it was completed on time and to the required standard. To address the situation, I convened a team meeting to reassess the project. I compiled a list of pending tasks and requested the remaining team members to take on additional responsibilities based on their skills and expertise. I also reached out to another department in the company to request the temporary transfer of a team member with the required specialized skills. Now for the remaining technical tasks, I hired a suitably qualified freelance contractor from upwork.com whose contribution was instrumental in overcoming this challenge. Through our collective commitment and innovative thinking, we were able to meet the project deadline which was of significant importance to the company. The successful completion was a testament to my determination and our team's resilient and adaptability in the face of adversity. So that is another brilliant example answer that will help you pass your Amazon interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have many more tips, questions and sample answers to give you but when you are ready, click the link in the top right hand corner of the video and you can instantly download my brilliant example answers to 16 Amazon leadership principles into view questions. But here is the next question I strongly recommend you prepare for. This question is based on the leadership principle of invent and simplify.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0077}
{"question": "What does this leadership principle mean?", "answer": "It means that people who work for Amazon seek innovation and simplicity, they think creatively while finding ways to streamline processes and make things more efficient.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "So the example answer, sorry the example question I recommend you prepare for is, can you give an example of a time when you invented something or found a simpler way to do something?", "answer": "So here is another great example answer to this Amazon leadership principles interview question that uses a star method.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0526}
{"question": "Can you give an example of a time when you invented something or found a simpler way to do something?", "answer": "Here we go. In my last job I was frustrated with the team's culture of waste. People in our office often ordered large quantities of supplies and resources which were not always needed. My task was to create an inventory tracking and ordering system and to also educate team members on how to reduce waste. I searched on YouTube for the best tutorial on creating an inventory tracking and ordering system using Microsoft Excel. Once I had created the Excel spreadsheet which included strict reorder limits, I created a PowerPoint presentation. The presentation would be used to teach the team the importance of a cost-conscious culture and how to use the Excel spreadsheet to manage and order office supplies. Once the presentation was ready I showed everything to my manager and asked his permission to deliver my presentation to the team to which he agreed. My actions combined with the team's dedication led to a 50% saving for the company in office supplies and resources. The Excel spreadsheet also fostered a new cost-conscious work approach in the team demonstrating their commitment to the initiative. That's another really strong example answer that will help you pass your Amazon leadership principles interview. Here is the next leadership principle I recommend you prepare for and that is, are right a lot.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What does this leadership principle mean?", "answer": "Well it means that people who work for Amazon make sound decisions based on judgment and strong instincts. They are right often and seek diverse perspectives to challenge their thinking. So the type of question that comes up all the time at Amazon interviews that assesses this leadership principle is, tell me about a time when you had to make a decision with incomplete information.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0154}
{"question": "How did you make the right decision?", "answer": "Here is my example answer to help you. My manager asked me to launch a new company product in my last job. A lot of time and effort had gone into creating the product and I wanted the launch to succeed. My task was to launch the product to ensure strong sales. Now after quickly analyzing the market, I determined the product needed to be launched immediately to capitalize on seasonal demand. Now unfortunately I did not have sufficient data or information to identify the best social media platforms to promote the product. I would normally conduct thorough market research and obtain customer feedback before commencing the launch but there was insufficient time. I used a combination of my instincts and readily available tools to create the best launch campaign in the time I had available. I used the Google Keyword Planar tool to identify the most searched for terms online and I also asked chat GPT to analyze our competitors use of online platforms. I then launched the product using Google Targeted Adverts based on relevant search terms. I also used Facebook Adverts to target potential customers based on age, gender and demographics I felt would yield the greatest return. The product launch was not just a success, it was a triumph. Our results surpassed all previous product launches by 17%. Now this achievement borne from a combination of my initiative and the resources available to me serves as a testament to what can be achieved even when time and information are not on our side. Now that is another great answer and you can see how these in-depth responses will help you pass your Amazon leadership principles into view. Here is the next leadership principle I strongly recommend you prepare for and that is higher and develop the best.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What does this leadership principle mean at Amazon?", "answer": "Well it means that people who work for Amazon always higher and mentor exceptional talent continually raising the performance bar and developing future leaders. So here is my example question that I strongly recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.027}
{"question": "How have you contributed to the growth and development of others in your previous roles?", "answer": "Here is my example answer that uses a star method. In my previous job I volunteered to help train new team members when they join the organisation. I wanted to develop my coaching and mentoring skills and quickly learn my new co-workers strengths because that would empower me to ensure the team met its objectives. My task was to devise a standardized training program that could be utilized by all incoming team members enabling them to swiftly attain competence. While training the first person, I wrote down a list of competencies they needed to learn and devised a series of step-by-step instructions to teach them how to use company systems and processes correctly. The documents I produced could then be used to train all future new employees to save time. The system I created was so successful that the company owner distributed it to all departments as the best practice model for new staff training. So that is another great answer pause the video and write it down if you want to. Let's move on to Amazon Leadership Principle number 6 which is Learn and Be curious.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0105}
{"question": "What does this mean?", "answer": "Well this means that all people who work for Amazon are constantly looking to improve and expand their knowledge which helps drive personal and professional growth. And the question that comes up all the time is give me an example of a time when you taught yourself and you skill to improve your work performance. This is a great answer again that uses that star method.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Give me an example of a time when you taught yourself and you skill to improve your work performance.", "answer": "Here we go. My last job I noticed that the company spent $1,000 a month with a local marketing agency to increase engagement on social media. After analyzing the work the marketing agency was producing I wasn't convinced this was a good use of company's finances. Recognizing the potential for cost savings I took the initiative to learn how to create engaging social media posts aiming to contribute to the company's financial efficiency. I watched an online marketing tutorial before teaching myself how to use Canva to create social media images. I also learned how to use chatGPT to create engaging social media posts based on our industry that we could upload to the company's social media channels with a scheduled post date. I then showed my manager the skills I had learned and persuaded him to stop using the marketing agency and permit me to handle the company's social media accounts. After my manager agreed I started periodically posting content online which resulted in a $1,000 monthly savings for the company. So that's another great answer. Let's move on to Amazon Leadership Principle number 7 which is insist on the highest standards. Now as you and I already know, Amazon has really high standards. That is why people use them all the time. I think in the last year I have ordered more than 360 products from Amazon and I use them because they have outstanding customer service and their standards are really high.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0039}
{"question": "Now what does this Leadership Principle mean?", "answer": "Well, it means that people who work for Amazon hold high standards, they constantly push to deliver top quality results even if others view it as unrealistic. An question that comes up all the time based on this Leadership Principle is, tell me about the time when you refuse to compromise on standards even though it was easier to do so. Let me give you my brilliant example answer that uses the star method here we go. I was attending a team meeting to discuss a client project we were required to collaborate on. During the meeting, two senior team members suggested we cut corners to save time and money. They argued that the client would never find out and we could reduce our project costs significantly. I strongly disagreed with their suggestion. My task was to speak out, disagree with their suggestions and explain the reasons why. I immediately argued that their suggestion was morally and contractually wrong. The client had paid good money for the project to be delivered in a specific way. Deviating from the agreed project specifications could damage the reputation of our employer and make the project unsafe. After listening to my arguments against their proposal, they agreed it was not a good idea. My actions demonstrate my understanding of how important customer obsession is to the success of a business and my ability to challenge decisions to achieve better outcomes. The brilliant answer that will help you demonstrate that leadership principle of insist on the highest standards. Let's move on to the next Amazon leadership principle and that is, think big.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0037}
{"question": "What does this mean?", "answer": "Well it means that people who work for Amazon create and communicate bold ideas that inspire and challenge, they always take calculated risks to achieve long-term impact. The question that comes up all the time is, describe a time when you took a big risk in pursuit of a large goal. This is a really difficult question to answer, but here is my excellent top scoring answer that uses a star method. The first thing to do is to describe a situation when you took a big risk in pursuit of a large goal. Here we go. In my previous role, we faced delays and errors from a long-term supplier causing customer complaints and affecting service reliability.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, switching suppliers carried risks, including potential disruptions and uncertainty, and finding a reliable replacement.", "answer": "My goal was to improve service reliability, customer retention and sales while minimizing risks associated with changing suppliers. After assessing options, I chose to cancel a supplier's contract. I negotiated a short-term agreement with a new supplier with performance metrics and penalties for non-compliance. I also implemented contingency plans monitored their performance closely and communicated with our team to prepare for potential transition issues. The transition went smoothly, improving delivery times by 20% and reducing errors by 30%. Customer satisfaction increased, leading to a 15% boost in retention and higher sales due to positive reviews and word of mouth. So that is a really good answer. I like how at the end you are giving percentages that help demonstrate how your actions help the company to improve. So there are eight remaining leadership principles you need to prepare for. We've already covered the first date. The next eight are bias for action, frugality, earn trust, dive deep, have backbone, disagree and commit deliver results, strive to be earth's best employer and success and scale bring broad responsibility. Now if you want my example answers that use the star method to all 16 leadership principles so that includes the eight that we've just covered plus an additional eight, go through to my website and click the link right now in the top right-end corner of the video. So go through to my website, passmainterview.com and you can instantly download these slides with all the exam palancers plus an additional eight Amazon leadership principles, interview answers that cover those final eight leadership principles. Go through to my website and you can literally have this guide in your inbox within two minutes from now. Also please make sure you hit that subscribe button thousands of you and I mean thousands of you are passing your job interviews at the first attempt. I can only help you if you are subscribed please hit the like button because that really does motivate me to create more great content for you and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an honor and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching and I wish you all the very best for passing your Amazon interview have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0199}
{"question": "So to begin with, what are behavioral interview questions?", "answer": "Well, behavioral interview questions are says how you have dealt with previous workplace situations as a software engineer. Now behavioral interview questions often start with either tell me about a time, describe a situation or give an example of when you and then they give the scenario. So they could say, tell me about a time when you had to solve a complex code problem or they could say describe a situation when you had to collaborate with a difficult software engineer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0122}
{"question": "So how do you answer these difficult behavioral interview questions?", "answer": "Well, I strongly recommend you use the start technique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "So what is the start technique?", "answer": "Well, the start technique is recognized by all hiring managers and employers as the correct way to answer behavioral interview questions. So let's assume you are sat down in the chair or you are undertaking your interview online and the hiring manager says to you, tell me about a time when you had to manage competing deadlines as a software engineer. As soon as you hear the interview question, start in that way you should automatically think to yourself, I need to use a start technique when answering this question. So start stands for situation, task, action and then result. So let me explain what each of those different elements are. So the hiring manager asks you a behavioral interview question. You start off in you outline the situation you were faced with. So you are actually telling them a story about a situation you have previously been in. You then move on and outline the task that needed your attention. You then move on and give in depth details about the action you took and then finally, finish your answer and talk about the results of your actions. And it's really important to make sure the result is a positive outcome for your team or company. So let me now give you some examples of behavioral interview questions and answers for software engineers that use the start technique. I will tell you where you can download all of the answers. You can see in a second how effective this start technique is for answering software engineer behavioral interview questions. So the first question I want to tackle is, tell me about the time when you had to solve a complex code problem. Here's an example answer that uses a start technique. Here we go. In a previous software engineering position, I worked on coding problems for an internal department. And in experience software engineer had created the code, but was on annual leave. So I could not contact him to discuss the issue. Therefore, I had to use a common sense approach to solving the problem. Now the most common errors, junior software engineers unwittingly make, are syntax and logic. Now because the system was generating a wrong solution, I presumed it was a logic error. And after further investigation, I confirmed this was the issue. Now once the problem had been rectified, I emailed the junior software engineer to explain the problem, I had found and advised him on how to prevent it from reoccurring. I recommended that he break down his code into small, manageable chunks and then test it before progressing to the next. So that's a really good example answer you are talking about. A situation you have previously been in where you solved a difficult coding problem. You used a process of elimination. And also I like the fact at the end of your answer. You are contacting the software engineer to help him or her not make the same error in the future. So there's a positive outcome for the team and company. It's a really good answer. Here's the next behavioral interview question and example answer for software engineers. The question is, describe a situation when you had to collaborate with a difficult software engineer. So this question is assessing your team working skills and communication capabilities. Here's my top scoring response that uses that all important. Start technique. Here we go. The first one is, describe a situation when you had to collaborate with a difficult software engineer. I was working on a project for a company client with three other software engineers. We all had varying levels of knowledge and expertise which was a strength.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0209}
{"question": "However, one of the engineers continually insisted his approach to solving the project challenges was right despite data and evidence suggesting otherwise.", "answer": "I detected his communication style and arrogance irritated the other engineers. So I decided to speak to him in private. I wanted the project to run smoothly. So decided to stop the conflict before it escalated. I explained to the engineer that his expertise and talent were invaluable to the team, but that we needed to focus on the facts and data to progress the project action plan. After I'd explained that time was of the essence and that we needed to collaborate solely based on the project objectives he agreed to change communication style. So that's a really good answer. It shows that you take positive action to diffuse the conflict and you use really good communication style to get your coworker to change their approach to stop that conflict from escalating. So it's a really good example answer and it shows that you can collaborate with difficult people to achieve your software engineering project objectives. Here's an question. Well, before we move on to the next question, I just want to let you know that if at any time you want to download these slides plus an additional 25 great answers to software engineering to be questioned, you can click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Let me move on to that next question and that is, tell me about a time when you had to manage competing deadlines as a software engineer. This is a really difficult question, but it is assessing your organization and prioritizing capabilities.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0193}
{"question": "Can you be left alone to manage competing deadlines? And if so, how do you achieve that goal?", "answer": "Well, here's a brilliant example answer that uses a start technique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What I'm about to time when you had to manage competing deadlines, here we go.", "answer": "In my last software engineer position, I volunteered to continue the work of a coworker who was on leave for several weeks. We were both working on separate time-sensitive projects, but I saw this as an opportunity to help him and the company during a busy period. It was my task to prioritize the workload for both projects to ensure the competing deadlines were met. I was using a grant chart for my project, so I set up another one for my coworkers to assess priorities and measure progress during the two week period. This proved to be a brilliant idea because I quickly determined that there were identical tasks across both projects that could be completed concurrently. Now for the tasks requiring separate time allocation, I drew up a list of the priorities, mock-tow all distractions and work quickly and efficiently. By being organised and analyzing tasks for both projects and creating a priorities list, I could make excellent progress on both projects while my coworker was on leave. So that again shows that you are willing to go above and beyond for the company, you are helping out your coworker and you don't need to be told what to do. And you are finding a smart solution because by using two grant charts you can see that there are work areas that you can do concurrently, so it's a really good answer. Here's the next behavioral interview question for software engineers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0121}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you had to persuade someone at work.", "answer": "This is another trick you want. Here's my example answer that uses the start technique to help you pass your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you had to persuade someone at work.", "answer": "Here we go. In a previous role, there was no uniformity in the software engineering teams project management applications. This meant that one week I could work on a project that used Monday.com. And the next week I'd be on a project that used resource guru. Now this lack of uniformity was not only holding up the progression of software engineering work, but it also meant new team members had to get familiar with various project management tools before they commenced work. So I decided to do something about it. I researched the best project management applications on the market for software engineers. I created a mini presentation highlighting the benefits of using the one I felt most suited the business strategic goals. I then met with my team and manager and presented my findings. At the end of the presentation, my manager thought it was a great idea and she took steps to change company policy so that only one project management tool was used and everyone had the appropriate training in its operation. That's a really good answer. It shows that you can see that there is a problem in the software engineering team. You want to create a solution that speeds up the progression of work and and a lot of the fact that you are creating a presentation, presenting it to your manager and team and then they are taking it forward to improve the business. So it's a really good example that comes out with a positive result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0117}
{"question": "Don't forget, make sure that when you're using the start technique, the result is a positive one for your team or company.", "answer": "Here is the next question. The next behavioral interview question for software engineers and that is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you failed at work.", "answer": "Now sometimes people respond by saying, I've never failed. I'm really good at my work. I will not let you down. I don't fail. That is not what this question is assessing. This question is assessing two things. Number one, your honesty and number two, how you respond to failure.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Do you learn from it? Do you accept responsibility, take ownership and then move forward?", "answer": "That's what they are looking for. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0625}
{"question": "Tell me about the time when you failed at work.", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous software engineering position. I was tasked with estimating the time it would take to create a web application for the company. I'd done this type of work many times before, so I was confident it wouldn't take long. It was my task to estimate the time for the project, create a plan of action and put forward a working proposal to my manager before setting to work. I anticipated it would take 10 days to complete the work. Now unfortunately, I made a foolish mistake and failed to consult a colleague of mine who I needed to carry out some development work on the project. After I'd submitted my proposal and it was accepted, I learned that my colleague was on holiday for that period. To ensure the project was still completed, I contacted a colleague from my network of software engineers and he agreed to carry out the development work for me. Now although the project was still completed, I learned a tremendous amount from that experience and now make sure I double check my action plans and work schedules before submitting them. So that's an honest answer, but what I also like about it, you still complete the project on time because you find an alternative solution. So there is a positive outcome you are taking on board the fact that you failed and you are learning from it and that's really important. So the next thing to do, if you want to accelerate your learning even further and make sure you pass your software engineer interview at the first attempt, is click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintivue.com and you can immediately download these slides with those great answers plus an additional 25 brilliant responses to difficult software engineer interview questions. It comes as a PDF guide and that means you can have it in your inbox literally within two minutes from now. Make sure you check out that link also. Please make sure you hit that subscribe button. I genuinely want to help you pass your interview and also progress throughout your career and negotiate to higher salary. I can only do those things if you are subscribed. Please give the video a like because that really does motivate me to create more content for you and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always a pleasure and an honour to connect with like minded professionals such as yourselves. Thank you for watching and I wish you all a very best for passing your software engineer interview. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.015}
{"question": "So to start with what are the Amazon leadership principles?", "answer": "Well, the 16 leadership principles are used every day in Amazon's work, including whenever exploring new product and service ideas or whenever they need to overcome difficult and challenging problems. So they want all of their employees to know the Amazon leadership principles and use them in their everyday work. They are basically the foundations of Amazon's success and in my opinion, Amazon is the greatest company in the world. And predominantly the reason why they have had so much success is because they hire the right people and they want those people to follow and use the 16 leadership principles. So you will be assessed against your knowledge understanding and experience of the 16 Amazon leadership principles. Therefore, you need to know them and understand them. And if you know them and understand them, it makes it far easier for you to get hired with this brilliant organisation. So let's now take a look at a quick overview of the 16 Amazon leadership principles and I will then work through some test questions with you and also give you more importantly some Amazon leadership principles into your questions to prepare for. So the 16 Amazon leadership principles briefly are customer obsession. Now Amazon obsesses over its customers. I use Amazon virtually every day. I think in the last month, I've placed over 30 orders. And I use Amazon because their customer service is so good. If there are any problems, I can contact them online and they will sort it out straight away. Amazon has been so successful because it obsesses over its customers. The next one in particular order is frugality. Now frugality is making sure that you look after resources you use them sparringly because the success of a business or an organisation such as Amazon isn't just focused on its turnover, how much it makes. It's also focused on keeping an eye on profits. So it expects all of its staff to take care of resources and supplies. The next one is that leaders are right a lot of the time. So leaders have the experience and the knowledge at Amazon to make the right decisions. The next one is deliver results. When you work at Amazon, you will be expected to deliver results. It's really important. And that brings me on to the next one which is a bias for action. There's a once people who work for its company to take action, to act with speed and not be afraid to take risks. The next one is learning be curious. So you need to be willing as an Amazon employee to always learn, be open to learning and also be curious. Look into things, find out how things work. The next one is that Amazon always hire and develops the best people. They want to raise the bar every time they hire someone new. And they also want to develop people. So if you were working at Amazon and someone in your team had the potential to progress, you should help them develop the right skills to progress through the organization because then that helps Amazon maintain its position as the number one e-commerce website in the world. The next Amazon leadership principle is a really important one which is dive deep. Amazon expects it to start to look into information and data carefully to dive deep into it because then that gives you the information and data to make the right decisions and to continually improve. The next one is that all Amazon employees should think big. Okay, think big and create brilliant products and services for their customers. So the next of our 16 Amazon leadership principles is insist on the highest standards. And this is definitely one of my favorites because in an organization such as Amazon, if you always insist everyone works to the highest standards achievable, you will gain success. The next leadership principle is invent and simplify. Amazon, once it's employees to come up with brilliant ideas that improve the efficiency of the company and the customer experience and they want to make things as simple as possible. The next leadership principle is strive to be the best employer. So Amazon takes its responsibility seriously. It wants everyone to be safe while they are at work. And it also wants to make sure that it employees a diverse workforce because diversity in any workforce is only a good thing. And it also takes responsibility for the impact it has on our environment. The next one of our 16 Amazon leadership principles is success and scale. Bring broad responsibility again. Amazon because of its success understands that it needs to take responsibility for its actions. The next leadership principle is to have backbone, disagree and then commit. So while that means it's, it wants its employees to not be afraid to disagree if they think something is wrong or if it can be done in a more efficient and effective manner. But it then also wants people to commit to the general consensus of what people are doing in the organization to succeed. And finally, the 16th Amazon leadership principle is earned trust. So you have to build trust between your team members, build trust with customers. And that will help the organization to succeed. So there's the 16 Amazon leadership principles, a brief overview. My interpretation of those leadership principles. So what we will now do is start taking a look at some Amazon leadership principles. Test questions to help you develop your knowledge and your understanding of them. Because as I mentioned previously, the Amazon leadership principles are crucial to your success. So the first question that I want to work through is based on the Amazon leadership principle of customer obsession. So just a quick recap, Amazon is obsessed with its customers, obsessed with giving out standing customer service and also creating products and services that make their customers lives better. So question one states, read the following information before choosing your answer. So I will put up on the screen a scenario and I will then give you four answer options. You choose which answer option you would go for based on the leadership principle of customer obsession. So the statement is, you are working as a customer service representative and a customer calls you during your schedule tea break to complain about the delay in receiving a product they have ordered. Now the customer paid for a 24 hour priority delivery service, but 48 hours have now passed. Answer product is ordered and dispatched. It is in the hands of a third party career company.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0214}
{"question": "What would you do in this situation?", "answer": "Answer option A. Ask the customer to call you back in 30 minutes once your tea break has finished. You will then deal with their complaint. Answer option B, apologise to the customer for the delay in them receiving their product. Ask for their order number until the customer, you will investigate the issue and call them back within the hour with an update. Contact the career company to obtain an exact delivery date before updating the customer and refunding their priority delivery fee. Logic complaint with a career company, it is important to make sure the situation does not happen again. Answer option C, apologise to the customer, but inform them that a third party career company takes care of company deliveries and it is therefore out of your hands. Tell the customer you will refund the fee they paid for the priority delivery service or answer option D, apologise to the customer for the delay in them receiving their product. Ask for their order number before telling the customer to contact the career company themselves to obtain an exact delivery date and time.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Explain to the customer that all orders are handled by a third party career company for which you have no control. So which answer option would you choose?", "answer": "In my opinion, the only one that is relevant and suitable to customer obsession is answer option B. That is what Amazon would do in that scenario. If you choose any of the other three, you are not demonstrating customer obsession, which is being obsessed with customers, obsessed with giving outstanding customer service. So now it is your turn to try one live on the screen. So I want to tell you the answer or want you to tell me the answer to question number two in the comment section below the video please and I will come on here each day and mark your answers for you. So this Amazon leadership principle is based on fruit gallery. So question number two, read the following information before choosing your answer. You are working in an office and you feel the way office supplies are ordered is ineffective. Everyone in the team has the power to order office supplies as and when they need them. This results in several deliveries each week to the office which is costing the company expensive curry of fees.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0219}
{"question": "What would you do?", "answer": "Answer option A. This situation is the responsibility of your supervisor. If they are happy with the way office supplies are ordered, so be it. Answer option B. This situation is the responsibility of your supervisor, inform them about your concerns, so they can make a decision on what to do moving forward. Answer option C. Raise your concerns during the next team meeting and ask everyone to be more mindful about how they order supplies or answer option D.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.025}
{"question": "Do some research and obtain information that backs up your concerns.", "answer": "Create a proposal for how you think the team should order supplies moving forward to limit waste and then present your ideas to your manager for consideration. Now there is a timer on the right hand side. You have 10 seconds to put your answer option in the comment section below the video. Here's a time. And don't forget that leadership principle is based on fruitality. Is your answer option A. B. C. or D. Now don't go anywhere because I still have many more questions and answers to work through review that will help you prepare fully for the Amazon selection process. But when you're ready, click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Head through to my website how to become.com and you can download my full set of Amazon leadership principles, test questions and also some brilliant answers to Amazon leadership principles into view questions. It's a great resource. Make sure you check that out when you are ready. Let's now work through Amazon leadership principles, test question number three and this is based on higher and develop the best. So question three read the following information before choosing your answer. You are working as a manager in a large organization and one of your best performing members of staff wants to go for a promotion. They need your approval to apply for the promotion. Now they have only been with the company for six months and they are relatively young. If they get promoted, they will move to a different department and you will lose your strongest team member.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0036}
{"question": "What would you do? Don't forget to focus on the leadership principle.", "answer": "Answer option A. Support them in their pursuit to get promoted. Now the needs of the organization come before the needs of your team and it's important that you encourage and develop talent because this helps the business grow. Their age and time with the company are irrelevant. Answer option B.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Do not support them in their pursuit to get promoted because they are the strongest member of your team and they have only been with the company for a few months.", "answer": "You don't feel the time is right for them to get promoted. Answer options C. In form them, you will consider supporting them in the future once they have gained more experience. Tell them they are young and inexperienced but you will coach them over the next few months to help them prepare for future promotion. Or answer option D. In form them, they are your strongest performing team member and you cannot afford to lose them. Tell them you are sorry but you cannot support their application.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Explain that once a new team member comes who is as good as they are, you will reconsider.", "answer": "Which answer option would you choose A. B. C. Or D. Well the only one that is relevant to Amazon's leadership principle is A. Support them in their pursuit to get promoted. The needs of the organization come before the needs of your team and it's important you encourage and develop talent because this helps the business grow. So don't forget the leadership principle of hiring develop the best means that this answer shows your ability to encourage and support talent. You understand that the needs of the organization must come first and your selfless approach to this situation identifies high performing members of staff, their needs and how they can help the organization progress. So now it's your turn to try another one on your own live on the screen. Please put your answer to question four in the comment section below for marking. Thank you. So this Amazon leadership principle is based on strive to be the Earth's best employer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.018}
{"question": "Don't forget being an Amazon employee means making sure the working environment is safe productive and responsible.", "answer": "Amazon understands the importance of having a diverse workforce and it takes its responsibility seriously in respect of the environment. So again I will put the passage up on the screen and you choose the answer option which you would follow if you were working at Amazon. Here we go. You are walking through the warehouse whilst working at Amazon. When you notice a member of staff not wearing the correct personal protective clothing. Now the member of staff is not your responsibility from a management point of view.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0112}
{"question": "But what would you do in this scenario?", "answer": "A. Now because I am not managing the member of staff, they are not my responsibility. It is the responsibility of their manager to enforce company safety rules and so option B. Speak to the member of staff and ask them why they aren't wearing the appropriate personal protective clothing. If they don't have a valid reason, ask them to start wearing it immediately. Answer option C. Speak to the member of staff and ask them why they aren't wearing the appropriate personal protective clothing. If they don't have a valid reason, tell their manager so they can take the appropriate disciplinary reaction or answer option D. Speak to the member of staff and ask them why they aren't wearing the appropriate personal protective clothing. Now if they They don't have a valid reason. Awesome to start wearing it immediately and explain why. It is so important to wear the clothing at work and follow company rules. You have 10 seconds to put your answer in the comment section below the video. Here's your timer. Fantastic. We're making brilliant progress in helping you prepare for the Amazon selection process. So now it's time to try another one. Another Amazon leadership principles test question. Again, put your answer to question five in the comments section below the video. This one is based on bias for action. This is a difficult one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0167}
{"question": "Tell me what you would do in this scenario. Don't forget bias for action is working fast and getting things done.", "answer": "And that's the difference between success and failure at Amazon. So Amazon encourages calculated risks that help the business move forward and maintain its position as the world's number one e-commerce website. Here we go. Read the following passage before choosing your answer. You work for a company that has just had its best financial year ever. You are holding a team meeting and a member of staff comes up with a new product idea. Now they present their idea to you. And whilst it appears to be an idea that could significantly improve the company's turnover, it is costly to develop and launch.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0093}
{"question": "What would you do in this situation?", "answer": "Answer option A. Thank them for putting forward their idea but explain the cost is too expensive. The company has just had its best financial year ever and you don't want to risk spending money on something that might not work. Answer option B. Thank them for putting forward their idea and agree to allocate the money to its development and launch. Answer option C. Thank them for putting forward their idea. Glory their idea in greater detail to establish its viability and the exact costs versus the potential return. Now with the data and information makes business sense, go ahead and develop and launch the product. Answer option D. Thank them for putting forward their idea. Tell them the company has had its best financial year ever and you don't want to agree to it just yet.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, you will explore their idea at a later stage. Tell me in the comment section below which answer option you would choose. What would you do in that situation?", "answer": "Here's the 10 second timer. You can see that all of these questions are helping you. These scenarios are helping you to develop your understanding and knowledge of the Amazon leadership principles.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What I now want to do is move on and take a look at some Amazon leadership principles into you questions.", "answer": "So you will be assessed against the leadership principles during your forthcoming Amazon interview. The first question we will look at is, tell me about a time when you are to work with limited time or resources. Now this is based on deliver results which is basically get things done on time and to the required standard. Amazon employees are never held back by setbacks or remember that. Now the best way before I give you an example answer to structure your answers to Amazon leadership principles into your questions is to use a start technique. So the start technique stands for situation, task, action and result. So you start off by outlining the situation you were faced with. You then give brief details about the task that needed doing. You then go into specific details about the action you took to complete the task and then finally you finish off and tell the interviewer the results following your actions. Let me now give you an example answer to that difficult Amazon leadership principles interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0227}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to work with limited time or resources that utilizes a start technique.", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous job I was working as part of a team on a very important time-sensitive project. Partway through the project, two team members went off sick which placed enormous pressure on the project due to the lack of resources. It was my responsibility to find a solution to this problem then ensure the project still got delivered on time and to the right standards. So I called a team meeting with the remaining team members and encouraged everyone to put forward their ideas as to how we could get through this challenge. I suggested which commit extra hours to the project and assess which elements we could outsource online to experience and qualified freelancers. Everyone agreed to these ideas and I started assessing which tasks could be outsourced. Now after several hours analysing the project tasks and seeking suitable freelancers online I managed to find someone to be qualified who could do the work we needed. After each team member had committed to an additional three hours work per week and by using the freelancer we still managed to get the project delivered for our company on time and to the expected standard. It's not a really good answer because it is a situational response of situation that perhaps you've been in previously. You give details about the action you took. Now a lot of people would simply go to their manager and say, you know we're a couple of staff down what do we do but you are taking the initiative you are thinking on your feet and you are not being overcome by that setback and that's what Amazon wants people to not be afraid of setbacks to come up with innovative ideas to make sure things are done on time. Let's quickly look at more Amazon leadership principles, interview questions that I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0063}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you took responsibility for a task outside of your job description.", "answer": "The next one, tell me about a time when you found a simple solution to a complex problem.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to make an unpopular decision.", "answer": "That's a difficult one. The next one, tell me about a time when you challenged someone's decision. Here's some more.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you influenced a positive change in an organization. Tell me about a time when you came up with an idea that improved the efficiency of an organization. Tell me about a time when you exceeded a customer's expectations and tell me about a time when you had to work with limited information or data.", "answer": "These are all really difficult. Amazon interview questions to prepare for. If you would like further help, the next thing to do is click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video. Head through to my website how to become.com and you can download my Amazon leadership principles, test questions and answers and also brilliant example responses to all of those are more Amazon leadership principles interview questions. It's a fantastic resource. Make sure you check that out right now. Finally, don't forget to hit that subscribe button. I love helping you guys prepare for your job interviews. I can only do that if you are subscribed. Please give the video a like because that motivates me to create more content for you. And don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always good to connect with light minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and for supporting my channel and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon test or interview have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0154}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself here we go.", "answer": "Thank you for this opportunity to become a business analyst for Amazon. I am a technically driven and collaborative business analyst with the experience, knowledge and soft skills to meet the roles demands. After obtaining my degree at insert the university, I worked for several organizations where I developed my analytical programming and business automation skills. I am a high achiever. In my last position, I was praised by my manager for my responsive work ethic and how I helped build and managed company key performance indicators to measure, control and benchmark reporting processes. Before applying for this position, I studied Amazon's leadership principles to ensure I have what it takes to add considerable value to the organization. If you hire me, I will support cross-functional teams to achieve their objectives, take ownership of reporting processes and work hard to innovate and improve customer experience. And I look forward to sharing additional details in the interview regarding my suitability for this position. So that is a brilliant example answer to that first, Amazon Business Analyst interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0056}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself. Don't forget, write down your answer and practice it before your interview to demonstrate confidence and good communication skills.", "answer": "So you can either pause the video if you want to and write down the tips, questions and answers as we work through them together or if you wait, I will soon tell you where you can instantly download my full set of 21 brilliant answers to difficult but common Amazon Business Analyst interview questions. But here is the next question that I strongly recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0147}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "Tip number one. So this next common interview question is assessing your motivations for wanting to work for this brilliant organization. Now I believe Amazon is probably the best organization in the world. They are a fantastic employer and therefore competition is fierce. So you must demonstrate a genuine desire for wanting to work at Amazon in your response. So tip number two, good things to include in your answer are, Amazon's impressive track record of success. So this means you will be working for a high achieving organization. You should also again mention Amazon's 16 leadership principles and how these will be the foundation of your work as a business analyst. And then finally, you can say that Amazon is a company that takes calculated risks and you find that attractive because that means you will be able to collaborate on exciting and forward thinking projects that make a real difference. So here is another brilliant example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0305}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "Here we go. I want to work for Amazon because you are the industry leader and have been for a long time. Amazon's successful track record tells me I will work for an innovative forward thinking, calculated risk taking organization that impowers its staff to contribute ideas to the business's commercial objectives. I thrive in fast-paced dynamic environments where critical thinking is essential. Finally, I want to work for Amazon because of your 16 leadership principles. These are values that I believe in. The leadership principles will give me clear foundations to work from and the fact that you are constantly improving, learning and customer centric gives me the confidence to be pushed and challenged in my work which is important to me. So that's another really good answer that's going to help you stand out from the competition at your Amazon business analyst interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have many more questions, tips and answers to give you. But when you are ready, you can click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video and head straight through at my website, pastmaintevue.com and download a copy of these slides plus my full set of 21 great answers to difficult but common Amazon business analyst interview questions. But here is the next question that comes up all the time in Amazon business analyst interviews. And that question is describe a time when you used data to solve a complex problem.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.004}
{"question": "What was the outcome?", "answer": "Tip number one. Now the majority of your Amazon business analyst interview will be focused on answering behavioral interview questions that are centered on the 16 leadership principles and tip number two. When answering this challenging behavioral interview question, I recommend you give a specific situation where you solve the problem that had a positive impact on the company. So let me give you a great sample answer to help you pass your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0135}
{"question": "Describe a time when you used data to solve a complex problem here we go.", "answer": "In my previous analyst role for an e-commerce company, I was tasked with improving customer retention which had been declining for several months. The challenge was to identify the root causes of customer churn which involved analyzing a vast amount of customer interaction data, purchase histories and use of feedback. I began by segmenting the customers into different cohorts based on their purchase frequency, product categories and engagement levels with our marketing campaigns. Using SQL and Python, I created queries to extract key metrics from our database such as average order value, the time between repeat purchases and customer lifetime value. After analyzing the data, I identified a few key insights, customers who received personalized product recommendations had a 20% higher retention rate. A specific product category had a higher return rate leading to customer dissatisfaction. Our email campaigns were not effectively targeting high value customers as they were receiving generic offers. Based on these findings, I recommended that we personalise our marketing emails based on customer purchase behavior and preferences. Additionally, I suggested improving product quality in the category with a higher return rate. These changes led to a 15% improvement in customer retention within three months and they noticeable increase in customer satisfaction as reflected in our net promoter score. So that is a really good in-depth answer to that common Amazon business analyst interview question describe a time when you used data to solve a complex problem. Here is the next question, again that I strongly recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0039}
{"question": "Describe a time when you had to make a quick decision.", "answer": "Tip number one. Now Amazon business analysts must make fast decision that allow the organization to continually improve and meet customer demand. Tip number two, give a specific situation where you used data and information to improve company systems or processes that had a positive outcome on the customer or client experience. So let me give you another brilliant example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0156}
{"question": "Describe a time when you had to make a quick decision.", "answer": "In my previous role, there was an instance where I had to make a quick decision during a critical online sales event. We were running a flash sale on one of our most popular product lines and midway through the event, I noticed a significant drop in conversion rates. This was alarming as it could have severely impacted the revenue generated from the sale and the team needed a swift resolution. With limited time to conduct a full analysis, I immediately pulled real-time data from our sales dashboard, I noticed that many customers were abandoning their carts at the payment page. I quickly cross-references with customer feedback, we had been receiving an identified a pattern. Several customers were encountering issues with a specific payment gateway that was not processing orders properly. I made the quick decision to advise the team to temporarily disable that payment option and re-root customers to our PayPal payment option. Within minutes, our tech team implemented the change and I monitored the conversion rates closely. The result was a swift recovery in sales conversions with a 12% increase in the next hour, which helped save the remainder of the event. So that is another brilliant example answer. You can see how I am using percentage increases at the end of my answers to demonstrate that I have had a positive impact on the company and that's a really good tip to give you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0041}
{"question": "Where possible use percentage increases as a result of your actions?", "answer": "Here is an next question. Again, that comes up all the time in Amazon, Business, Analyst, Interviews.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What would you do if you had a conflict with one of your co-workers?", "answer": "So tip number one, the ability to collaborate effectively with your co-workers at Amazon is crucial to the company's success. So this next common interview question assesses your ability to overcome conflict to ensure continued progress in teams. And tip number two, I recommend in your answer you say that you would take ownership of the conflict to empower the team to quickly move forward. So let me put all of that together in my brilliant sample answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0361}
{"question": "What would you do if you had a conflict with one of your co-workers?", "answer": "Conflict teams can be healthy because it demonstrates passion and they desire to achieve strong results for the employer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, if not handled professionally, it can hinder progress.", "answer": "Therefore, I would do three things to overcome it swiftly. First, I would assess my words and actions to ensure I wasn't the cause. Next, I would meet privately with my co-worker to establish their views and ideas based on the team's objectives. And finally, I would hold open and honest conversations with my co-worker to find an amicable solution that empowers to move forward. So that's a really good answer because you are saying you will take ownership of the conflict to achieve a satisfactory solution that is in the best interests of your team and employer. It's a really good professional answer. Here is an next question again that comes up all the time. This is another behavioral interview question. This is a difficult one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0075}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a difficult decision to sacrifice short-term gain for a longer term goal. How do you answer this question?", "answer": "Let me give you two tips. Tip number one. So this next difficult Amazon business analyst interview question is assessing the leadership principles of our right a lot and insist on the highest standards. Tip number two, give a specific situation where you recommended your company took an alternative course of action to achieve improved results. So let me give you another brilliant example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0308}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a difficult decision to sacrifice short-term gain for a longer term goal.", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous role as a business analyst, we were launching a new product line that had high revenue potential. There was a lot of pressure from upper management to launch it as soon as possible to capitalize on the upcoming holiday season.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, during the final stages of testing, I discovered through data analysis that our supply chain wasn't equipped to handle the surge in demand we were projecting.", "answer": "If we went ahead with the launch, we risked running into significant full-filmed issues which would lead to customer dissatisfaction and damage to our brand's reputation. I recommended delaying the launch by four weeks. This decision meant missing out on the holiday sales boost, but it would give us time to strengthen our supply chain, streamline logistics and then show the product was delivered without any major setbacks. It was a difficult decision as we had to forego short-term revenue and there was an initial resistance from some stakeholders.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, once I presented the data showing the potential long-term benefits, they agreed to delay the launch.", "answer": "In the long run, this decision led to a higher customer satisfaction, stronger brand loyalty and even higher revenue than initially projected. So that's another great example answer. I recommend when you answer these difficult Amazon behavioral interview questions, you give in-depth situations and these are in-depth examples where you are demonstrating those leadership principles. Here is the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0159}
{"question": "Why should we hire you?", "answer": "Tip number one. So this next common Amazon business analyst interview question will be asked to all candidates and the Amazon hiring manager will use yours and the other candidate's answers to help them decide which analyst can add the most value to the business. So tip number two, make sure you give several reasons why you are the best candidate and again, reference the leadership principles in your response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0282}
{"question": "How do you do that?", "answer": "Here is another example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why should we hire you?", "answer": "I am an ideal candidate for the Amazon business analyst role due to my strong analytical skills, problem solving abilities and alignment with Amazon's leadership principles. I am deeply committed to customer obsession using data to provide actionable insights that enhance the customer experience. I take ownership of my work ensuring long-term solutions and I act with bias for action making data driven decisions quickly and effectively. I also dive deep into data ensuring that my insights are thorough and lead to informed strategies. I am constantly pushing for improvement in line with insist on the highest standards always striving for innovation and excellence. My skills and values align perfectly with Amazon's mission and I am eager to contribute to your continued success. Great answer. I love these responses. So the next thing to do to accelerate your learning even further is make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintevue.com and you can instantly download these slides plus my full set of 21 great answers to difficult but common, Amazon business analyst interview questions. You can have all of it in your inbox literally within two minutes from now. Make sure you check out that link. Also please subscribe, hit the like button. It's a small ask but it really does motivate me to spend a lot of time putting together this valuable content for you and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an honor and pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching and I wish you all the very best for passing your Amazon interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0098}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Here we go. Thank you for giving me the opportunity to be interviewed for this position with Amazon today. I would describe myself as a detail orientated, safety driven and fast and diligent worker who has a track record in previous roles of being able to quickly solve problems whilst adhering to strict rules and procedures. Over the years, I have worked in various positions where the need to provide exceptional service has been the norm and where people are depending on you to make difficult decisions that keep the business running smoothly. For example, in my last role, we had a situation where our regular supplier had letters down and this had the potential to impact on operations and customer service.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, because I already had a system in place to find a new suitable supplier quickly, it meant there was no downtime.", "answer": "If you hire me as an Amazon transportation specialist, I will ensure the 16 leadership principles are at the core of all my work. I will collaborate closely with internal managers, external contractors and stakeholders to ensure the highest levels of customer service Amazon is renowned for are always maintained. That's a really good answer to that first question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Now you can either pause the video if you want to and take a note of the questions and answers as we work through them together or if you wait, I will soon tell you where you can download my full set of 23 Amazon transportation specialist interview questions and examples including the ones we are covering today. Here's the next question for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to be an Amazon transportation specialist?", "answer": "Now this question is assessing whether you have the motivation and natural abilities to become an effective and highly efficient Amazon transportation specialist. Now it takes certain qualities and attributes to do this job at Amazon. Simply due to the pressure you will be under. You need to be an excellent problem-solver. So here's another great example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0159}
{"question": "Why do you want to be an Amazon transportation specialist?", "answer": "I want to be a transportation specialist for Amazon because the skills and qualities needed in the role are a strong match for my natural abilities and my previous experience. I excel in roles where I have ultimate responsibility for smooth operations and I enjoy the challenge of having to quickly find solutions to problems that have the potential to impact on the performance of an organization. For example, in my last role, I noticed some customers were complaining about the lack of information available to them about their online orders. I carried out some research and I put forward a proposal to my manager about how we could make this type of information readily available to our customers via an online portal. Now once my proposal was implemented, customer service standards and customer retention rates increased significantly. I am a natural problem-solver. I thrive whilst working on the pressure and I enjoy having the responsibility that comes with a safety and operational critical role such as the Amazon transportation specialist. So that's an other really good solid answer and you will notice that what I'm doing in my example responses, I'm giving examples of previous high work performance. And I believe that's really important to do throughout your Amazon interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you, but when you're ready, click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Head through to my website, passmaintoview.com and you can instantly download my full set of 23 Amazon transportation specialist interview questions and examples are including the ones we are working through together today. But here's the next question for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0034}
{"question": "What are the most important skills and qualities needed to be an Amazon transportation specialist?", "answer": "Now this interview question is clearly assessing your knowledge of the job description and one of the best tips I can give you is to make sure you fully familiarize yourself with the job description for an Amazon transportation specialist before you attend your interview. Here's another example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are the most important skills and qualities needed to be an Amazon transportation specialist?", "answer": "To be a competent and effective transportation specialist for Amazon, you need a background in transportation, possess outstanding data driven problem-solving skills, be able to quickly pull and analyze data from various sources and seek ways to make improvements to the transportation and logistical processes that are utilized by Amazon. You need outstanding critical thinking skills be able to identify the root cause of problems whilst working under extreme pressure and have excellent working knowledge of all Amazon transportation tools, apps, online resources and operational procedures. Other essential skills and qualities include being safety-focused on all your work, being able to conduct dynamic risk assessments, possess exceptional communication skills, and have the ability to take ownership of your ongoing professional development. Finally, you must have a good working knowledge of and be able to demonstrate in your work the 16 Amazon leadership principles and be a totally focused collaborator who can work closely with internal and external freight operators, drivers, suppliers and contractors. That's a great example answer to help you prepare for your Amazon interview. Here is the next question. This is a tough one and one that often catches candidates out.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What is Amazon relay and how does it work?", "answer": "So this is another interview question that features often during Amazon transportation specialist interviews. I strongly recommend you familiarize yourself with Amazon relay before you attend your interview. It will form an integral part of your work as a transportation specialist. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0204}
{"question": "What is Amazon relay and how does it work?", "answer": "Amazon relay simplifies great. It is a portal where freight and transportation carriers can quickly and easily access Amazon's network and their technology to grow their business whilst ensuring safety is the priority. For example, if you are a carrier, you can access Amazon relay to book loads at the click of a button. You can easily accept a sign and monitor your workflow seamlessly whilst gaining valuable insights into how your business is performing. Another example is if you are a driver. Amazon relay allows drivers to access an app in real time, which enables them to check in and check out read in yard instructions to reduce driver dwell time, and instantly receive alerts for assigned work and load cancellations. Now the app is universal in the fact that it is supported in 17 languages. So to summarize, Amazon relay is a technological resource and tool set that allows businesses to haul loads effectively for Amazon and it would be an integral part of my job as a transportation specialist. That's a great example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0056}
{"question": "The next question I recommend you prepare for is, why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "So this is another difficult Amazon interview question that comes up often. Make sure you give genuine and valid reasons for wanting to work for this great organization. In my opinion, Amazon is one of the best organizations to work for because they are innovative and forward thinking. They will always be the market leader in my opinion. So my advice is to write down a list of five things that attract you to Amazon before you attend your interview. That will help you to give a really good genuine answer. Here's my own example response to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.02}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "I want to work for Amazon because having used your products and services for many years now, I am a cutely aware of the exceptional levels of customer service you insist on from your employees. Your four principles of customer obsession, passion for invention, commitment to excellence and long-term thinking are very attractive to someone like me who is seeking long-term employment with the same organization. Amazon is so good at what it does because of the people it's employees. As a transportation specialist, I will get to work alongside lots of bright enthusiastic and talented people and I will also have the freedom to express myself in a diverse and inclusive working environment that thrives on change. That's a brilliant answer. That's how I would personally respond to that Amazon transportation specialist interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0143}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "The next question I want to work through with you is tell me about a time when you had a disagreement with your boss. So this is an example of an Amazon leadership principles interview question. So Amazon has 16 leadership principles and one of them is have backbone, disagree and commit. Now this question is assessing your ability to confidently challenge your boss in a professional manner. So here's a brilliant example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0385}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had a disagreement with your boss here we go.", "answer": "In a previous role, I had been communicating with a customer who was not happy with their order. They complained that the online description relating to the product was not accurate. I spoke to my manager to get permission to refund the customer but he refused. So he stated that the customer's reason for wanting the refund was invalid and the product description was actually fine. I disagreed with him and so I put forward my argument in a reason and respectful manner. I explained to my manager that all customers should be valued and we had the opportunity here to improve service standards and retain the customer moving forward simply by giving a refund. I also explained that I felt the product description was not entirely accurate and this same situation could happen again after listening to my argument and the potential benefits to the company my manager agreed for me to issue the refund. We then got together to discuss ways to improve all product descriptions moving forward. Now that is a really good example answer of a situation that I was in where I had a disagreement with my boss and it's a really good response because it shows that I'm putting the success of the organization above everything else. I'm caring for the company but I'm also caring for the customer. Remember one of the leadership principles for Amazon is customer obsession. They always obsess with customers instead of focusing on their competitors. So the next thing to do is please make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video head through to my website. PassmainTV.com and you can instantly download my full set of 23 Amazon Transportation Specialist interview questions and examples are including the ones we covered today during this tutorial. Make sure at the very least you go through to that page because I've also given you some more really important tips for helping you to pass your Amazon interview. Remember Amazon only hires the best so it's really important that you put the preparation time in before you attend your interview. It will definitely be worth it because as I said previously I personally believe that Amazon is one of the greatest companies in the world to work for their fantastic and I really think that you should put the effort in to make sure you stand out during your interview. Okay finally don't forget to subscribe to the channel it is really important. We have a brilliant community here a career vids lots of you are passing your interviews. I can only help you if you are subscribed and by subscribing you will be the first person to be alerted whenever I upload interview tips. Career strategies and I can also help you to negotiate to salary or a pay rise when you are employed. Please do give the video a like it's a simple ask but it really does motivate me if I see people liking the video. It motivates me to create more content for you and also answer questions for you in the comments section below the video and also don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video and it's always great to connect with like minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon transportation specialist interview. Have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0134}
{"question": "If you have a job interview coming up with Amazon, they are going to ask you the question, why Amazon? Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "And in this tutorial, I am going to give you a number of examples that will help you prepare fully for your Amazon interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "So here's the first example answer to the interview question, why Amazon?", "answer": "Here we go. I want to work for Amazon for five reasons. The first reason is Amazon has an impressive track record of achievement over the years. It has constantly been innovative in the products that it creates and how it delivers its goods and services to its customers. I only want to work for an organization that is constantly moving and driving forward. The second reason why I want to work for Amazon is because having personally used Amazon's products and services over the years, they are always created to a very high standard. You are always trying to solve problems that customers might have and that is one of the main reasons why I believe customers are constantly coming back to the organization. The third reason why I want to work for Amazon is because you are clearly obsessed with customers. In everything you do, I understand that you always start with a customer and you then work backwards. And that's a great model for an organization to have and it tells me that Amazon will always be successful. And I want to work in a role where I am constantly pushed and challenged. And that's the fourth reason why I want to work for Amazon is because I want to work for a company where I will be rewarded for helping other people. So within Amazon, I will get to be creative and innovative and come up with different ideas to help the organization to move forward and also to solve problems for customers. And I believe that will be highly rewarding. The final reason why I want to work for Amazon is because of your leadership principles, your 14 leadership principles. I studied them in detail before applying for this position today and I was impressed by them. I believe they are the foundations of why Amazon has always been successful. And if I am successful in applying for this position, I will look forward to implementing all of them into my daily work. So that was a confident and positive answer to that common Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0056}
{"question": "Why Amazon? Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "And in a second, I am going to give you some more example scripted answers you can use in your Amazon interview. But first of all, let me give you a list of good things to mention in your answer to the interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why Amazon?", "answer": "Well, you could say that Amazon has a brilliant track record of success. It is innovative and it is at the cutting edge of product development. You could also say that Amazon always focuses on delivering exceptional customer service and you have first hand experience of using some of their products and services. You could also say that you want to work for Amazon because Amazon is an employer that encourages it start to invent and create. And being a creative person yourself, you find this highly appealing. Or you could say that having studied and learned the Amazon leadership principles, you are impressed with the foundations the company has been built up. So let me now give you some more example answers to the interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0079}
{"question": "Why Amazon?", "answer": "Here's the first one. Answer option one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "I want to work for Amazon for several reasons. The first reason is Amazon is an organization that is constantly pushing the boundaries of innovation. You are always moving forward and I find this appealing because I want to work in an organization where I can be creative and innovative. I want to work for Amazon because the leadership principles you have are the bedrock of success. And if I apply the leadership principles in my work, I will always be successful. Finally, I want to work for Amazon because I will get to work alongside other like-minded professionals who are all seeking to grow, learn, improve and develop. We spend a lot of time at work and I want that time to be put to good use. Now I like that answer to the why Amazon interview question because you are not just giving one reason why you want to work for Amazon. You are giving lots of different reasons and that's the best way to tackle that interview question. Here's my second example answer to the question why Amazon to help you. I want to work for Amazon because having personally used many of your products and services before, you are a company that stands for exceptional customer service and high quality. You genuinely care about your customers and I find this appealing. I also want to work for Amazon because there will be opportunities for me to advance within the organization. I have ambitious career plans and I see myself as a long-term employee of Amazon and someone who will be able to help the organization grow and improve. Finally, I want to work for Amazon because you are never satisfied with what you have achieved. I will feel proud to work for an organization that is always creating new things and that is at the cutting edge of innovation. That is a really good answer. You can decide out of the three answers I have given you which one you want to use, join your Amazon interview when responding to the question why Amazon. Now if you would like to download my full set of Amazon interview questions and answers in a PDF guide, click that link right now that has appeared in the top right hand corner of the video. Head over to more website, passmaintevue.com and you can download my full set of Amazon interview questions and top scoring answers, including the ones I have covered during today within this presentation. Finally, please don't forget to subscribe to the channel. Lots of you are passing your interviews and I don't need to miss out. I have also placed some links to a number of other Amazon interview questions and answers training tutorials in the description below the video. Make sure you check them out. Finally, don't forget to give the video a thumbs up. I very appreciate your support. Thank you very much for watching and wish you all the best for passing your Amazon interview. Have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0058}
{"question": "Why, why the move?", "answer": "Well, my wife's job is moving down south and I'm coming along with her. It's very noble and admirable about you at the same time.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How did you hear about the position open with our company here at RRI?", "answer": "Well, when I thought about the opportunity of changing locations and moving from one physical location to another, I thought about making a career move as well. And I was starting with my main interests and passions. And I love being outside. I love doing outdoor activities. And I love working with people. And I thought if I could use my experience as a teacher, helping people, and my interest in the outdoors together, that would be a good place to start a new career. And when I was looking online, I found RRI's website and that there were positions available in the Jacksonville area, so I thought I would apply. Great. Well, you say you have an interest in outdoor activities. So this would be a great company for you to work at.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0148}
{"question": "That being said, what else do you know about our company?", "answer": "Well, I know you've been around for a long time since the late 1930s. And what really caught my attention the most was the idea that it was started by people who had a passion for the outdoors and found a way to involve others in their experience. I like the idea too that your company is consistently ranked among the top 100 companies to work for by Fortune Magazine. And I thought growing with a company that has that level of success would be a good place to be. Great.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0109}
{"question": "Why do you want this particular position here within our customer service department?", "answer": "Because I want to start in a position that allows me to learn everything about the company from the very basic level of interacting with the customers all the way up throughout the sales process, the marketing process, and the production of goods and services. When I saw the opportunity for customer service, I thought it would align very well with the skill set that I have, and also with some skills that I could bring to the company that might be with me.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Can you tell me a little bit more about these skills that you would transfer from your previous line of work to our department here?", "answer": "Sure. In education, it's all about making the customer or student feel comfortable and helping them grow. I feel that within a company like REI, it's the same philosophy, getting a customer comfortable with the product and helping them grow as they advance in whatever sport they have and we were participating in.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0182}
{"question": "Why do you think that our company should hire you specifically among star pool candidates that are interviewing for this position?", "answer": "Sure. I think one skill set that I have involves my background in education. Teachers are among the highest-stressed professionals in the workplace. REI offers a number of products that help alleviate stress by getting people outdoors. Teachers also have a lot of downtime in the summers. My thinking is that once I learn the ropes and advance it from the company, I'll be able to market the services and products that REI offers specifically to the teaching profession. I have to ask this question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Given that you are making a career change here, especially with finishing a master's degree in education, if a position becomes available in your current field down here in the Jacksonville area, how do you approach being offered this job versus being offered a position in your field?", "answer": "I'm asking that in the now and in the future. Sure. That's a great question. I'm not pursuing further educational opportunities within that profession. I feel like this customer service opportunity, the chance to work and feel that I enjoy as much as teaching, is a place that I could grow into long term.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0175}
{"question": "What I get out of teaching is working with people and helping people become a little bit better than they were when I first met them.", "answer": "That skill translates very well into REI's mission. I don't anticipate leaving a successful career for something I've already done. I feel like this is a natural confluence of my two interests.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0286}
{"question": "Chris, what would you identify as your greatest professional strengths?", "answer": "I think patience is probably my greatest strength. That translates across the careers being able to listen to a student or customer's difficulty and help them overcome that difficulty with patience and compassion is my greatest strength.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Would you consider any weaknesses that you have to be detrimental to the job?", "answer": "I think there's a risk when it comes to compassion. I think people can misinterpret compassion as being easy or willing to roll over. When it's important to understand that compassion is something that is earned and it's interactive and I feel like if I establish clear boundaries with customers, clients, students, they understand that I am understanding, I am patient, I am kind, yet I'm also going to hold the people I interact with to a high standard.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.012}
{"question": "To date, what would you say is your greatest professional achievement?", "answer": "Personally, becoming a teacher, earning a master's degree, those have all been wonderful experiences for me. But the greatest achievement would have to be working with young people and helping them get a little bit better at communicating with the world around them.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Chris, can you tell me about a challenge or a conflict that you've faced in the workplace and how you would deal with it?", "answer": "Sure. Within the education profession, there are challenges every day. You're dealing with hundreds of different personalities and interests and levels of enthusiasm. Being able to engage students with content in an enriching way is part of overcoming a conflict or difficulty. I think building professional relationships is another way to deal with conflicts, understanding where people come from. Prior to teaching, I was involved with a photography company, photographing events like weddings and bar mitzvahs and very, very important events in people's lives. A lot of times, conflicts would arise. So again, just like in teaching, overcoming those conflicts with patients and listening to the client or customer's needs is very important. You are interviewing for a position that is not an entry level position and there is the possibility that those in our company that were overlooked for this position may have some animosity regarding the new hire for this position.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0192}
{"question": "How do you approach this potential challenge here at the workplace?", "answer": "The important thing is to listen to the people around me and understand that I am a newcomer and that they know more about the work environment than I will come in. I think because I have a friendly demeanor and I'm not confrontational when meeting new people that in time will have a chance to earn each other's mutual respect and understand that we both want the same thing, the company to grow and us to grow within the company.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Where do you see yourself in five years specifically within our company?", "answer": "Hopefully I'll be able to develop a market that allows me to interact with people within the teaching profession and grow our brand using that market as a target client base. That's great.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Are you interviewing currently with any other companies and if so, what interests you about those particular companies as well?", "answer": "Since I'm new to the area, I haven't had the opportunity to interview with a wide variety of companies. I have looked at Bass Pro Shops and I'm currently scheduled to interview with them. They have a similar mission and similar goals to REI. It's just that their product line is more specifically tailored than REI's more-deversed offerings. We here at REI, you know, it is being in customer service. There are aspects of your job that are going to be a little less active than I could expect you being in a teaching position where I assume you're on your feet more one-on-one based of base with individuals.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0085}
{"question": "Do you prefer a specific type of work environment? Do you thrive in a variety of work environments and what does this look like?", "answer": "Well, I thrive in a variety of work environments. I wouldn't expect to be sitting in a cubicle interacting with customers unless I'm handling a phone call and that's fine. That's part of the job. But what I would expect is to be actively engaged with the customers who come into the store and helping show them the products that might best suit their needs and introducing them to products that they might not have considered before. So what I would expect to be up moving around and being consistently engaged with a customer or trying to find ways to improve what we offer to our customers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.009}
{"question": "Can you describe a time for me ever that you may have disagreed on a decision that was made for you and staff members at work and how did you deal with this?", "answer": "Sure. Within the field of education, there are new initiatives being rolled out all the time. And sometimes those initiatives get mandated. You have to teach this way this many times a week. And when something like that happens, I think it's important to go back to what you know about your profession or your skill set and be able to provide research that supports why you do what you do. And I think when faced with the difficulty again, it's important to do what the boss says and it's important to also advocate for what might be best for the customer or student. Alright, we're going to move on to some cognitive behavioral questions and basically these questions are designed. They're not necessarily about your past, your experience. They're sort of out of the box questions. And so just do your best at answering them as you go through this.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0255}
{"question": "So if you were an animal, what would you be and why?", "answer": "That's a tough question. I think considering the traits of my dog, if I had to be an animal, I would certainly want to be a domesticated dog. They just have that ability to love unconditionally. They're intensely loyal and they just provide so many benefits to people. That's something I'd like to do in my life as a human too. Great.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0303}
{"question": "The next question, how many tennis balls can you fit into a limousine?", "answer": "Kennis balls in a limousine. Well, I guess to effectively answer that question, I would need some help. I would need to know what type of limousine because if we're talking about a stretch SUV, that's a much larger volume than a smaller limousine.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Are we talking to door four door?", "answer": "I also don't know what's in the limousine already.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Are there people in there or is it empty?", "answer": "Once I had those questions answered, I would have to do some calculations about the size of a tennis ball, how much area or how much volume it takes up, calculate the inside of the limousine, and then make sure the math works out. I could get that answer to you. I just can't do it off the top of my head. Great. Let me ask this final question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Do you have any questions for us?", "answer": "Well, I've mentioned a couple times about being interested in helping grow a market for RII.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "I'm just curious as a new employee or someone starting out on the lower level, how open is upper management hearing the ideas of an employee?", "answer": "We do try to have monthly meetings where we meet with a variety of employees at random. These aren't things that are necessarily scheduled regularly. They're very semi-annual. They're very informal. We do like to hear our employees' opinions about our products especially and about marketing. One thing that we don't necessarily do is the lower level positions that are dealing maybe with collections or the intake and distribution of customer service calls. We don't necessarily talk to that group of employees very often, but I'd be very interested to hear your opinions on that.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0098}
{"question": "Should you be hired for the position and maybe ways that we can do better as well by reaching a larger group of our employees to benefit our company? Okay, and the last question from me, what from your perspective is the best part about working for RII?", "answer": "I think the work atmosphere with our company is very welcoming. And even in my position and somewhat upper management, those that I work for that are above me, they're very good to our employees. And I think because of the treatment of our employees, we retain employment. It's very easy for us to get things done because people want to do their jobs. I have worked myself in positions where I've worked underneath people who are more tyrannical in nature. And it's very difficult to want to do more and go above and beyond what you need to do in those situations. So I believe that that's the number one benefit of working in our particular company is the atmosphere itself. Great. Thank you so much for your time, Kate. I appreciate you so much. Take care.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.021}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself here we go.", "answer": "Thank you for giving me the opportunity to be interviewed for this process assistant role with Amazon today. I read the job description carefully before applying and I already have the skills, qualities and safety attributes to perform competently in the role. I am a diligent, industrious and innovative worker who understands how important customer service is whilst working as a process assistant. Now Amazon has built its business on the 16 leadership principles and I have the experience to apply them in this role. I have worked in several positions where attention to detail skills, accuracy, flexibility and safety were crucial to the successful function of my day-to-day tasks. I am comfortable with daily production goals. I can be relied upon to maintain a clean and safe working environment and I will always manage and direct my team to ensure Amazon achieves its operational objectives. So that's a really good confident answer to that first Amazon process assistant interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0061}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Now you can either pause the video if you want to and take note of the answers. But if you want to wait I will soon tell you where you can download my full set of 21 Amazon process assistant interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are working through together today. Now here's the next question for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "Now in your answer to this next Amazon process assistant interview question. Talk about the positive Amazon workplace culture how you will be able to grow in the position and ultimately build a long-term career with their organisation. So here's another really good answer to help you prepare for your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0189}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon here we go?", "answer": "I want to work for Amazon because you are the best in the world at what you do. I will get to work in a positive environment where everyone has a can do attitude, where everyone supports each other in their duties and where I will be kept constantly busy. Now because Amazon is such an innovative and forward thinking company there will always be new things for me to learn which is important to me in my work. If I am successful I see my long-term future right here with Amazon. I also want to work for Amazon because the pays competitive there will be career growth opportunities and I will be able to save for my future by way of the Amazon pension. And I will also be working in an environment where everyone is striving to achieve great things. So that's another really good answer to help you share your interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you. But when you are ready click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Head through to my website, passmaintv.com and you can download my full set of 21 Amazon process assistant, job interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are working through together today. But here's an next question for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0043}
{"question": "If you saw someone being unsafe at work what would you do?", "answer": "Now one of Amazon's 16 leadership principles is called strive to be the Earth's best employer. And part of that principle is always operating in a safe manner. Now when you are answer demonstrate you are awareness of safety and how important it is to manage it effectively in your role as an Amazon process assistant. And just quickly I will talk more about the 16 leadership principles later on towards the end of this tutorial. They are absolutely crucial to your success in my opinion when you attend your Amazon interview. So here's a great example answer to this next Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0093}
{"question": "If you saw someone being unsafe at work what would you do?", "answer": "Here we go. I would tell them to stop what they were doing straight away. Now one of the 16 Amazon leadership principles is strive to be the Earth's best employer. And that means always carrying out your duties with safety in mind. I would explain what they were doing wrong and what they needed to do to put things right. I would also insist they read the operational safety procedures again that were applicable to their role and the task they were carrying out. I would then reaffirm to all Amazon associates in my team the importance of safety and read out the standard operating procedure. Finally, there may also be the need to update the standard operating procedure relevant to the task that was being carried out unsafely. And if that was the case I would liais with my area manager or safety supervisor to get this actions. So that demonstrates that you understand you need to stop. Get them to stop what they are doing straight away. And also make sure that they are retrain. They read the operational safety procedures again to familiarise themselves with what they should be doing that's relevant to that task.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.005}
{"question": "Can you are also?", "answer": "And I think this is important making reference to the leadership principles in your answer. Here's the next interview question I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are the main responsibilities of an Amazon process assistant?", "answer": "Now my advice is to make sure you read the job description for the Amazon process assistant role before you attend your interview. This is really important because if you are unable to explain the core responsibilities you will have in the role during your interview you are unlikely to be successful. So here's a great example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0161}
{"question": "What are the main responsibilities of an Amazon process assistant here we go?", "answer": "As an Amazon process assistant I would have a multitude of different responsibilities. I would be responsible for delegating duties to team members. Taking control of team meetings, directing and assigning duties in response to operational requirements and liaising with internal and external suppliers. As an Amazon process assistant I would also be required to provide cover for area managers when they were on vacation and sure compliance with standard operating procedures, track associate's work performance and take part in Amazon's operational excellence initiatives. Now other duties and responsibilities include helping with production duties and analyzing the efficiency of daily production goals and workflows, maintaining a clean and safe working environment, reporting injuries straight away to the area manager and providing coaching and training to Amazon associates in respect of their duties and safety compliance responsibilities. That's a really good example answer that shows you have thoroughly read the job description and you understand responsibilities that are relevant to the position of an Amazon process assistant. Here is the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What was the one task you were involved in where it seemed you were meant to fail?", "answer": "Now this is a really difficult interview question and it's more commonly referred to as a behavioral interview question and it's aligned with the leadership principles. Now this next Amazon process assistant interview question is obviously assessing your determination, resilience and your ability to solve challenging problems whilst under pressure. So my advice is think of a specific situation you have been in where against the odds you managed to achieve a successful outcome. So here's a great example answer to help you prepare for your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0222}
{"question": "What was the one task you were involved in where it seemed you were meant to fail?", "answer": "I was working in a previous role, processing and packing orders for customers following a weekend sale. Now we had sold hundreds of products over the weekend and we needed to get them out before 3pm that afternoon. Now part way through the morning are internet crashed which meant I could not access the orders. Now not being deterred I ran across to another business on the site and requested use of their internet to process the orders and also print off the delivery labels. Now once I returned to the site to carry on my duties a team member informed me that we had run out of packing boxes. Now time was now running out. So I asked 2 team members to drive out to 2 separate packaging companies in the local area to buy some replacement boxes. Now I sent 2 people out just in case one of the packaging companies did not have the boxes we needed. Now when they returned an hour later we managed to get all the orders packed and sent out just in time for the 3pm postal deadline. That's a really good answer because it is specific in nature. It gives an actual example but it also shows that you have several challenging problems to deal with but you use your initiative to overcome them to achieve a successful outcome and that's really important. Here's the next Amazon interview question I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0041}
{"question": "How do you handle stress?", "answer": "Now as an Amazon process assistant you will have multiple duties and responsibilities. Therefore it is essential you can handle the stress and pressure that will inevitably come with the make sure you give a confident answer that shows you can prioritize and plan your work effectively because when you do prioritize and plan your work you can then handle the stress that comes with the role. So here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0132}
{"question": "How do you handle stress here we go?", "answer": "I handle stress by first and foremost prioritizing my working day in advance. I determine which tasks need my attention, what the likely obstacles are and how I can potentially overcome them. Prioritizing tasks and thinking ahead helps to minimize stress. Now if you understand that stress and pressure are part of your working day you can remain calm and composed and then deal with challenging situations as and when they arise much easier. Finally to handle stress and pressure I maintain a healthy lifestyle outside of work. I attend the gym several times a week which helps me keep a positive mindset and strong concentration levels.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "That's a really good answer to that common Amazon process assistant interview question how do you handle stress?", "answer": "Here is the next question tell me about a time when you helped develop the career of a team member. Now part of your role as an Amazon process assistant will be to help develop team members. Now Amazon employees are selfless in their approach to supporting motivating and encouraging people in their teams to achieve great things. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you helped develop the career of a team member here we go.", "answer": "In a previous role a co-worker was trying for an internal promotion. They asked if they could shadow me for a week to gain an insight into my daily tasks and how I approached my responsibilities. Now they needed to develop skills in certain areas to meet the essential criteria of the role they were applying for so I agreed to help them. Now to begin with I sat down and determined what they wanted to learn and achieve over the week they were shadowing me. We drew up a list of the top 10 things they wanted to learn before commencing work. Now I showed them how I prioritized daily tasks based on the company's commercial objectives and what I did to double check everything was completed to the right standard. Now where possible I asked them to perform some of my duties so they gained real hands-on experience and at the end of the week we had worked through everything that was on the list and they thanked me for my assistance. Now when my colleague went to interview they successfully gained a promotion they wanted which was great news. So that demonstrates that you are a selfless employee and you also plan what you wanted to teach the person during the week they were shadowing you so it's a really good answer. Now in a second I'm going to give you another video right here on YouTube that I strongly strongly recommend you watch because it will really help you to pass your process assistant interview. But you can now click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. You can head through to my website passmaintovue.com and you can download my full set of 21 Amazon process assistant job interview questions and top scoring example answers including the ones we have worked through together today. Now this guide comes as a PDF guide so you can literally have it within your inbox within two minutes from now and it's going to make a big difference to your preparation. Make sure you check that out.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.014}
{"question": "Now what about that video I recommend you watch?", "answer": "This is the video and there is a link right there at the top of this video that if you click that it will take you through to another video right here on YouTube where I talked to you about the importance of the Amazon leadership principles. It's my opinion that you will not pass your interview for Amazon as a process assistant unless you learn and understand the 16 Amazon leadership principles. They are absolutely crucial to all employees who work at Amazon in my opinion. Amazon is one of the greatest companies in the world. And primarily that is because they have the 16 leadership principles that they want everybody to demonstrate in their work. Make sure you check that out. Finally, again don't forget to subscribe to the channel. It's really important. I want to help you not just pass every job into view you ever attend but also help you progress throughout your career. I can only do that if you are subscribed please also give the video a like. That is all I ask. It just tells me that you find these tutorials useful and also don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video and it's always really good to connect with light-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon process assistant job interview have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0078}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a mistake. Tell me about a time you had a conflict with a coworker and tell me about a time when you disagreeing with your boss.", "answer": "Now behavioral interview questions are designed to quickly determine whether or not you have the experience to handle difficult situations you will likely encounter in the workplace. Now the idea is that if you have already experienced the situation being assessed, you will be able to meet the demands of the job role and therefore require less training and supervision in the position. Now that is why it is so important when answering behavioral interview questions you give a specific situation you have been in based on the question being asked.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.011}
{"question": "However, if this is your first ever job interview and you have no previous experience of the situation being assessed, make sure you answer the question by telling the hiring manager what you would do in the situation to achieve a successful outcome.", "answer": "Okay, let me now quickly tell you what the star method is and how to use it while answering behavioral interview questions. Now the star method stands for situation task action and result. Now when answering behavioral interview questions, start your answer by outlining the situation you were faced with. Next, tell the hiring manager the task that need you doing, then give details in depth details about the action you took to complete the task and then finally finish your answer with the results following your actions. Okay, let me now show you how to answer behavioral interview questions in a live job interview and I will then give you the scripts to write down here we go. Richard tell me about a time you made him stake. In my last job, I was taking a customer's order over the telephone. It was my task to pay attention to the customer and deliver excellent service.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, in my hastiness to deal with the customer quickly, I failed to listen fully to their requested order and when I dispatched their goods, it was incomplete.", "answer": "This was a foolish mistake and as soon as I realized, I contacted the customer, apologized and sent out the correct items along with an apology note and a 10% discount off their next order. Now to make sure I never made the same mistake again, I wrote down all customer orders on a sheet of paper and double check them with the customer to make sure they were correct.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you disagreed with your boss.", "answer": "I was in a team meeting with my boss discussing the redesign of our company's website. My boss wanted to use an expensive local contract for the work but I disagreed with their choice. It was my task to explain to my boss why I disagreed in a professional manner. I explained to my boss that the contract was expensive and after reading reviews from previous clients, I felt there were better alternatives. I suggested we use an online contractor from the website at work.com where we could choose one with better reviews and who would be more cost effective helping save the company money. Now after considering my alternative option, my manager went ahead and hired a contractor from upwork.com who delivered a great design at half the price. Okay next question, tell me about a time you delivered excellent customer service. In a previous job, I was helping an elderly customer on the telephone. They wanted to place an order from our website but they had concerns about security. It was my task to be patient with a customer reassure them and walk them through the online payment process. I listened patiently to the customer's concerns, asked them questions and taught them clearly through every step of the ordering process, making sure they fully understood everything I was saying. Now although the call took much longer than expected, the customer successfully placed their order and they thanked me for being patient and reassuring them throughout the process.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had to work and to pressure.", "answer": "I was working on several important tasks in my last job when my manager asked for a volunteer to cover the duties of a coworker who had to take a leave of absence due to a family emergency. I volunteered to do their work. It was my task to reassess my current workload in addition to my coworkers duties to ensure everything was completed on time. I created a list of all tasks I was now responsible for and collocoded them in order of priority. Red tasks required my immediate attention. Blue tasks came second and green tasks could be left for the end of the working day. I then estimated the time it would take to complete each task blocked out distractions and started work. By prioritising my workload against the company's goals and working methodically and efficiently, I completed all tasks to the required standard and on time. There's four top scoring, powerful answers to difficult behavioral interview questions. In a second, I'm going to give you the scripts to write down. I will put up live on the screen, the exact answers I just gave in that job interview and you can pause the video and write them down and then use them when preparing for your own interview. If you don't want to do any of that and you simply want to download the answers, you can click that link at any time. Okay, here's my top scoring answers. I just gave in that interview here we go. Okay, so let's start working through those exact answers. I just gave in that interview to the behavioral interview questions. All these answers use the star method of situation, task action and result. So the first behavioral interview question was, tell me about a time you made a mistake. Lots of people respond to this question by saying they never made a mistake because they are a perfectionist. That is not the way to answer this difficult question. Here's the exact response I gave.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0058}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a mistake.", "answer": "In my last job, I was taking a customer's order over the telephone. It was my task to pay attention and deliver excellent customer service.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, in my hastiness to deal with the customer quickly, I failed to listen fully to their requested order.", "answer": "And when I dispatched the goods, it was incomplete. Now this was a foolish mistake. And as soon as I realised, I contacted the customer, apologized, and sent out the correct items along with an apology note and they discount off their next order. To make sure I never made the same mistake again, I wrote down all orders on a sheet of paper and double checked them with the customer to ensure they were correct. That is a really good answer you are using the star method, situation, task action and result. You are giving a situation where you made a mistake, you are recognizing the mistake, apologizing and then taking immediate steps to put things right. And then more importantly, at the end, you are saying you learned from the situation. So it's a really good answer to that tough behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0068}
{"question": "Don't forget, you can pause the video and write down the answers if you want to, or at the end, I will tell you where you can download all of the answers in a PDF document.", "answer": "Meaning you can have everything in your inbox within two minutes from now. Here is the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you disagreed with your boss.", "answer": "Here is the answer. I just gave that uses a star method. I was in a team meeting with my boss discussing the redesign of the company's website. My boss wanted to use an expensive local contractor for the work, but I disagreed with their choice. It was my task to explain why I disagreed in a professional manner. I explained to my boss that the contractor was expensive and after reading reviews from previous clients, I felt there were better alternatives. I suggested we use an online contractor from the website upwork.com where we could choose one with better reviews and who would be more cost-effective helping save the company money. Now, after considering my alternative option, my manager went ahead and hired an online contractor from upwork and created a brilliant website for the company at half the price. That is a really good answer again. The use is a star method of situation, task action and result. Lots of people respond to that tough behavioural interview question by saying they would never disagree with their boss because their boss is the person who is in charge.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, this question is assessing your confidence and communication skills to see whether you would disagree if you think there's a better alternative that will help the company.", "answer": "That is a great answer. The next behavioural interview question I had to answer in that live job interview was tell me about a time you delivered excellent customer service. This question comes up all the time during job interviews.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget to give a specific situation you have been in.", "answer": "Or if it's your first job interview, tell them what you would do to deliver excellent customer service. Here is the exact answer I gave that uses a star method. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you delivered excellent customer service.", "answer": "I was helping an elderly customer on the telephone. They wanted to place an order from our website, but had concerns about security. It was my task to be patient with the customer, reassure them and walk them through the payment process. I listened to their concerns, asked questions, and talked them through every step of the ordering process, making sure they fully understood everything I was saying. Although the call took much longer than expected, the customer successfully placed the order and they thanked me for being patient and reassuring them while assisting them placed their order. The really good answer is shows that you go above and beyond to deliver excellent customer service. Again, you are using that brilliant technique, the star method of situation, task, action and result. It will help you get higher scores in your job interview because it is recognized by all hiring managers. Now the next behavioral interview question I had to answer was tell me about a time you had to work under pressure. Again, this is one of the more common behavioral interview questions. Here is the exact answer I gave. I was working on several important tasks in my last job when my manager asked for a volunteer to cover the duties of a coworker who had to take a leave of absence due to a family emergency. Although I was busy, I volunteered to do their work. It was my task to reassess my current workload in addition to my coworkers to ensure everything was completed on time. I created a list of all tasks I was now responsible for and color coded them in order of priority. Red tasks required my immediate attention. Blue tasks came second and green tasks could be left for the end of the working day. I then assessed the time it would take to complete each task. Blocked out distractions and started work. By prioritizing my workload against the company's goals and working methodically and efficiently, I completed all tasks to the required standard and on time. That's a great answer. I like that response because at the beginning you are saying, although you are really busy, you volunteered to do the work of your coworker as well as your own. It shows that you are a team player. It's a really good answer to that tough behavioral interview question that uses a star method again situation task action and result. Now the next thing to do is click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintevue.com and you can instantly download. These answers I just gave these slides plus 50 brilliant quick answers to tough interview questions. That guide includes more brilliant responses to common behavioral interview questions. Make sure you check out that link download the guide. It will make a huge difference to your performance at every job interview you ever attend. It will save you lots of time when preparing for your interview, so make sure you check it out and download it. Also, don't forget to hit the subscribe button. Thousands of you are passing your job interviews. I can only help you if you are subscribed. Please hit the like button. It's a small favour to ask you, but if you like the videos, it does motivate me to create more great free content for you. Thank you very much. And don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. Thank you very much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your job interview. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0064}
{"question": "But the question states which of these inquiries would you respond to first?", "answer": "Now this is a difficult question to answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, if you understand those Leadership Principles, you will know which one the you need to respond to first.", "answer": "So let's take a look at them and then I will get you to answer this question by putting your response in the comment section below the video. So let's have a look. The first one is called an urgent, unfulfilled audit. You start work and these five inquiries are in your email inbox. And this one says, it's from a customer. I placed an order for a laptop two weeks ago and it still hasn't been delivered. This is urgent. I need it for work. Please assist ASAP. Now the second customer inquiry is called a product inquiry. So the customer has said to you, hi, I am interested in buying a laptop. But I need help comparing different models.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.024}
{"question": "Can you provide detailed specifications for laptops, A, B and C?", "answer": "The next customer inquiry is a return and refund request. I received a damaged phone case. I would like to return it and get a refund. Please guide me through the return process. The fourth customer inquiry is called Account Access Issue. I can't access my account. It says my password is incorrect. But I haven't changed it. Please help me regain access to my account. And the fifth customer inquiry that you have to deal with is called feedback and suggestion. And it says, I have some feedback and suggestions about your website's user interface.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0101}
{"question": "Is there a way I can share my thoughts with the development team?", "answer": "Okay, so those are the five customer inquiries you have to deal with.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0769}
{"question": "But the question is, which of those inquiries would you respond to first? Would you respond to A, the urgent unfulfilled order? B, that product inquiry, C, the return and refund request, D, that account access issue, or the feedback and suggestion?", "answer": "So please tell me which answer option you would respond to first, A, B, C, D, or E.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0556}
{"question": "Tell me in the comments section below the video.", "answer": "I will come on a each day and mark your answers for you. You've got 10 seconds to put your answer in the comment section below the video. Here we go. Okay, well done. And don't forget, the 16 Amazon leadership principles, customer obsession. Question number two, try another answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "This time, question two is, which of the inquiries would you respond to last? B, C, D, or E? Tell me your answer in the comment section below the video.", "answer": "Here's your 10 second timer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget, customer obsession is one of the leadership principles and you have to act decisively.", "answer": "Okay, let's now move on to a different type of Amazon assessment test, practice question. This is called a work style assessment test. Now, this test, assesses that your work style is in line with Amazon's leadership principles. So again, you can see why it is so important that you learn, understand and demonstrate these leadership principles in your work. So work style assessment test question number three. Now we are given a statement. My emphasis on making customers feel valued and delivering excellent service outweighs my focus on outperforming competitors. And we are given some options.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0303}
{"question": "Do we a strongly agree with that statement?", "answer": "Be agree with it. See, neither agree or disagree. D disagree or E strongly disagree. Now, I would choose strongly agree.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why would I choose that answer?", "answer": "I would choose it because of the customer obsession leadership principle, which says, start with a customer earn their trust and obsess over their needs. So that's exactly how I would answer that question. And again, you can see why it is so important to learn and understand those leadership principles before you undertake your Amazon assessment test. Because you're making the customer feel valued and you are delivering excellent service. And that is more important to you than your focus on outperforming competitors. The reason being, if you deliver brilliant outstanding service, customers will come back to you time and time again and you will by default beat your competitors. So now it's your turn to try some. Work style assessment test question number four. Whenever I have an idea during a team meeting, I will either a, put forward my idea or as soon as possible without interrupting others. B, wait until the end of the meeting and then put forward my idea. C, listen to others contributions first before deciding whether my idea is worthy. D, wait for my manager to give me the opportunity to put forward my idea and E, wait until the meeting is over and then send my idea to my manager by email. Please put your answer, ABC, D, or E in the comments section below the video and I will market for you. Here is your 10 second timer. Okay, brilliant. Well done and don't forget to focus on those leadership principles. Is another one for you to try. Work style assessment test question number five. You propose an idea during a team meeting, but your manager explains to you why it will not work.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0104}
{"question": "What do you do?", "answer": "A, apologise for putting forward a bad idea and don't contribute any further. B, decide that this job isn't for you and start to look for a new job elsewhere where your ideas will be valued. C, accept your manager is right, learn from the experience and think of alternative ideas to contribute to the team. D, wait until the meeting is finished before confronting your manager about why you believe your idea will work. Please put your answer in the comments section below the video for marking.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Is it ABC or D that you would do based on that statement?", "answer": "Here's your timer. Brilliant. Well done. You are making fantastic progress. Let's try two more. Work style assessment test question number six. Now your manager gives you the opportunity to attend a training course that will develop a new skill, but you are very busy with lots of tasks.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What do you do?", "answer": "A, politely decline the offer of the course stating you are too busy to attend. B, accept the offer of the training course and then find the time to study and complete all your tasks simultaneously. See, tell your manager you are very busy but you would love to attend the course later in the year when you have more time or D, tell your manager you are too busy to attend, but you would be happy if they offer the course to one of your co-workers so it isn't wasted. Put your answer in the comments section below the video.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0097}
{"question": "Don't forget those Amazon leadership principles.", "answer": "Here is your 10 second timer. ABC or D in the comments section below please. Thanks. And try one more before we move on to some different test questions. This is Work style assessment test question seven. You notice one of your co-workers keeps making errors in their work and they are often late completing tasks.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What would you do?", "answer": "A. For the situation you are not a manager and therefore this is none of your business. B, inform your manager of your co-workers under performance so they can deal with the situation. C, tell other people in your team about your co-workers under performance so you can collectively put pressure on them to improve. D, speak to your co-worker privately to explain your concerns and tell them what they need to do to put things right and then offer to support them in their work. Your answer, ABC or D in the comments section below the video for marking. Thank you very much. Here is your 10 second timer. Here we go. So again you can see that those people who learn those leadership principles read and learn them are more likely far more likely to pass their Amazon online assessment test. Let's now try a slightly different type of work style Amazon practice test question. This is test question number eight. So it says read the two statements below one and two and then choose the one statement that best applies to you. Let's have a look at it. Statement number one says I will not take calculated risks when making important decisions and statement number two is I see waste elimination is an important part of budget control and your answer options are statement one or statement two.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0169}
{"question": "So which of those statements one or two best applies for you? Now I would choose statement two why?", "answer": "Well because of the leadership principles.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget through Galatys states you achieve more with fewer resources and you foster resourcefulness and statement two says I see waste elimination is an important part of budget control.", "answer": "So that statement shows that you are applying the leadership principle of frugality. Now statement number one says I will not take calculated risks when making important decisions but that goes against the leadership principle of bias for action which is value speed take calculated risks but that says not take calculated risks. So that one is not applicable to me because I want to demonstrate those leadership principles again you can see why it is so imperative you learn and understand those leadership principles take calculated risks. Right now it's time for you to try some work style assessment test question number nine. Read the two statements below one and two and choose the one statement the best applies for you. Statement one rules and regulations at work are there to be broken. Statement number two I obsess over the needs of customers which one would you choose a statement one or b statement two please put your answer in the comment section below to video for marking for question nine is your 10 second timer. Well done let's now try work style assessment test question number ten. Read the two statements below one and two and choose the one statement the best applies to you statement one quantity is more important than quality statement two we should be led by customer input answer option a statement one or statement two which one of those best applies to you please put your answer in the comment section below the video.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0119}
{"question": "Don't forget the leadership principles.", "answer": "He's your 10 second timer. Tremendous well done I'm really proud that you are still practicing these questions. They're definitely going to help you pass your Amazon assessment test. Let's now take a look at chart data interpretation test. So this type of practice test assesses your ability to use accurate information and data to solve challenging problems. So we are given a chart. Now this chart is called online daily orders for a three week period at a specific company.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0235}
{"question": "And question 11 states what was the total number of online orders for that three week period?", "answer": "So the chart we have the weeks one two and three across the top on the left we have the days. Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday and Sunday at the bottom we have the total for each week.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0256}
{"question": "So we after then decide what was the total number of online orders for that three week period? Is it a? 2,196 orders be? 2,916c? 1,946d? 1,216 orders or e none of the above?", "answer": "Put your answer to question 11 in the comment section below the video. I'll give you 12 seconds to answer this question and you can use a calculator if you want to or the calculator on your smartphone to work out this answer to this question 11. He's your time. Brilliant. Well done try another one. So this is the same chart.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0156}
{"question": "But question 12 is how many more orders were there on Monday compared to Sunday across the three week period? Is it a? 2,196b? 2,916c? 93d? 119 or e none of the above?", "answer": "So put your answer to question 12 in the comment section below the video for marking.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0625}
{"question": "So the question again is how many more orders were there on Monday compared to Sunday across the three week period?", "answer": "Here's your 12 second timer. Fantastic. Well done. You can see how important it is to practice under time conditions. By the way, if you need more time to answer any of these questions, just pause the video is important. You get the answer correct.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Question 13, which day of the week had the most orders across that three week period? Is it a? Monday, b, Tuesday, c Wednesday? D Thursday or e none of the above?", "answer": "Please put your answer in the comment section below the video. Now you should be able to do this just by analyzing the data and numbers on the page. Try doing it without a calculator.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Have a look at each day and see what which one you think has the most orders across the three week period?", "answer": "Here's your 12 second timer. Brilliant. Well done. You are making tremendous progress. Let's now take a look at a different chart. Question 14, the following chart shows the number of five star reviews received by a company in one week.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What is the average daily number of five star reviews?", "answer": "So across the left we have the number of five star reviews received by the company. And across the bottom we have the day of the week. So we have Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday, Friday, Saturday and Sunday.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0526}
{"question": "Okay, how do we calculate the answer?", "answer": "We'll step one at the total number of reviews for the week. So we have 100 there, 60 on Tuesday, 40 on Wednesday, 100 on Thursday, we have 60 on Friday, we have 20 on Saturday and 40 on Sunday. We had all of those together and that equals 420 but we need to know the average daily number of five star reviews. Well to work out the average we follow step two which is divide the total number of reviews for 120 by the number of days seven and then we get the average. So the answer is 420 divided by seven and the answer there would be 60. So now it's your turn to try some of these test questions. Question 15. Of our Amazon practice test questions. The following chart shows the number of orders a company processes per day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0207}
{"question": "What is the average daily number of orders processed?", "answer": "So across the left the number of orders across the bottom the day of the week. So tell me your answer in the comment section below the video. Feel free to use a calculator. Now I'm going to give you 15 seconds. If you can do this in 15 seconds you are doing brilliant. But don't forget pause the video if you need more time here's your timer. Tremendous well done. Let's now try some numerical reasoning practice test questions that will help you prepare for your Amazon assessment test. So this test assesses your ability to use basic calculations in your daily work duties. Question 16. Mary has $100 to spend at the shops.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0252}
{"question": "If she spends $7 on a drink $5 on chocolate $37 on a dress and $38 on a pair of shoes, how much does she have left? Is it a $17? B $15?", "answer": "See $13 or D nothing.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How do we calculate this?", "answer": "Well here's what we do. Step one. Simply add together all the items purchased by Mary. So that would be $7 $5. $37 and $38. And that equals 87. That's how much she has spent. And in step two simply deduct subtract what she has left from a total amount. $100 she had to spend at the shops minus 87 will give us the answer of C. So now it's your turn to try some of these. It will help you prepare for your Amazon assessment test. Question 17. Jonathan goes shopping and spends $42 on a pair of trousers. $57 on a pair of shoes. $16 on a shirt. And $29 on food.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0171}
{"question": "How much change will he have left from $145?", "answer": "A $1. B $4. C $11. D nothing. Put your answer in the comment section below the video for marking. Here's your timer. Well done. You are making fantastic progress.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget very soon.", "answer": "I'm going to tell you where you can get more free practice tests to help you pass your Amazon assessment test. Question 18. A family have $1,500 to spend on a holiday.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "If they spend $350 on flights, $370 on a hotel, and $220 on a higher car, how much spending money will they have left?", "answer": "A $660. B $750. C $560. D $650. Please put your answer in the comment section below the video for marking. Here's your timer. Well done. Question number 19. Clive. There's Clive. Travels to work five days a week in his car.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "If he's journey to work is 22 kilometers, how many kilometers will he cover in three weeks?", "answer": "A $310. B $101. C $770. D $330. Please put your answer in the comment section below the video for marking. Here is your 12 second timer. Fantastic. Well done. Question number 20. Mario gets a taxi to work four days a week. Each day it costs him $17.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How much will he have spent on taxes in eight weeks? Is it a?", "answer": "$870. B $952. C $588. Or D $544. Please put your answer in the comment section below the video. Here is your 12 second timer. Well done. Tramendous work. Now the next thing to do, if you want to accelerate your learning even further and try more, practice Amazon assessment test questions, is click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website how to become.com and you can instantly get access to more free Amazon assessment test questions. This is a brilliant resource. It will help improve your scores during the real Amazon assessment test. Make sure you check out that link. Also don't forget to give the video a thumbs up. Hit that like button. It really does motivate me to create more great content for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0071}
{"question": "Don't forget to hit the subscribe button.", "answer": "I am here to help you pass every job interview and assessment test you ever undertake. I can only do those things if you are subscribed. Also please consider connecting with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always a pleasure and an honour to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon assessment test have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0119}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Here we go. First of all, thank you for giving me the opportunity to be interviewed for this engineer position with your organization today. My name is Richard and after graduating from University with a degree in engineering. I went on to work at several companies where I was required to solve technical problems, work on complex engineering projects and take ideas from the initial engineering design stage through to completion. I am industrial, a decisive problem solver. I operate with creativity and innovation and possess excellent interpersonal and communication skills that are a benefit to the engineering team I am a part of. I have a track record of achievement as an engineer. In my previous role, I was praised for my knowledge of technical and regulatory documents and my ability to communicate complex engineering ideas and solutions in a simple and easy to understand way to non-technical individuals. If you hire me, I will carry out my duties diligently, demonstrate excellent attention to detail skills and support the senior management team in their engineering goals. That is a brilliant answer to that first engineer interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Now, you can either pause this video if you want to and write down the answers as we work through them together or if you wait, I will soon tell you where you can instantly download my full set of 20 engineer interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are covering today during this tutorial. Here is the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to be an engineer?", "answer": "Now, this next interview question is assessing your motivations for working as an engineer. The interviewer wants to hear how passionate you are about your career choice and also what drives you to succeed. Tip number two, talk about how you get to work on difficult challenges as an engineer and also make improvements to people's lives. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to be an engineer?", "answer": "I want to be an engineer because it is a job that I'm very passionate about. I am naturally a curious and inquisitive person who enjoys difficult challenges and I enjoy working alongside other technically minded individuals who are working towards a common goal or objective. I also want to be an engineer because I get the opportunity to improve people's lives. I can innovate and I enjoy the elevated trust that comes with the position. Finally, I want to be an engineer because of the increased earning potential. Now, whilst financial gain is not a major motivator for me, I do want to job that enables me to provide a stable life for my family and where I get rewarded fairly for the hard work I undertake. That is another brilliant answer and it will demonstrate passion and motivation for your career choice as an engineer and it also helps you to put across really strong communication skills and you need those as an engineer. Now, don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you but when you're ready, you can click that link that has appeared in the top right hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, past my interview.com and you can instantly download a copy of these slides in the answers in addition to my 20 engineering interview questions and top scoring answers in a PDF guide. But here's an next question for you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a time you demonstrated leadership skills at work.", "answer": "So engineers, as you know, are leaders. A name a step up, take the lead and speak out when things can be improved. Tip number two, give a specific situation where you took the lead or even spoke out to ensure an engineering project was completed to a high standard. So here's my own example answer to assist you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.05}
{"question": "Describe a time you demonstrated leadership skills at work.", "answer": "Here we go. I was in a team meeting with a group of engineers and stakeholders discussing an engineering project we were responsible for. Now several engineers from a different department suggested we could cut corners and save money during the project by using a non-standard production part. I immediately intervened and explained the dangers this idea posed. I explained that we had a contractual obligation to deliver the engineering project as per the initial brief and using the non-standard part would go against the contract. I also explained there were serious safety concerns about the part because he had not undergone rigorous testing and on that basis I would not support the idea. Everyone else in the meeting then agreed we should not explore the idea further. And I was pleased I took the lead and intervened for the project safety. That's a really good answer. It's a clever answer because as you know as engineers you need to be safe. It's a top priority and you are demonstrating that in your answer and you are also demonstrating you have the confidence to take the lead and speak out when something is not right. It's a really good answer and that question comes up all the time during engineer interviews. So here's the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.009}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "This is a difficult one. Tip number one give several strengths that demonstrate your competence as an engineer. I'm also your ability to add value to their organization. Tip number two, only give one weakness but make sure the weakness is not a match for anything that is listed on the job description. So here's my top scoring answer to help you partial interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0152}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "My strengths include my up-to-date technical and compliance knowledge that's relevant to my area of engineering. I am passionate about research, maintaining competence and learning what is relevant in this industry so my skills are always useful to my employer. Other strengths include my communication skills, my ability to explain technical ideas and concepts to everyone regardless of their level of knowledge and my critical thinking skills which enable me to solve difficult problems and challenges. I am also not afraid to speak up if I think something can be done in an improved or more efficient way. My enthusiasm, drive and positivity have always been welcomed in every engineering team I have been a part of. In terms of my weakness I sometimes find it hard letting go of engineering projects I am working on. I keep checking things before signing them off and whilst this is good for the safety of a project I need to learn to let the project go once complete and then move on to the next one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0056}
{"question": "However I am mindful of my weakness and I am taking steps to improve in this area.", "answer": "So that's a really good answer to that common engineer interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0769}
{"question": "What are your strengths and weaknesses?", "answer": "Let's now move on to the next question. By the way I really do hope you are enjoying this tutorial.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget to subscribe and please do give the video a like.", "answer": "Thank you so much.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.25}
{"question": "How would you respond if a superior kept asking you to redo your work as an engineer?", "answer": "This isn't another common question that comes up during engineering interviews tip number one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "So this question is being asked to assess your temperament? How do you respond are you defensive? Do you refuse to do it? Are you argumentative or are you a team player?", "answer": "So in your answer demonstrate your ability to remain calm, ask relevant questions and do all you can to deliver the engineering work requested. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0312}
{"question": "How would you respond if a superior kept asking you to redo your work as an engineer?", "answer": "Here we go. I would ask my superior questions to determine the engineering work they wanted from me and exactly how it should be delivered. Now the more questions I ask, the more information it gives me which in turn helps me deliver everything to exacting standards. Now if ever I am asked to redo my work. I am positive, supportive and remember that I am here to carry out my tasks as an engineer based on the organization's goals because I'm a team player. Having to redo my work is not a problem providing what I am being asked to do is safe, compliant and achievable. That's a really good mature answer and it shows that you are a collaborator, your team player who puts the needs of the organization first. Here's an question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why should we hire you as an engineer?", "answer": "Now this is one of the most common engineer interview questions that needs a confident and positive answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't be afraid to sell yourself.", "answer": "You know, big yourself up, talk about your achievements in your answer. Remember, they will ask this question to all engineers and they will pick the candidate who can give them the most value in the position. So when you're answered, talk about your track record of success, your problem solving capabilities and your ability to adapt to the changing needs of an engineering project. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.029}
{"question": "Why should we hire you as an engineer?", "answer": "You should hire me because I am a highly skilled and experienced engineer with a strong track record of success. In my current role, I have been entrusted with challenging engineering projects and I have consistently delivered high quality work on time and within budget. My qualifications have given me a solid foundation in the principles and theories of engineering. In addition, I have gained valuable hands-on experience through internships and projects and I'm always looking for ways to continue learning and growing as an engineer. I am a strong problem solver with excellent attention to detail and the ability to work effectively in a team. I am confident that my technical expertise and ability to adapt to changing needs and requirements would make me a valuable asset to your company. I am excited about this role and I hope I get to contribute to the success of your company. That's a great answer. I have a really strong answer that will put you ahead of the competition at your engineer interview. The next thing to do is to make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, passmaintoview.com and you can instantly download these slides and an additional 20 engineering interview questions and top scoring answers in a PDF guide. Fantastic resource. Make sure you head through to that website because there are also some additional tips on there that will help you be the standout candidate at your engineer interview. Also, please make sure you subscribe. Literally thousands of you are passing your job interviews as I said at the start of this tutorial. If you have any questions, put them in the comment section below the video. I will be more than happy to answer them. I personally answer all questions myself every day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget to give the video a like.", "answer": "That does motivate me to create more content. I'm also connected with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always a pleasure to connect with like minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your engineer interview. Have a fantastic day. Thank you guys.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0299}
{"question": "Are passing your job interviews at the first attempt, I can only help you if you are subscribed and please give the video a like, give it a thumbs up because that motivates me to create more content for you.", "answer": "Thank you very much indeed.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Okay, the first section of this training tutorial is what are competency-based interview questions?", "answer": "Well, competency-based interview questions assess how you have dealt with or how you would deal with common workplace situations. So competency-interview often start with Eva, tell me about a time when you describe a situation when you or given example of when you. So example competency-based interview questions are tell me about a time where you handled conflict in the workplace. So if the hiring manager starts off one of the interview questions as tell me about a time you know you are being asked a competency-based interview question. Another common competency-based interview question is describe a time when you are style of communication improved a situation. That is a really difficult interview questions to answer. Very soon I will give you the perfect response. Another example of a competency-based interview question is tell me about a time when you achieved success even when the odds were stacked against you. So now that we understand what competency-based interview questions are, let's take a look at some example answers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0284}
{"question": "Don't forget we need to give specific situations we have previously been in to prove to the hiring manager that we already have what it takes to excel in the position.", "answer": "So the first competency-based interview question I want to give you an answer to is tell me about a time you handled conflict in the workplace. Here's my top scoring answer to help you pass your interview. In my last job two colleagues argued over the best way to complete a project. Now I could detect the conflict was impacting their progress. So I offered to mediate and find a resolution. I got together with them in private and asked them to outline their project brief and the main cause of the conflict. I encouraged them both to focus on the project goal and write down a list of how they could achieve it in the fastest and most efficient way possible. Now when they brought their collective ideas together in writing they could see the best way to achieve the project goal. They then went on to successfully complete the project without further issue. Getting them to focus on the project objective, not their personal agendas, helped them gain clarity and overcome the conflict. That's a really good example answer to that common but difficult competency-based interview question tell me about a time you handled conflict in the workplace. You are being a responsible and mature employee and you are facilitating a resolution to the conflict of two of your coworkers. It's a fantastic answer. Let's now move on to competency-based interview question number two. This one comes up all the time during job interviews. It's really difficult to answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0077}
{"question": "Describe a time when you're style of communication improved a situation.", "answer": "Here's my top scoring example answer to help you. I was in a team meeting discussing the plan for a project we were tasked with completing for a valued client. Now two team members suggested that we use a sub-standard product part for the project that was cheaper and would enable us to save project costs. They argued the client would never know about the sub-standard product part and we would increase the project's profit margin. I was opposed to this idea based on safety and moral grounds. When I objected however they said I was being unreasonable. I then changed my communication style to a firmer, more determined at tone. I explained there was a danger to the project safety and morally we had a duty to deliver to the client precisely what they had paid for. After I changed my tone of communication they agreed to disband their idea which was the right decision. That's a really good example answer to that difficult competency based interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Describe a time when you're style of communication improved a situation.", "answer": "It also demonstrates that you have really good values. Now please don't go anywhere because I still have more interview questions and answers to give you but when you're ready you can click that link that has appeared in the top right-hand corner of the video head through to my website pacmaintoview.com and you can instantly download these slides plus my full set of 26 great answers to difficult competency based interview questions. It comes in a PDF guide you can have it in your inbox literally within two minutes from now. Here is the next competency based interview question I recommend you prepare for and that is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you achieved success even when the odds were stacked against you.", "answer": "Here's my top scoring response to assist you. I worked on a week long project with three team members in my last job. Our manager gave us a responsibility of undertaking an overhaul of the company's website blog and information pages. We allocated different blog categories to each team member based on our writing skills and experience. Unfortunately a team member went off sick after the second day of working on the project. Their absence meant our deadline was in danger of being missed but I wasn't prepared to let that happen. I assessed my absent colleague's writing tasks and decided we could split them among the three remaining team members. I had no plans during the evenings for that week so I volunteered to take on the bulk of the extra writing. By reassessing our plan and allocating tasks accordingly we could still complete the project on time despite the odds being stacked against us. That's a really good answer. I like the fact that you say I wasn't prepared to let that happen. Lots of people would go to their manager and ask for an extension of the deadline but you're not prepared to allow that to happen. You reassess your plan, allocate tasks and you volunteer to take on the bulk of the work. It shows you to be an outstanding employee. It's a great answer. Here is the next competency-based interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0082}
{"question": "What's been your biggest achievement to date?", "answer": "Now you can give an achievement from your personal life but where possible give one from your career a previous workplace situation preferably. Here's my top scoring response to assist you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What's been your biggest achievement to date?", "answer": "Here we go. My most significant achievement was in my previous job when the team I was working on achieved the best ever sales for a new company product launch. We got together to brainstorm marketing ideas and once we decided on the best ones we allocated tasks based on team at strengths. I'm very good at posting on social media so my job was to set up advertising campaigns on Facebook and Instagram. Other team members had various tasks including promoting the product to our current database of customers and also creating website blogs highlighting the product's benefits. It was my biggest achievement to date because it was a fantastic combined team effort that surpassed sales targets and all managers' expectations. That's a really good example answer. An example of a brilliant achievement that has helped your employer progress and grow and that's why it's a clever answer to that common competency-based interview question. Here's the next question I recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0058}
{"question": "Tell me about your time when you supported a work colleague who was struggling.", "answer": "Here is my top scoring response. A new member of staff joined our team and I could tell he was having difficulty using our computer systems and software packages. He was too anxious to ask for help so I spoke to him in private and explained that I had felt the same when I first joined the company. I asked him if he would find it useful if we spent some time together working through the different software packages and he said yes. I then put a plan of action in place of the things I wanted to show him and spent 30 minutes each day during breaks teaching him everything on you. Within two weeks he had reached competence in the position and I gave a copy of the action plan I had used to my manager and suggested we could use it again in the future to teach new staff members. That's a really good answer because you identified that your work colleague was reassured him. You said it's fine because that's how I felt when I first joined the company. You then put a plan of action in place which demonstrates you are organised and methodical. You then spent time during a work break teaching him and then you went to your manager and showed them the action plan so you could use it again when people joined the company. It's a really good answer. Put you across as a selfless employee. It's a really strong answer. Here is the next competency based interview question. I want you to prepare for and that is tell me about a time you dealt with a difficult person. Here's my top scoring response to assist you. When I started to work in my last job, a senior member of the team was difficult to collaborate with. He dismissed my ideas during team meetings and when I asked him for guidance, he was always too busy to assist.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.006}
{"question": "However, despite his difficulty, I was determined to build a good relationship.", "answer": "I found out that we both supported the same sports team so I taught him about our shared interest during a work break. His attitude toward me changed instantly. From that day forward, we built an excellent relationship inside and outside of work. I understand the importance of effective collaboration in a team and I will try my hardest to work well with everyone.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0156}
{"question": "You'd want to employ someone like that wouldn't you?", "answer": "Somebody who finds a clever and smart way to build a connection with a difficult coworker for the benefit of the company. Now, the next thing to do if you want to accelerate your learning even further is click that link right now that has appeared in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintoview.com and you can download instantly a copy of these slides plus an additional 26 brilliant answers to difficult competency based interview questions. It comes in a PDF guide which means you can have it literally in your inbox within two minutes from now and it's going to help you beat the competition at interview. Check out that link. Also, please make sure you hit that subscribe button. It is important. Thousands of you are passing your interviews. If you are subscribed, I can help you not just pass every job interview you ever attend but also help you to negotiate to salary progress throughout your career and get promoted when you are ready and make sure you give the video a like. Please give it a like because that tells me you find these training tutorials useful and it also really does motivate me to create more content for you. Thank you very much and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching. I wish you all a very best in your pursuit to passing your job interview have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0108}
{"question": "Why don't we start by having you tell me a little bit about yourself?", "answer": "So I'm a senior communications major here at Curry. Graduating anticipated graduation is May of 2015. I have very strong points in working with people. I am very involved here at Curry so I'm a part of the student activities office. I'm a student worker there. I'm an orientation leader as well. I have a background in theater. I've spent almost half of my life doing theater. I have vocal talents. I've taken voice lessons for nine years. I don't know what else to say. I don't know what else to talk about. I'm from Franklin Vance. Overall, really good. I think you did a really nice job of showing both parts of your background but also some interests. It really helps to paint a picture of who you are as a person. I think what you need to be careful of and what is a common mistake is to not just reiterate everything that they're looking at on your resume. So once you started to get into that I'm at this type of major and that I did this job and before that I did that job, all you're doing is reading your resume to them and they've already read your resume. That's why they brought you in as a candidate. So you kind of have to think about what your pitch is and what your story is and what is it that I want them to know within the first few minutes of meeting me. And that's really hard. This isn't something that's an easy thing to do but you want to just try to stay away. And you actually did a good job. I would say you weren't. I've had, you know, I, well, I'm from Franklin Mass and I went to such and such high school and then I went to Curry College and then I did this job and you didn't do that which was good. But you want to try to stay away from what I kind of would describe as like the chronology of your background and more as a summary of who you are as a candidate, what you're looking for, where your passion lies as it relates to the position.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0179}
{"question": "What is a weakness that you have?", "answer": "A weakness is when things are going, aren't going my way, I tend to like stress myself out to the max and I just don't know where to go from there but then when it all comes down to it I can pick myself back up. So it's a weakness that builds into a string kind of thing. I have a little bit of a formula that I like students to follow when it comes to answering this question because this is a tough one and it's a three-part formula. Pick something that's honest and authentic. So you did that.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0377}
{"question": "I didn't get the, oh I'm just, I work too hard, right?", "answer": "That's not very authentic. So you did, you picked an authentic weakness. Step two is to not pick a weakness that's going to throw yourself under the bus. So you don't want to say for instance you're going into PR, I really don't like working with people. Like that's a weakness that's going to be a deal breaker for that kind of industry. Three, you then take it and you talk about how you mitigate that weakness. So that's where the step, the third step I'd want you to take. So I think you hit one and two, but three would be to then say so typically what I do when I feel myself getting really overwhelmed is I stop, I take a breather or I begin to write lists or I figure out a way to organize my day so that if you were to ask my co-workers at Outback they probably have no idea that I'm like this but internally this is something that I go through and so these are the things that I do to make sure that it doesn't affect my work.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0503}
{"question": "Can you give me an example of an accomplishment you've had and what that tells us about you?", "answer": "So I think one of my greatest accomplishments is the general focus of me going to college because initially graduating high school I didn't, I wasn't planning on going to college. I was a C student high school, wasn't involved in anything, basically just went to school and left and didn't really do much. And then coming to college I had that mindset of I'm just going to do whatever and then I got involved on campus. I ended up getting deans list both semesters of my freshman year and then both semester sophomore year and then it continued up until my senior year, made deans list almost every semester a couple of semesters I haven't but close enough. I'm extremely involved on campus, I was an orientation leader, I have been involved in Curry Theatre and I'm participating in all of these specific things that go on at Curry which initially had no idea or anticipation of me doing anything that I've done at Curry so far. So I think that right there is a great aspect of my life that I initially had never expected to happen. Great. I think again very good, very good sort of common way to answer an interview question I think taking it up a notch is to complete the question which I kind of fed you which was and what does that tell us about you as a worker and that's usually not how that question is going to be asked. I'll say what can you give me a sense of an accomplishment that you've had but what you want in your brain to do is to translate that for them. So your example of making deans list. So I didn't think I was going to go to college and then I went to school and I made deans list immediately and what that can tell you about me is that once I get myself going I'm really committed that I've got great time management skills. You know it took me a little while to really put a commitment to education but once I did I was committed and that's where I am now and you know to start to think about what those what is it that made you get that accomplishment. So what skills because those are transferable skills those skills that you might that helped you to get deans list or the same type of skills that an employer wants that time management the attention to detail the getting things done getting things done on time. Those are the things that help you to get deans list are also the things that help you be a productive employee. So anytime you have an opportunity to talk about an accomplishment you want to tie immediately back to what attributes about you helps you get that accomplishment because that's going to paint a picture for them of what kind of worker you're going to be.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0195}
{"question": "What do you think sets you apart from other candidates?", "answer": "This sort of ties into like my strengths. I'm incredibly well at communicating with people and just being with people in general. I tend to have people gravitate towards me when I go places. I'm respectful. I am able to put forth any effort to help others including myself but others as well. And I'm just very creative as well and I'm always able to bring like a creative aspect into a situation. So again, I would encourage you to think about what sets you apart what makes you truly different and oftentimes look at your combination of experiences because most people won't have the exact same background as you. So if you piece together the different areas that make you different so might be the combination of event planning plus the theater or something that is a real interesting cross section that then brings a certain caliber to the workplace and kind of figure out what that is. And I think the other part of it is anytime you have an opportunity to talk about a story or an example that that could have been another opportunity to to providing an example to support what you're saying when you answer that question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0239}
{"question": "Do you have any questions for us?", "answer": "I don't have any questions. Thank you. We always want to have questions prepared prior to coming into an interview and oftentimes what happens is just through the back and forth of the interview those questions get naturally answered. That said, you do want to have some additional questions or have questions that are most likely not going to get answered unless you ask them. So the best way to do that is through company research. Research that organization, research have they been covered in the news. If you ask a question related to PR agency or interview with a PR agency and you saw it in the news that they just had a new client come on, that's a great opportunity to show that you've been really keeping track of them as an organization. So I noticed that you are now PR agency for XYZ company.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0133}
{"question": "Can you tell me a little bit about how that might impact the work of this area that I'm interviewing for?", "answer": "So that's a way to show that you've been engaged and you've been following them and that you're really interested in them as an organization and it also gives you a chance to ask a really good question. I would say overall, very good. I think your interviewing level is above average of a typical college student. I think this feedback is intended to take you to the next level and to be more on a professional, seasoned professional level of interviewing. So it's not an organ exam. I think a lot of times students think it's just answering the questions and there's a right way to answer, wrong way to answer and it's an ABC. It's not that it's really a back and forth conversation and you should be driving the interview as much as them. So it's your opportunity to learn about the position, the organization, when you're on an interview, you're trying to figure out whether this organization is a good match for you as much as they're trying to figure out whether you're a good match for them.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0152}
{"question": "What's probing question?", "answer": "Well all Amazon hiring managers are very, very good at their jobs. They are trained to ask the right questions and to delve a bit deeper into your responses to ask to take your intentions and the skills and qualities you have that will enable you to be a high performing Amazon employee. So probing questions will always come after you have given a response to an interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0145}
{"question": "Examples of probing questions include why did you approach things that way? Would you do anything different next time and also what did you learn from the situation?", "answer": "So to explain how I would answer probing questions I will give you another example response to an Amazon leadership principles interview question. So the next sample interview question is based on the leadership principle success and scale bring broad responsibility and the question is tell me about a time when you were faced with a moral dilemma at work. Let's take a look at my answer. A situation occurred whereby I was in a team meeting discussing a client project. All the other team members wanted to cut corners during the project delivery phase to save money but I disagreed with this approach. I felt it was my task to challenge my coworkers and to explain that whilst the client would not be aware that we had cut corners morally it was wrong. I immediately spoke and explained in a professional manner that I was not comfortable with this approach as the client had put their trust in us to deliver things to a very high standard. If we wanted to save money then we should discuss this with the client in an open and transparent manner. Now although my coworkers disagree with my viewpoint they all agreed not to cut corners and to stick with the initial project action plan to ensure everything was done to a high standard.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.009}
{"question": "So that's a really good response to that Amazon leadership principles interview questions but what about the probing questions?", "answer": "Let's take a look at them. So once I've given my answer to that interview question the Amazon hiring manager may ask me several probing questions an example probing question to that response might be in hindsight should you have not gone with the overall team majority to save the company money and I would respond by saying no I would do exactly the same thing again if this situation arose because the reputation of the companies on the line and I believe trust is vital when delivering projects for customers and clients. Another example of a probing question to that interview response could be should you have not informed the company owner in this instance to make them aware that the other team members were prepared to cut corners and potentially jeopardise the business's reputation and I would say to that probing question yes thinking back that's exactly what I should have done and it was a mistake not to although I made my views clear to the team at the time I should have made the company owner aware so he could ensure the same situation never happened again it's really important to admit if you've done something wrong when responding to the Amazon interview questions. Amazon interview tip number four is really important if you want to pass your Amazon interview and that is to make sure you have more than one example on the ready for each of the 16 leadership principles because by doing so you will be showing the hiring manager you have a diverse set of skills, a broad depth of knowledge and also more importantly transferable experiences that are a match for the job description. Now of course creating several responses to all 16 leadership principles is a difficult task so to help you I have created a brilliant Amazon interview questions and answers PDF guide that I think you're going to want to get access to. Now when you're ready click that link in the top right and corner of the video you can head through to my website pastmaintevute.com and you can download lots of sample responses to all 16 Amazon leadership principles. Amazon interview tip number five is to make sure you give a unique standout answer to the interview question why Amazon why do you want to work for Amazon so during your Amazon interview the hiring manager is going to ask you that question why do you want to work for Amazon so here's what I would say in response to this interview question I want to work for Amazon for several reasons because you are a forward thinking organization that strives to continually improve and grow this is a place where I feel I will be constantly pushed and challenged where I will get to work alongside other like minded professionals and where I will be able to work at the cutting edge of technology and customer focused advancements. I also want to work for Amazon because having studied the 16 leadership principles they certainly resonate with me from a personal and professional perspective. Finally I want to work for Amazon because I will feel a great sense of pride working for a company that is socially responsible the ones to always improve and that wants to be the best it can possibly be that's a brilliant answer to that tough Amazon interview question why Amazon Amazon interview tip number six is to make sure you have specific examples ready of where you have taken risks at work where you have succeeded and also where you have failed so taking risks Amazon has been so successful because it takes calculated risks that are in the best interests of its customers and its business overall so my advice before you go along to your interview is to think of a previous situation you've worked in where you took a risk that paid off.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.015}
{"question": "What about being successful? Well, my advice is to think of more than one occasion where you succeeded at work maybe you won an important sales contract for your employer maybe you succeeded by helping your employer save money maybe you've previously come up with a new conventional product idea for your company or maybe you worked as part of a team on a very important company project that succeeded against the odds and finally what about failure? Don't be afraid to show in your Amazon interview that you have made mistakes and failed in the past.", "answer": "Remember we all fail but it is what we learn from that process and what we do next that is most important. My advice is to think of a situation you've previously been in where you did make a mistake and you failed but you learned from it and there was a positive outcome. Amazon interview tip number seven is to make sure you are customer obsessed throughout the interview. Now remember Amazon has been so successful because it is one of the very few businesses in the world that has focused entirely on the customer they always provide brilliant customer service. Now I can almost guarantee that you will have to answer several interview questions based on your ability to put the customer first in everything you do at work. So for more example answers based on the Amazon leadership principle customer obsession make sure you click the link at the top of this video right now it will take you through to another important video right here on YouTube where I give you some brilliant example responses to tough Amazon interview questions. So I hope you've enjoyed that don't forget to click the link in the top right hand corner of the video if you want to download lots of example responses to Amazon interview questions don't forget to hit the subscribe button lots of you are passing your joint interviews I can only help you if you are subscribed please also make sure you give the video a like because that motivates me to create more videos for you and you can also connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video so it's great to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon interview have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0217}
{"question": "Could you tell me a little bit about yourself?", "answer": "Yeah, absolutely. First of all, thank you so much for having me. It's an honor to be here. So a bit about myself. I'm originally from Morocco where I lived pretty much my whole life. I then came to Boston and studied industrial engineering at Northeastern University. While I was in college, I did a few different internships. I did technical ones at a local power plant and at Amazon Robotics. I also did one in consulting at the Boston Consulting Group and was also the president of the consulting club at my university. So really, I'm someone who enjoys both the business side of things, but I also do have a passion for technology. So down the line, my goal is to start my own education technology company in my home country, Morocco. So I can make education more affordable through the use of tech. And outside of school and work, I also do magic tricks on college campuses. Oh, wow. That sounds like a very impressive background.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0349}
{"question": "So why exactly are you interested in interviewing with our consulting firm?", "answer": "Yeah, my reasons for joining your consulting firm are twofold. Number one, I think the exposure to the strategy work is very appealing to me. And the second, the opportunities for externship is also one that I am highly looking at. So on the strategy side, I know that your consulting firm is one of the few that gives you exposure to see-sweet executives and to strategy type projects early on in your career, which is something that I won't find at other companies. Then the second reason is the opportunity to do externships. So as I mentioned, I am interested in the education sector down the line. And I know that your company offers the opportunity to work for six months at a public sector type company or a nonprofit out in Africa focused on education. So I think those are some of the things that highly appeals to me in your company. Okay, awesome. That's good to know. So now we'll dive into a little bit more behavioral questions.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0229}
{"question": "So could you tell me about a time where you solved a difficult problem?", "answer": "That's a good question. I think the moment that I can think of is when I was working at the electrical power plant. We were trying to launch a new department and my task was to essentially source a supplier. Typically, we work with a supplier of generators from France, but this time around their capacity and also their pricing did not match our budget and what we were looking for. So what I ended up doing is I ended up creating a large list of all the different suppliers that are out there. And then I found a supplier in South Korea that I negotiated with and also was able to bring them in and implement all of the new generator technology. So that was able to save us a total cost of 10% from the total project and it was a huge success at the end of it. Awesome. Thank you for sharing that.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0127}
{"question": "So next, could you tell me about one or two of your key strengths?", "answer": "So I would say the biggest two would probably be my ability to persuade people and then the second would be leadership. I would say those are the biggest two.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0333}
{"question": "Okay, so could you dive a little bit more into that first one, your ability to persuade people?", "answer": "Maybe tell me about a time you were able to convince someone to change their mind. Yeah, so what I can think of is when I was working at Amazon, one of the big projects that we're trying to launch is the first new robotic facility. But it came out of time when COVID had just hit and I was unable to essentially source a lot of the material that we typically get from our Japanese supply. So the vice president of supply chain at the time, his executive decision was to push the launch and push it out for a few months. So instead, what I decided to do is try to see if there's a way to still keep the launch at the same time and I looked at some of our existing facilities already and try to source some of the unused material from there so that we don't delay the launch. So initially the VP of supply chain wanted to delay the launch but through the analysis, through explaining to him that we could source it from the other facilities, I was able to convince him to not delay the launch and instead change the strategy to still be able to get the facility right out on time. Okay, great. So now we'll dive into that second strength you had mentioned.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0262}
{"question": "Could you tell me about a time that you demonstrated strong leadership skills?", "answer": "Yeah, the one that I can think of is when I was working at the Boston Consulting Group. There I was leading a big real estate occupancy project where I wanted to essentially showcase what the attendance of each office looked like.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0238}
{"question": "What I had to do was then automate the process for a lot of the partners so that they have like a dashboard that they can like manipulate and change and look at the data.", "answer": "So I had to work with a large team of 15 different developers, software engineers and data engineers. So I worked with them to essentially gather the data, clean the data and process it and put it and visualize it through Tableau. So that was a great opportunity where I was essentially working with different teams, putting game plans, putting timelines for them. And as I mentioned at the end of it it was a very strong project and the partners were very happy with the dashboard. And it was a good like managerial experience for me at the time as well. Awesome, that sounds like a very worthwhile experience. So now that we've talked a little bit about your strengths maybe you could tell me about a weakness that you face in the workforce. Yeah, I'd say the biggest one is probably my ability to prioritize when there's a lot of conflicting and computing priorities. The big one in that case would be when say there's three or four different projects and all of them are high urgency or high priority. Sometimes a someone who's still very junior in their career, I still don't have that business sense on which one I should tackle first. But I've been trying to improve on it and work on it. So what I do now is I typically just chat with my manager and try to understand where the business focus should be. And sometimes even just directly ask on how I should prioritize some of the work. So I have been improving on that a little bit and I think with some seniority I will hopefully be able to get there and understand what I should start with first. Okay, definitely makes sense. So those are all the questions that I had for you today.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0289}
{"question": "Before we end do you have any questions for me?", "answer": "Yeah, I think I have two big questions. I think the first one is as you know there's a lot of big push for like the remote workforce right now. And as a consulting company there's a lot of work working directly with clients or coming in in person to visit the clients.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0364}
{"question": "Do you think that the consulting business model would necessarily change now that we are in a remote environment?", "answer": "I think that's a big one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "And then the second question that I had for you is what are the kind of the big goals of your consulting company by say 2025? What are the big milestones that you guys are hoping to achieve and is say international expansion one of those big milestones that you're looking at?", "answer": "Great, so I think Cia did an amazing job with that interview. There are four main things that I think he did really well. First, he was very poised and confident throughout the entire interview. We were going back and forth and I was asking him a lot of questions but he came back very prepared for each question. Second, he used the star method very well. I could really understand the situation, task, action and result. And he introduced each story in a way that made me understand what he was saying. Third, he was very concise in each of his stories. And lastly, he ended with some very thoughtful questions that made it seem like he really cared about the company and the position. Overall, Cia did a great job and I would accelerate him to the next round.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0142}
{"question": "Okay, so why are you being asked behavioral interview questions?", "answer": "Well, behavioral interview questions often start with, tell me about a time when you delivered excellent customer service.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you worked under pressure. Tell me about a time when you worked in a team.", "answer": "So you are being asked these questions too assess your suitability for the role you have applied for. Now, if you can give the interviewer previous examples of where you have demonstrated key workplace skills, you are far more likely to get hired. And that is the purpose of this tutorial. To give you example previous situations that you might have been in where you demonstrate the key workplace skills. That's very important if you are going to pass your interview. So let me tell you how to structure your answers to behavioral interview questions. This is really easy to remember. So this structure is called the star technique. Star stands for situation task action result. So if the interviewer asks you any type of behavioral interview question, you will use a star technique to structure your answer. Let's assume the question is tell me about a time when you worked in a team. So you would start off your answer and you would tell the interviewer the situation you were in. You would then move on and briefly outline the task that needed doing. You then move on and give in depth details about the action you took to complete the task before finishing off and telling the interviewer the result following your actions. So always use a star technique when responding to behavioral interview questions. Okay, so let me now give you seven brilliant answers to the most common behavioral interview questions. Here we go. So the first question is tell me about a time when you worked in a team. Let me give you my example answer that uses that star technique of situation task action and result. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.028}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you worked in a team.", "answer": "I was working in a previous role when two team members went off sick at short notice. It was our task as the remaining team members to take on the additional duties of our sick co-workers to deliver the company's objectives and goals on time. We got together assessed the duties of our sick co-workers and allocated tasks based on our strengths. We agreed to support each other and if anyone was struggling with their additional duties, we would step into help. Now at one point a co-worker was unsure how to complete one of their tasks. So I finished my own work and went over to help. By working together and supporting each other as a team, we were able to get all tasks and duties finished on time despite being two team members short. So that's a really good example answer. The use is a star technique that demonstrates when you have previously worked in a team. Let me now give you the second behavioral interview question and top scoring example answer. So that question is tell me about a time when you had a conflict at work. Now the majority of people respond by saying, I've never had a conflict with anyone at work. That is not the way to answer this behavioral interview question. Let me give you my example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.013}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had a conflict at work here we go.", "answer": "I was working in a previous role when I noticed a co-worker was consistently late for team meetings. Each time he was late he gave a different excuse. His lack of punctuality was starting to affect the team, so I saw it as my responsibility to talk to him about it. I spoke to him in private and explained how I was concerned about his time keeping. He initially became defensive and told me to mind my own business. I remained calm and explained how each time he was late for team meetings it put back the progress of our team. I then asked if there was anything I could do to help him arrive on time. Just by speaking to my co-worker and offering to help him made him realise how important it was to be punctual. Moving forward he was never late again. I was pleased I intervened in a calm and pragmatic manner. That's a really good example answer and it shows that you can deal with conflict in a competent professional and calm manner.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0055}
{"question": "Don't go anywhere because I still have five more behavioral questions and answers to give you.", "answer": "But when you're ready, click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintv.com and you can instantly download these slides and also my full set of 27.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time, behave, interview questions and top scoring examplances.", "answer": "It's a fantastic resource and it's going to help you pass your interview at the first attempt. Here's question number three.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about your time you worked under pressure.", "answer": "Again, this question comes up all the time during job interviews. Here's my example answer that uses a star technique of situation task action and result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about your time you worked under pressure.", "answer": "My manager asked for a volunteer to complete the work of a coworker who had recently left the company. A replacement team member had yet to be found, so they needed someone to do their work in the interim. I saw this as an opportunity to diversify my skills, so I volunteered. It was my task to learn my former coworkers duties quickly and complete their work and my own on time. I studied their job description and ticked off the work I could quickly complete. Now for the tasks I was unsure of, I read the company operating procedures and used online training tutorials. Now once confident, I prioritized all my tasks based on the company's needs. Red tasks were urgent and came first, Amber tasks second and green tasks could be completed when I had more time available. Now by using a systematic approach to learning and completing all tasks, I could do the work of two people which helped the company in its time of need. That's another really good thorough answer to that common behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0109}
{"question": "Tell me about your time you worked under pressure.", "answer": "And what I really like about that answer is you are explaining how you prioritize your work using a traffic light system of red, amber and green tasks. Behavioral interview question number four is, tell me about a time you disagreed with your boss. Now again, a lot of people respond by saying, I've never disagreed with my boss. That's not the way to answer this question. Let me give you my example response that uses that brilliant easy to remember structure called star situation task action result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0111}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you disagreed with your boss.", "answer": "In my previous role, my manager was conducting my annual performance review. He said he was very impressed with my overall performance, but wanted me to spend less time talking to customers on the telephone. I disagreed with this and it was my task to explain to him why in a professional and respectful manner. I explained that I had worked hard to build long-term relationships with customers, so they became long-term advocates of the business. I cited several examples where customers had spent considerable sums of money with the company and left positive online reviews after I had spent time helping them on the telephone. After listening to my thoughts, he agreed that the length of time I was cultivating relationships on the telephone with customers was, in fact, beneficial. That's a really good example answer. So you are not being defensive, you are disagreeing with your boss in a calm and respectful manner, but you are explaining why. And that reason is to the benefit of the company. Here's an next question. Question number five.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.011}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a mistake.", "answer": "Again, this is a really difficult behavioral interview question to answer. Most people say I've never made a mistake.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't say that.", "answer": "We all make mistakes, but it is how you respond to the mistake and learn from it that is being assessed here. Here's my example answer that uses a start technique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a mistake.", "answer": "When I started working my previous role, my supervisor asked me to write a blog for our website. It was my task to write a compelling blog about a new company product. Now, unfortunately, because I was busy with other important tasks, I failed to thoroughly check the finished blog. When I submitted it to my supervisor, she highlighted several grammar mistakes. I was very disappointed because I'd let myself, my team and my supervisor down. After apologizing, I rewrote the blog and ran a thorough spell and grammar check before resubmitting my work for approval. Now, I learned a lot from that mistake, and I now always check everything thoroughly to make sure it is perfect. That's another really good example answer. And that mistake is not too bad, but you recognize you made a mistake. You are apologizing, you put things right, and also you learn from it. Behavioral interview question number six.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you provided excellent customer service.", "answer": "Again, this comes up all the time during job interviews. Now, some of you might be saying, but Richard, I'd never been in these situations before. Well, if this type of question comes up and you've never been in the situation, give them an example of when you were on the receiving end of excellent customer service. Because that shows strong observational skills. You can give an example of when you witness somebody else doing the situation that is being assessed. Let me give you my example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you provided excellent customer service.", "answer": "I was helping a customer in a previous role choose a product suitable for their needs. Now, my task was to ask them questions to determine precisely what they wanted and help them choose a product within their budget. I welcome them to the store and our several questions to establish their desired product and budget. Now, the customer expressed an interest in one of our more expensive products. But I explained that I felt this was different from what they needed and a slightly cheaper product would be more beneficial. They thanked me for my honesty in helping them decide on a more affordable alternative, and they left a brilliant review of our company online. So, brilliant answer to that common behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.008}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you provided excellent customer service.", "answer": "Here's the next one.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you went above and beyond what was expected.", "answer": "Wow, this is a tricky one. Here's my example answer that uses a start technique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you went above and beyond what was expected.", "answer": "It was late on a Friday afternoon when the company website went down. This was a significant problem because an online sale was due to commence at 9 a.m. the following morning. Now, my manager asked for a volunteer to stay behind late that evening to help resolve the issue. I volunteered to help. It was my task to help my manager troubleshoot the problem and get the website back up and running again quickly. Now, I started by researching the issue online. I could not find an obvious cause of the problem. So, I then went to the website upwork.com and hired a web developer to assess the issue for us. He informed me the problem was down to the size of our server. It wasn't sufficient to handle the upsurge in traffic. The website was experiencing. So, I asked my manager for permission to upgrade the server. As soon as a new server was live, the website started functioning again and we were able to have a successful online sale. So, that's a brilliant response because it shows you are prepared to help out the company. You go above and beyond. You try and resolve the issue yourself. You can't. But you then use your initiative and you go on a website called Outwork.com which is somewhere you can hire contractors and developers. And you hire a suitably qualified web developer who then resolves the issue for you. It's a really good example answer. Now, the next thing to do. If you want to pass your interview, at the first attempt, he's click that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website. PassmainTV.com and you can instantly download a copy of these slides.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0099}
{"question": "Are my full set of 27? Tell me about a time behavioral interview questions on top scoring exam palanters.", "answer": "It's a fantastic resource. Make sure you check that out. Thank you so much for watching. Please don't forget to subscribe to the channel. As I said at the start, literally thousands of you are passing your job interviews. If you are subscribed, I can help you to pass every job interview you attend. Negotiate a salary and progress throughout your career.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0156}
{"question": "Don't forget to give the video a like.", "answer": "It's a small ask, but it really does motivate me to create more content for you. Thank you. Oh, and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an honor and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and always you all the best. For passing your job interview, have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.025}
{"question": "Ari, can you tell me about a time where you have to deal with the failure?", "answer": "Hey, everyone. I'm Diana, as you know, and this is one of the best channels to get tips on async your product management in and of you. Today, we have a very special guest with Ari here today. And I'm going to have her give an intro. Hi, I'm Ari. I'm super excited to be here. Diana definitely helped me a lot both in her YouTube videos. And we did a private session as well. I'm at strike now. I started a little over a month ago. And I got offers from TikTok, lift, stripe, and a series D startup called upside. Awesome. And that's why we have already here today because she serves as the model example how to do behavioral interviews. So today, we're going to be asking Ari a couple questions. So the most asked questions in behavioral interviews. And we're going to see how she aces them. All right. So we're going to get into it. So most behavioral questions or even case questions will start off asking, tell me about yourself.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.027}
{"question": "So are you?", "answer": "Pretend that I'm stripe interviewing you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me a little bit about yourself.", "answer": "Awesome. Happy to be here. Let me just give you a little introduction to myself. I started my career working in finance initially in investment banking. And then moved into corporate finance at Groupon. My participated in a little internal hackathon and then kind of discovered product management and haven't looked back since. If you've used Groupon before, you're probably most familiar with our voucher product, very annoying to use like you always have to print something out. So the product that I was on was completely rethinking that experience. It was called card linked offers. A user could upload a deal directly onto their credit card, type it as they normally would at like a restaurant and then earn cash back. So I was responsible for the entire consumer experience there initially kind of thinking about growth and then moving a little more into retention and monetization. I then moved to London where I joined Stripe and I was on our advertiser measurement platform team.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0237}
{"question": "So an example I always like to use is if you're overeats and you're trying to advertise on Twitter, you might want to figure out like is this taco creative working or is this hamburger creative working?", "answer": "And so one of the products that I was responsible for was a detesting to help them kind of figure out what's working and not working to be able to get some of those rich insights onto their dashboard. So I'm really excited to be seeking to you at Stripe today to kind of bridge my experience and finance and product. Awesome. All right. Let's talk about what worked and things that folks would have liked to see more. So I'll give a spiel myself and then I'd love to open it up to Arieta. Give what she thinks works. The first thing that stood out. I love the experiences she talked about at Groupon at Twitter. I could really imagine it because she gave really specific products. A lot of product companies hiring today care a lot about consumer experiences. So the way that Ari was able to talk about it shows that she can break things down to explain it to a five year old. The second thing that worked really well was these product buzz keywords. So Arieta's talking the talk, which makes the other person on the other side believe that she's done the work. She mentioned things like retention, A.V. testing, you know, all these PM buzzwords. All right.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0315}
{"question": "What do you think was great about that intro?", "answer": "Yeah. I think one thing that's always resonated with the other side of the interview is being able to latch on to something that they can actually understand the team that I was on at Twitter was actually a pretty back end heavy product. But if you're able to root it in some sort of example that they can kind of understand. I think it helps a lot. And then in your following examples and your behavioral questions, they can kind of remember what you were talking about in the beginning. Yeah. And another thing I for a convention are did amazingly well. She answered a question that was not asked yet, but isn't the back of the mind of the hiring manager, which is why are you good fit for this role. So you saw her at the end saying, I am interested in this role to bridge the gap between product and finance, which she started off in in her early career. So this again shows why she's a good fit. And I always recommend ending with that and tell me about yourself. So great job. All right. The next commonly asked question. So Arya, tell me about a time in your career, where you've had to deal with the conflict. Sure. Just give me a second to just write down some of an example that comes to mind. Yeah. Sure. Take your time. Awesome. Cool. So let me just kind of briefly mention some of my thoughts on kind of conflicts in the workplace. I think that they often fall into kind of three categories. I think the first. It's sort of healthy pushback that you get from your cross functional partners like design and engineering that make the product and the user experience better. I think the second is oftentimes like misalignment on maybe, oh, fast, you want to get to market, which can often be solved in sort of sharing like what's your risk tolerance for some of these things in some vision or a strategy. And lastly, the end of the day, we're all just sort of people. And so you're not going to get along with every single person. And so the example I love to share with you kind of at a mix of all three of these, which I think is an interesting thing. And so this was with an engineering manager that I worked with in the past, who was new to be an engineering manager from an IC when was also new to our team. And so one day I received an email that was copying my manager as well as my skip level and his manager and kind of have like a bullet pointed list of all of the things that he felt were wrong about a certain product decision I had made to include a feature in this MVP. And obviously my initial reaction was very defensive. I think anytime you see your manager or your skip level CC on something you feel like it's an escalation. And I was also kind of surprised because the specific feature that he was kind of calling out and questioning my product decision making there. I thought we had kind of had many conversations back and forth about why we wanted to include this feature or not include this feature. So I sent him a Slack message saying like, hey, here's kind of the document where we kind of talked about this decision and came to something just to jog your memory, but we have a one on one coming up. So let's kind of talk about it live then. And during that conversation, we kind of pretty quickly were able to kind of get to like really what the root cause of the issue was one of the engineers was behind schedule. And so in order to sort of make up for that last time he was like, well, if we get rid of this feature, we can kind of still hit that code complete date. I think getting to that root cause helped a little bit, you know, we were able to advocate to kind of figure out how to get more resources on the team, etc. So after I think this period of kind of tension where it felt like, again, I felt still defensive that why are you escalating this issue in one of the following one on ones that I had with him. I shared that I think that the PM EM relationship is so key to the success of our products and also just to making our relationship good and enjoyable for the duration of the time we're working together. And one thing that I can see that you're perhaps I didn't give that psychological safety and those meetings, for example, for him to be able to say, well, this engineer is behind schedule. Maybe that's something that I could have caught. And maybe there was something that I was not necessarily showcasing to be able to show that that true partnership. And so I think in this example, one thing that I really learned is not every relationship is going to come completely seamlessly and naturally. And in this example, I think it was a relationship that I had to more actively move towards to be able to kind of get to that true EM PM partnership and can kind of happy to kind of to share some of those details of how we got there. But I think that we eventually got there and I think it was an interesting learning that, you know, again, two people are not always going to seamlessly get along, but you can definitely make strides to get there. Awesome. Now, how many of you guys watching are like, that's happened to me because that was my mindset. I was like, I remember that time. My, yeah, I'm also escalated to my manager copied to see everyone else on the email. So one thing that I loved about that story was how much it resonated. A lot of the times when they're looking for product managers, they want to be talking to people with dealt with the same challenges. So are you talking about her conflict with an EM will tell the interview on the other side, I know how to manage these conflicts. So that was the first in this so now the second thing are it was very proactive about sharing what she did in this case that she was being proactive. So a common thing we always talk about as some of you might see in previous behavioral interview videos is you want to focus on the traits or actions that you did in these stories. The context itself is not going to get you very far because the context is going to change from job to job. But in this case, are you focusing on her pulling the EM to the side in a one and one to figure out the root cause. Her then, proactively reaching out to the EM to say, how do we build a strong relationship going forward. Those are the things that traits that they want to see in the people they hire.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0284}
{"question": "Are thoughts from you.", "answer": "Yep, I think I agree with that. I think one thing with conflict stories like you mentioned is the context is not necessarily important, but you want to show that it was truly something that maybe wasn't solved by just like I showed him this data point and it solves the issue because things never are that easy. Yeah, I did love the first rendition. I was like, I showed him the document where yeah, we agreed on everything. I did that as well. I love that. I had a question. You took a second to write things down.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.03}
{"question": "What were you doing? What were you writing down?", "answer": "For sure. I think this is something that you taught me is it's super helpful for me to write down the question, even if it's a rather simple question like conflict writing it down helps me sort of just remember. Then I read just a couple bullet points of like what the story is itself that I want to be able to follow so that I can kind of keep track of my own thoughts. And then the last thing that I do is take a second to really figure out what am I trying to convey in this story as Diana was mentioning. And maybe that's a few sentence like a sentence, a couple words that you want to convey. So here I've written down relationship building ability. Maybe something like empathy that you want to just make sure that that's coming across in your answer. Yes. And because Ria was focused, it did come across right those traits beyond just context of what happened was what stood out and I'm like, yes, I'd hire Arya the putter in the war with the yams that I don't want to do it. Awesome. So given that we dealt with a lot of conflicts, there's sometimes where we also have to deal with failure.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.036}
{"question": "Arya, can you tell me about a time where you have to deal with a failure?", "answer": "Yep. Just give me another couple of seconds to try to down some thoughts. Sounds good. Awesome. I would love to tell you about the first time I had to Sunset a product. I was working on a new monetization product during my time at Groupon. So as a product, I was super excited about it was one of those things where like I really felt like this is going to make Groupon a kind of money. I rallied the troops and was like, this is the next big thing that we're going to work on. I set our success criteria for the initial launch as well as sort of kind of a north star metric that we wanted to eventually get to, which is based on proper per thousand impressions as the metric. So after our launch, we we crushed that initial success metric and you might be wondering, well, how is this end up being sunsetted. So one thing after that initial launch was I started thinking, okay, great.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0349}
{"question": "Now how do we start to build a roadmap to get to that north star?", "answer": "I think that was my mistake number one is that even prior to that initial launch, I should have some idea of how I plan to get to that north star metric. So rather than kind of being near sighted and just looking at that initial success metric, how do I get to where I actually want to get to, whether that be in six months or a year. And that was something that I didn't have. So because I didn't have that now, I'm starting to put together kind of a list of future ideas I brought together one of those same kind of troops that I mentioned of design and engineering to brainstorm. And every time we came up with an idea, we would size it and we were barely moving the needle. They needed to move it by dollars of profit and we were really looking at sense. So this is when I started to really think, oh, like, what are we going to have to do now that we're really not moving the needle and we are so far away from getting to that north star metric. So I remember literally going back to my desk and starting to kind of write down my thoughts here to figure out like what went wrong. You're how did this go from something I was so excited about that now I'm kind of questioning if this is even going to be a successful product in the long term. Some of the things that I noticed with this product is I over-indexed on the numbers, you know, it was really a monetization product and I was like running all these models figuring out how this is going to be successful from strictly a monetization perspective. But when I really thought about it, I was like, what is the user problem we're solving and I couldn't articulate that and I think that's really bad if I was a product manager, I can't articulate the user problem we're solving for. So sort of a solution to a problem that didn't exist. And I think one thing that I could have caught here is just doing kind of basic user research. I remember there was a coworker who was, you know, didn't work in this area at all and she said she saw it on our group on.com page and she said like no idea how the product worked. And so we have an employee who has no idea. I could have done some like really scrappy user research to do some of that kind of gut checking.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0378}
{"question": "Does this make sense or not.", "answer": "So that being said, I kind of had to make the decision to sunset the product, poke at it from every angle to see if I can make it work. And again, there was really no problem that needed to be solved. And so I brought that back to that same group of people. Very nervous because just a quarter earlier, I was saying the opposite to this team. And kind of just like shared with them exactly what I had kind of been going through hoping to be able to bring some of those insights into, you know, these are some of the gaps that I missed. And this is why we need to sunset this product and was kind of hoping that the key takeaway was like we make mistakes. And in this case, I definitely did. But part of that is just product development where you fail and you kind of have to get back on to it. I think that there was a bunch of people who understood that and I remember there was two engineers who were upset because it felt like throw away work and kind of wasted their time. And so with those two folks in particular, I had to really be super diligent about every feature thereafter, like in the couple sprints after every product requirement was like super thorough. I made sure I didn't skip any stands and stuff like that to really be able to get that trust back with them. And so I think some of my learning here were I think there's some tangible things like make sure that you have a sort of a roadmap when you're doing product development. And part of that kind of initial strategy is being able to really articulate a problem and make sure that you have a lot of conviction around that problem and everyone is able to rally about that. And if you do need to sunset a product, you need to be able to regain that trust from your cross-monctional partners. I love that again, another story that resonates I've definitely sunset products before, but what I loved about that story when they ask you these failure stories. They are looking for humility and vulnerability. So when those folks answering the story that like, oh, I failed at not making this thing perfect. That's not what they're looking for. So Ari did a good job of going through a story where she actually failed and lost the trust of some of her co-workers. So that's the first thing that stood out. The second thing that I noticed throughout this story, Ari is sprinkling in again, product skills. She talked about coming up at the metric of what was it, something impressions. I think it's a standard metric. A lot of times when e-commerce. So that's a skill that they're often looking for, and product managers, as you can see in the case studies they gave you, can you come up with success metrics. She also talked about skills that included figuring out what the monetization plan was, the strategy was, and also optimizing for impact. That's what they're looking for. So she gave a failure story. She highlighted some of these successful things that they are looking for in a product manager. And then third thing that I loved. This was a story ultimately. So she gave initially this, we killed it on our success metric. But then you might be wondering why did we sunset it. I know a good story is when there are teasers or some thing unexpected thing that something that was unexpected. So that really continued to engage the audience.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0333}
{"question": "Are your thoughts new?", "answer": "I definitely agree that I think sometimes you need to. I think anytime it's like conflict or failures, maybe just sort of show that are really kind of tell the story at the arc of when you were maybe disappointed in yourself or others were disappointed in you, but then ultimately what the learnings were. I think one piece of advice is sometimes with stories you can have a specific metric like the increased conversion by 5%. But in a lot of behavioral stories, you don't have like a metric of success. So your metric of successes, your key learnings. So maybe try to end every story with a. These are the two things are learned or my biggest takeaway from the story was X. That's a really good point. I think that's a key learnings because they want to show someone who continues to learn can continue to grow. So that is something that I have heard from many companies.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0364}
{"question": "And I'm also curious, Arya, how do you come up with your stories?", "answer": "I know most of my clients, they struggle to remember one specific story for all the 50 hundred variation of question. Yeah, for sure. I remember I also did the same thing where I put together like a hundred most asked questions and a story for each, but that's not sustainable. So in stat, I sort of thought of the five to 10 most memorable career stories for me. Honestly, maybe even closer to five different really big products that I've worked on that have a lot of stories with them. And you can kind of get stories from any of those experiences. So even with the conflict story, there's sort of a follow up with another designer who I conflict with. So you can kind of get a lot of answers maybe from just one key story or product you have done. So that's amazing. So the takeaway with that was focus on five experiences that you had. I think about five products that I've launched in chip. And then to Arya's point, you kind of go deep because throughout that product about life cycle, there were conflicts, failures, ways that you came up with a metric and managed stakeholders.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.029}
{"question": "So go deep thinking about those experiences, which can be hard, right?", "answer": "Yeah. Those were things in our past and you working on that was years ago.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How do you tend to recall them?", "answer": "I think one thing my dad actually taught me is that like if you're kind of in the middle of something that you feel like is going to be something you want to retell later, just document it right now. Like maybe you're like struggling with a coworker or you're working on something that you think is like really successful, just putting like your own personal notes up. So you can kind of refer to it later. Wow, that is very proactive. So come up with a work diary is what I wish I was working like you can kind of like paying old co-workers and stuff like that, fast, to jog your memory.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.1017}
{"question": "But yeah, what was that thing we thought about and thing?", "answer": "Yeah. Amazing. All right, we have one last story. So all right, tell me about a time you committed to a deliverable and you couldn't deliver on it. Great. Yeah. And the example from Twitter comes to mind. As I mentioned, I was working with advertisers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0213}
{"question": "And so one of the specific features that I was working on was one of those features that advertisers were long knocking on our door being like, one is this going to be ready? And so naturally in turn, sales was always pinging me saying, one is this going to be ready?", "answer": "And we finally had a date for our beta launch and everyone was super excited. So when it was kind of finally coming time for that launch, we were not actually hitting our beta success metric, meaning we were not able to kind of pass that threshold to sort of give us the green light to get to beta.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0339}
{"question": "Where I kind of had to make a decision, you know, do we still want to move forward given kind of this excitement around this launch or do I want to, you know, really respect the success metric.", "answer": "And I decided to delay the launch of that beta because ultimately you set success metrics for a reason that being said, then I needed to kind of go back to the folks that I had committed to namely sales to kind of explain what was going on. And so we have this biweekly meeting between product and sales during which I wanted to kind of talk about this. And before going into that meeting, I wanted to make sure I was really prepared and one thing I thought about was if I was sales, what would I ask and like, why, why do they keep pinging me and why are they going to be disappointed in this. The same way product managers think of users and really empathize with them, I tried to now think of sales in this case as my stakeholders that I needed to empathize with and kind of figure out what their needs are. And so there's a couple of things that I knew that they were going to ask me was why, like, why is this delayed what's going on, what happened with the success metric. They were going to say, okay, well, now what, when is it going to be ready. And then lastly, they were going to kind of ask like, well, what's my health like, how do we how do we expedite this in whatever way we that we can. So I sort of prepared questions for all three of these. The first was a little tricky with the why. So I tried to sort of demystify why in the specific example, there are ML models for a little off to kind of get that into a sound bite that they would be able to recognize. The reason they might be concerned with these ML models not working is because they actually showed Twitter in a less positive light as advertisers. It was actually under estimating the effect of Twitter as an advertising tool. And so I knew that was something they would be able to latch on to and they'd be like, okay, yeah, make sense. Like we're not going to launch this unless that's fixed. That was helpful. And then the second is now, when is this going to be ready. And I'm sure you've been in this position sometimes you don't know because you still need to wait for. A root cause for engineering, you still need to kind of get a date for a date. So in lieu of that, I basically put together like a week by week kind of cadence of providing those date for date. So by the end of this week, I'm going to make sure that we have the root cause completed from there. We're going to do like a technical design review and then from there we're going to commit to the work, etc. So rather than this being a biweekly meeting, I said I'll be able to give updates twice a week so that you're able to kind of follow along and was able to give them the geartickets to follow along, etc. And normally maybe that level granularity I wouldn't provide to sales, but in this case, I knew that would be super helpful them to actually track what the end date might be. And then lastly, I had sort of an ask prepared for them as well. I wanted to get another data scientist on our team. And so I had the head of sales, sort of co author this ask with me to be able to get that extra data science resource. So we didn't get that in time for this specific launch when we got them on board later. And I don't think that that would have been possible unless I had sort of this ask prepared in this meeting to really kind of show the case of why this product is important. Next time we can maybe hit our launch date up in a different experience. Awesome. So as with every story we've seen, Ari has been really focused on the particular traits you stranic may.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0339}
{"question": "So I'm curious, can I guess the trait that you're about to convey?", "answer": "And let's try to say it the same time and see if we come up with it. All right. Okay. One, two, three. Empathy. That's how you know you've done a good job when the audience can play back to what they heard. And that is that validated that she was able to successfully convey the traits she's trying to show. And Empathy is a really, really key trait as a product manager, whether you're dealing with the products to deliver consumers or building relationships. So that really stood out.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0211}
{"question": "What do you think worked in that story? What did you like about it?", "answer": "Yep. I think this is probably also an experience many people have had and working with sales as maybe kind of your users because they're your liaison to oftentimes your end users. And I think oftentimes we see sales teams are legal or something as roadblocks to be able to get your product to be shipped. But I think hopefully this story showed that I didn't see them as that, but rather as enablers to be able to get to my user. So like again, sort of empathizing with why they might be excited or disappointed about this product being delayed. Let's hopefully what I'm trying to convey. And she also conveyed other skill like managing stakeholders. Oftentimes as the product manager, you're managing multiple, whether it's leadership, you mentioned sales and figuring out. You mentioned usually we don't give them a week by week update. But in this case to build that relationship, you went out of your way to do the extra work to do that.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0171}
{"question": "You then also sat in their shoes to say, what are they going to need to convey to their consumers?", "answer": "And what's going to be enough to persuade them that this is okay. I really like that one where like I told them that they don't want to look bad in front of customers. Yeah. That also shows strategic thinking. Yes. Amazing. So we saw a star example of what it's like to answer behavioral interviews. So some of the things we talked about just to summarize is one focus on the trait you're trying to convey to talk about the different product skills. Just embed them and sprinkle them throughout your story. And third focus on the storytelling element. Right. Having these teasers, things that we talked about a lot of failure stories. And if you create that heroism, the heroic arc is what a lot of these famous movies are known for. So those are some of the things Arya did any other advice you give and awesome curious. You've been interviewing during a crazy time when the tech market has been down.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0353}
{"question": "Have you struggled?", "answer": "Yeah, I think I got those four offers that for every offer there was probably, you know, maybe 10 on sites that I did legitimately that I didn't get from. It's a tough market. I mean, I think even in a good market product interviewing is very difficult. So you're watching this like hanging there and trying to find the light at the end of the tunnel. I think one thing that Diana shared with me during one of our one on one coaching sessions is to really just kind of show yourself as a person. Like for me, I think that following the star method, for example, to a tea didn't really bring out the traits that I wanted to showcase. So instead of kind of figured out my own way of storytelling and being able to highlight those to show vulnerabilities to show humility. So I think I just like figure out what works for you and don't feel like you need to necessarily stick to one framework rigidly. Yeah, that's such a good point, but do have a structure. I think that's also what Arya did really well throughout. And I think that's what I think about her story about tell me about a time you had a conflict and she's like, these are the three types of conflicts. That's something else they're looking for in your behavioral responses. Because most common mistake will hear is people start rambling. They lose whatever point they're trying to make a trying to figure out as they talk. So that was something already did great throughout. And then as you heard from Arya, it is a struggle. And I think that's why they're not alone. So whoever is watching, because I have seen in a lot of forms or even my own clients dealing with rejection after rejection hanging there. It only takes one job for it to matter. In this case, Arya got four offers, but it was after, you know, a while where she was struggling. So hanging there guys. And again, thank you so much, Arya, for showing us a great example of asing to behavioral injuries. Thank you so much. Thank you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0421}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to make a difficult decision.", "answer": "Here's a brilliant answer. In my previous job, my supervisor was on annual leave. A supplier kept letting us down, which resulted in customer complaints. I had to decide what to do about the situation in the absence of my supervisor. I weighed up the pros and cons of keeping the current supplier and decided to see can you one because I felt it was in the best interests of the company. Before informing the supplier we no longer needed them, I sought an alternative. I researched online, found several potential suppliers, checked their reviews and company history and discussed terms with them. Now, once I had found a new supplier, I let the old one go. Customer service standards then quickly improved, are my supervisor thanked to me for making the right decision when she returned from her holiday. Behavioral interview question number two.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you anticipated a problem before it arose. How did you deal with the situation?", "answer": "This is a really difficult one to answer correctly. Here's a super answer. In my previous role, we were working towards a black Friday sale event. The team I was a part of had been preparing hard for the sale. We had several promotions planned, had contacted all previous customers to give them discount codes to use on the day of the sale, and we had employed an online marketing agency to run adverts for us across social media. In the build-up to the sale, I had concerns that the website server would not be able to handle the surge in traffic. If the website crashed during the sale, all our hard effort would go to waste, and the company would lose money. I carried out some research online and confirmed the company server would not be sufficient. I informed my manager about my research and he thanked me for my proactive thinking before commissioning an external IT company to upgrade the server in time for the sale. Behavioral interview question number three, tell me about a time when you went above and beyond what was required at work. Here we go. My manager came into the office one day and said another department within the organization needed someone to help out for a few weeks to cover a staff shortage. I decided to volunteer because it was an excellent opportunity for me to develop new skills and learn more about the company. The next day I started working my new team and obtained a brief from my manager. I was tasked with dealing with customer queries on the telephone and by email something I hadn't done before. It was a great experience because it taught me the importance of consistently providing excellent customer service and I better understood how the company functioned and what I could do to assist its growth. Behavioral interview question number four is, tell me about a time when you helped to improve a process at work. This is another really difficult one but here's an outstanding answer. I had concerns in my previous job that we needed a feedback facility to enable customers to make recommendations on how we could improve. Because I understood how crucial excellent service was to the businesses success, I found a feedback form online that could be easily installed on our website, allowing customers to complete it once they had made a purchase. The form gate customers the opportunity to rate their shopping experience and provide written feedback on how they felt we could improve. Once the form had been installed, we started receiving valuable feedback that enabled us to increase customer service standards. This in turn helped to increase sales and customer retention. Behavioral interview question number five is, tell me about a time when you disagreed with a coworker. This is another tough one but here's my outstanding answer. I was tasked with working on a client-based project in a previous role with another team member. We were responsible for working together to finish everything within four weeks for the client. At the start of the project, we disagreed on an appropriate plan of action and method of working. This was because we both had different working backgrounds and experiences. I listened to my work colleagues suggested approach to completing the project and I considered the best way forward that when ensure the needs of the project came first. I agreed to compromise on several areas of the project but stood my ground in the areas where I had substantial experience and expertise. After in-depth discussions, under few heated debates, we agreed on a great plan of action to ensure the project was completed on time and to the necessary standard. OK, so there's five brilliant answers to some of the hardest behavioral interview questions. Now, if you want to download those exact answers plus, my full set of 100 brilliant answers to difficult interview questions, click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintvu.com and you can download 100 outstanding top scoring answers to the most difficult interview questions. It comes as a PDF guide which means you can have it in your inbox within two minutes from now and it's going to put you ahead of the competition at your next interview. Also, please make sure you hit that subscribe button. Literally thousands of you are passing your job interviews at the very first attempt. I can only help you if you are subscribed. Please give the video a like, give it a thumbs up because that really does motivate me to create more content for you. Thank you very much indeed. And don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always a pleasure and an honour to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the very best in your pursuit to passing your interview have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0046}
{"question": "However, I thought it was important to speak out for safety reasons.", "answer": "It was my task to express my concerns with my boss in a calm and professional manner to achieve the correct outcome. I met my boss in private and explained why I felt allocating the task that a new team member was dangerous. I stated that the company had strict safety policies we should follow and if the task wasn't completed safely, our position could be compromised. I also offered an alternative solution because I'd received training in how to carry out the task safely and competently. I suggested I complete the task while the new team member observed. I also suggested we arrange safety training for the new team member which would empower them to complete all tasks moving forward. After listening to my suggestion, my manager agreed it was the correct course of action to take. Behavioral interview question number three is, tell me about a time when you dealt with a difficult situation. Here's my star method answer. In my previous job, I encountered a challenging situation with my coworker on how to approach a time-at-centitive task. We were responsible for identifying emerging trends and opportunities in our industry to support the company's growth strategy. This disagreement had the potential to affect the completion of the task within the given time frame. The responsibility fell on me to quickly resolve the issue and find a mutually beneficial way to proceed with the task. To address this situation, I initiated a productive conversation with my coworker. I began by actively listening to their proposed approach. I also articulated my own ideas and emphasised the importance of the tasks in the goal. My ideas included assessing the market leaders in the industry to see what they were doing to thrive and also using Google Trends to see what people were searching for. My colleague wanted to focus solely on feedback from previous customers. I agreed to use a combination of our best ideas as opposed to focusing on one thing we were able to complete the task and present our findings to our manager. Behavioral interview question number four is, tell me about a time when you successfully accomplished a task that was entirely new to you. Here is my star method answer. I managed to ask for a volunteer to cover the work of someone in a different department while they were off sick. I had never done their work before but was eager to help the company so I volunteered. It was my task to learn their role quickly to ensure consistency and productivity were maintained. I started by reading their job description and highlighting the tasks I was unsure about. I then studied training manuals and asked other people in the department for tips on task completion before creating a step by step checklist of what I need to do in order to complete my duties. Now although the learning curve was steep by maintaining focus double checking my work and asking for advice when needed I successfully completed their work on time and to a very high standard. Okay so there you have it fantastic answers to the most common behavioral interview questions that you use the star method. Now if you want to download the answers and accelerate your learning even further make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website passmaintoview.com and you can download my ultimate job interview preparation pack. This is a formidable resource that will put you ahead of the competition at every job interview you ever attend. When you download my ultimate job interview preparation pack you get the following items in PDF format. You will get the 17 best questions to ask in an interview. Now at the end of your job interview I recommend you are three questions or you have to do is choose three questions from the 17. You will also get my body language technique trading. I will teach you how to create a positive impression at your job interview. You also get and this is brilliant my 30 60 and 90 day plans for job interviews you will get my top 25 best words to say in your job interview you will get an interview closing statement. I will tell you what to say at the end of your interview to impress the hiring manager you also get ready-made CV and resume templates plus those answers I just gave you plus an additional 50 brilliant responses to difficult interview questions. Make sure you get these resources by clicking that link right now also. Please make sure you hit that subscribe button. I am very passionate about helping you pass your interviews and progress throughout your career. I can only do those things if you are subscribed. Please hit the like button that really does motivate me to create more videos for you. And don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always an honor and a pleasure to connect with like minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching and I wish you all the best for passing your job interview. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0045}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself here we go.", "answer": "Thank you for giving me the opportunity to be interviewed for this operation supervisor position with your company today. I would describe myself as a confident, knowledgeable and commercially driven operation supervisor who has a track record of success in previous roles. Over the years I have worked in various positions that always pushed and challenged me and that gave me the right competences and attributes to become a highly effective operation supervisor. For example in my last role I was responsible for turning around and underperforming team and I took decisive action early on in the position to streamline operational processes and procedures. I am a strong communicator and delegator. My time management skills are impeccable and I always demonstrate excellent interpersonal skills whenever dealing with team members, contractors, suppliers and stakeholders. Everything I do in my work will be geared toward helping you achieve your commercial and financial objectives and if you hire me as your operation supervisor. I will come into the role and have an immediate and positive impact. I will make sure my team operates at maximum capacity and I will deal with daily problems in a way that is always in the best interests of your company. I will give you confidence for the rest of your interview. You can either pause the video if you want to take note of the questions and answers as we work through them together. If you wait I will soon tell you where you can download my full set of 24 operations supervisor interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are covering together today.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to become an operation supervisor?", "answer": "Being an operation supervisor is challenging. You must manage multiple responsibilities, respond quickly to operational problems and also manage a team of people. It takes skill and determination to be competent in this type of role. Make sure you give valid reasons for why you want to become an operation supervisor. Here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why do you want to become an operation supervisor?", "answer": "I want to become an operation supervisor primarily because I enjoy the level of responsibility that comes with the role. In operational management there are always difficult challenges to overcome. You have to work smart and fast to achieve your objectives and there is always something new to learn. I also enjoy the people management side of being an operation supervisor. I believe I can get the most out of any team and I enjoy being the person who has ultimate responsibility for the day to day operations of an organization. Cracking answer are really good answer and you can see how these responses are going to put you ahead of the competition at your forthcoming interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to work through review. But when you're ready click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video head through to my website passmaintoview.com and you can download instantly my 24 operations supervisor interview questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are working through together today. Here's an next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are the most important skills and qualities needed to be an operation supervisor?", "answer": "Now this interview question comes up often during operation supervisor job interviews. Make sure you read the job description carefully before you attend your interview. Studying the job description will help you to understand what the employer is looking for in the successful candidate. Here's another great example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are the most important skills and qualities needed to be an operation supervisor?", "answer": "Here we go. To be a competent operation supervisor you need excellent planning, organizing and delegation capabilities, delegating tasks to team members based on their strengths is vital if you are to achieve the company's strategic objectives. Outstanding operations supervisors are brilliant communicators and listeners. They can sell their vision to their team, give instructions and messages with total clarity. And they can persuade and influence people to follow their course of action. Other important skills and qualities needed to be a competent operation supervisor include strong leadership capabilities. A versatile style of leadership to suit the situation you are facing critical thinking and problem solving skills and the ability to motivate, lead, a managed teams of people to deliver best value for the company. Another really really good answer that shows you have a thorough understanding of the different skills and qualities needed to be an outstanding operations supervisor. Here's another question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How would you deal with an underperforming member of your team?", "answer": "This is a difficult one. Now underperformance must be dealt with swiftly in your role as an operation supervisor. Make sure you give an answer that demonstrates you already have a set plan you will follow to quickly resolve team member underperformance in your role as an operation supervisor. Here's a great example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How would you deal with an underperforming member of your team?", "answer": "Here we go. I will deal with an underperforming member of my team by responding to the situation robustly and swiftly. As soon as I detected there was an issue, I would speak to the team member in private and are sent to explain the reason for their underperformance. Now this would be an important step to take because they may have personal problems they are dealing with or they may feel they haven't received the right training. I would be very surprised if their underperformance was due to a lack of motivation because I am a good motivator and mentor who can get the most out of everyone in a team. Now once I had established the reason for the underperformance, I would put a definitive plan of action in place, including the steps I wanted them to take to make the necessary improvements before monitoring them over the forthcoming weeks to make sure they get back on track quickly. Now as an operation supervisor, if you fail to deal with underperformance quickly, it can affect the entire team's performance and it also sends a message to the rest of your team that you are not a responsive and confident leader. That's a great decisive answer to that common operation supervisor interview question. Here's the next one that I strongly recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you have to make a decision without all the information you needed.", "answer": "This is a really difficult one. It's called a behavioral interview question. So this is a very difficult operation supervisor interview question to answer. My advice is to make sure you use the star technique to structure your answer. So star stands for situation, task, action and result. Let me give you a brilliant example answer that uses a star technique.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0323}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you have to make a decision without all the information you needed.", "answer": "In my last role, I received a request from another company department for a member of my team to join theirs for 14 days to work on an important time-sensitive project. The member of staff was needed due to staff sickness in the other department. I made contact with a department head to ascertain the type of skills they would need, the member of staff to have, however, she was unavailable. So I had to decide which member of staff to send them without all the information I needed. So I called another supervisor in the company who I knew had some knowledge about the project they were working on. Now he informed me that it was a technical web-based project and the majority of team members were competent IT workers and strong communicators. Now once I had this information, I then analyzed the strengths of my team and chose a member of staff to send over who I felt would add value to their project. Whenever I have to make decisions we've limited information. I will try to gather facts from other available sources before deciding on the best course of action that is in the best interest of the company. That's a great answer. It shows that you're not afraid to make a decision without having all the information to hand and you then try to get additional information from other sources. And you then use a logical approach to making the right decision. Here's an next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0078}
{"question": "How would you motivate your team as an operations supervisor?", "answer": "This is another tough operation supervisor interview question that is assessing your leadership skills. My advice is to talk about the guiding principles you always follow when motivating a team of people toward achieving a company's goals. So use those words in your answer guiding principles. Here's a brilliant example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0189}
{"question": "How would you motivate your team as an operation supervisor?", "answer": "Here we go. Whenever I motivate a team I always follow six guiding principles. Number one, I conduct performance reviews with each team member of staff to ascertain their strengths, their training needs and their ambitions. I can then motivate my team members based on their individual needs. Number two, I share my vision openly with all team members and I refer to it often during team meetings and discussions because this helps give clarity about the goals we are all working towards. Number three, I will communicate regularly with my team members without micro managing them. I will periodically check they are all okay and I will be on hand to offer advice and guidance when needed. This helps make everyone in the team feel appreciated and supported. Number four, I will create a positive working environment and also recruit a diverse workforce because diversity brings different ideas and opinions which I think is healthy. Number five, I will be honest with my team members and provide feedback and constructive criticism to help them improve because without feedback my team will not move forward. Finally, number six, I will give praise for good work and I will create opportunities for everyone in the team. That's a brilliant answer. And you are referencing six guiding principles whenever you motivate your team. I recommend you learn those because these are great management skills to have when you are undertaking your role as an operation supervisor. Here's an expression. A member of your team fails to complete a task on time and to the required standard who's to blame. Wow, this is a tricky one. Now this question again comes up often during operations supervisor interviews, but if you say the member of your team is the one who's responsible, you could fail your interview. So here's a great example response. A member of your team fails to complete a task on time and to the required standard who's to blame. As the operation supervisor, I would be responsible for this situation. It is my responsibility to lead a monitor my team and to make sure suitable resources and staff are allocated to each task to ensure it is completed on time. And to the expected standard, that's a great answer because it shows that you understand you have ultimate responsibility. It's up to you to make sure everything is done on time and to the required standard. So it shows that you take ownership of everything within your team and your job remit. Now the next thing to do is click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video head through to my website, passmaintoview.com. And you can download my full set of 24 operations supervisor interview questions and top scoring answers, including the ones we have been working through together today during this tutorial. It's a fantastic resource and it's going to put you ahead of the competition at your forthcoming interview. The very least, go through to that website and take a look at all the 24 questions I recommend you prepare for. I've also put five really important tips on that page to help you get the most out of your pre interview preparation time. Make sure you check it out. Also, don't forget to hit the subscribe button as you can see lots of people are passing their interviews and I can only help you if you are subscribed. And also by subscribing, I can help you negotiate a salary in your job interview and also gain promotion during future job interviews. Please give the video a like because that tells me you do find these tutorials useful and always motivates me to create more content for you. Thank you so much and also don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always great to connect with like-minded professionals and managers such as yourself. Thank you very much for watching and with you all the best for passing your operations supervisor job interview. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0071}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you took a risk at work.", "answer": "Here we go. Whilst working for a previous company I was concerned about the experience some of our customers were receiving. Now the career company we used to deliver products was very cost effective but they weren't very reliable. And some of our customers had complained about poor service standards. I felt it was my task to find an alternative career company that could help improve customer service standards. Now after researching new careers I found one that promised exceptional service standards. Now the only issue was they were twice as expensive as the previous career.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However I felt this was a risk worth taking because I believed that by improving customer service standards it would result in better feedback online which would then in turn attract new customers.", "answer": "And offset the additional expense of the new career. So I decided to take the risk and we signed up with the new career. Literally four weeks after using the new career online positive reviews increased significantly and this attracted new business. And three months later new customer revenue had overtaken the cost of the new career meaning the risk had a positive outcome. So that's a really good example answer to that first Amazon leadership principle interview question tell me about the time when you took a risk at work. And that's based on the think big Amazon leadership principle and you can see that by using that process the start technique situation task action and result you are able to construct a brilliant top scoring answer. Now don't go anywhere because I still have many more questions and top scoring answers to give you. But when you're ready click the link in the top right and corner of the video head through to my website passmaintevue.com and you can download my full set of Amazon leadership principles into your questions and top scoring answers including the ones we are working through together today.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.01}
{"question": "However here is the next question for you.", "answer": "Next on the leadership principle of dive deep and the question is tell me about a time when you used information or data to make a decision. Let me give you my example answer again that utilizes the start technique here we go. In a previous role I was part of a team whose responsibility it was to launch a new company product online. Now it was our task to use data and information to increase return on investment from the initial product marketing campaign. Now before attending the first follow up meeting after the initial product launch I conducted some research into the results from the online marketing campaign. Now I noticed that certain keywords and phrases were not converting which resulted in unnecessary expenditure. Now during the team meeting I presented a list of keywords and phrases that were converting and I recommended we increased the advertising spend for those campaigns whilst at the same time deleting the ones that brought no return. Now the team agreed this was a great idea to implement immediately and after analyzing the results seven days later our sales had increased by 15%. That's a really good specific example of where somebody has del deep into information and data to make a decision that's in the best interest of the organization. And again it utilizes the start technique so it's a really good format to use when preparing for your Amazon interview. Let's now move on and take a look at the next Amazon leadership principle interview question and this is based on the leadership principle of think big.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0037}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when the organization you were working for adopted one of your ideas.", "answer": "Now this is a difficult question but Amazon being in my opinion the greatest company in the world wants to employ people who can come up with really good ideas. That's going to help their organization move forward. Let me give you an example answer. So the question again is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0196}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when the organization you were working for adopted one of your ideas here we go.", "answer": "In my previous job I felt the prices we sold our products for were too cheap. The products were created to a high standard but I felt the cheap prices were putting off some customers due to perceived value. Now it was my task to present my suggestion to my manager based on evidence. So I put together a short presentation that included my ideas and examples of other companies in different sectors that took advantage of increased prices that reflected the standard of their products. I then presented my idea to my manager. Now he was reluctant to change the pricing model that we had used for several years. So I suggested we should try increasing the prices on one or two products initially to gauge the reaction to which he agreed. Now 14 days after increasing the prices we assessed the data and we had actually sold 37 more products compared to the previous period. Now it proved that the cheaper prices were putting off some customers. So we ended up rolling out the idea to all company products which helped to significantly increase company revenue over the year. So that's a really good example of someone who has come up with a really good idea that has improved the performance and the efficiency of an organisation. And again, as you can see, it utilizes a start technique. Let's move on to the next question which again is based on the dive deep Amazon leadership principle. And the question is, tell me about a time when you had to delve deeper into information or data to come up with a suitable solution to a problem. This is a really difficult interview question. A difficult Amazon interview question to answer correctly. Let me give you my example response. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0164}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to delve deeper into information or data to come up with a suitable solution to a problem.", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous job, I was concerned that sales were starting to drop compared to the previous year. It was my task to delve deep into the information I had available to produce actionable strategies that would quickly result in increased sales. So I gave an information and data from various sources including marketing campaign results, lead generation and retention rates, Google trends and website visitors. So starting with the marketing campaign results, I quickly established these work converting at the previous year's results based on the same expenditure. Google trends indicated that based on seasonal demand, this was the same year on year. I then moved on to the number of website visitors we were receiving and the figures were healthy and in keeping with the previous year's figures.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0148}
{"question": "However, when I came to analyze lead generation and retention rates, these were down by 30%.", "answer": "Now upon further inspection of the data, I found that website leads were unsubscribing within two days of the initial sign-up. Now the reason for this was that the email campaign assigned to the new online leads contained an error that resulted in a loss of trust between the lead and the company. Now once I had spoken to the IT department, the error was quickly rectified. After analyzing the results 28 days later, website leads were being retained one small and sales had started to increase back up to the previous years levels. So that's a really good example, Answer. To that question, tell me about a time when you had to delve deeper into information or data to come up with a suitable solution. And I like that answer because you are using an assessing lots of different sources of information and data and you are basically eliminating the ones that are fine and you eventually find where the problem is and you come up with a really good solution for the business. So that shows that you can dive deep. Let's now move on to the next Amazon leadership principles interview question. This again is think big and the question is tell me about a time when you used a radical approach to solve a problem. Now the key word here is radical. It doesn't say tell me about a time when you, you know, solve the problem. It's a used a radical approach. So you have to come up with something that's unique and different. And again, one that contains a little bit of a risk. You need to try risks because risks can often lead to reward within organizations. So here's my example answer that again utilizes that start technique to the Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0228}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you used a radical approach to solve a problem.", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous job, all team members were required to attend meetings regardless of whether they were really needed or not. So I calculated that this was a significant waste of some people's time and a new approach was needed. I decided to explore different options for holding team meetings with a view to radicalising the process to increase productivity levels. So after thinking of different ideas, I came up with a simple solution. It was a very basic idea, but one that radicalised company meetings moving forward. Once the meeting agenda was disseminated amongst everyone in the group, I stated that attendance at the meeting was purely voluntary. If people felt their attendance at the meeting was not warranted, and their time could be better allocated elsewhere, they did not need to attend. Now at the end of every meeting, action points would be sent to all staff, whether they attended the meeting or not. And it would be their responsibility to action them before the start of the next meeting. It also meant that those people who attended company meetings were empowered to contribute in a positive and fruitful manner. Now this radical approach to company meetings had a significant impact on staff morale and productivity levels. That's another great example. The shows you're not afraid to take a risk and you're capable of coming up with a radical approach to something that you think needs changing. And as a positive outcome, so it's a really good example answer. Now the next thing to do is you want more Amazon leadership principles, interview questions and answers. Including the ones I've covered today during this tutorial is to make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video head through to my website, passmaintoview.com and you can download my full set of Amazon leadership principles, interview questions, and the example answers that's going to help you prepare fully for your forthcoming Amazon interview. Make sure you check that out. Finally, don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I've put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always good to connect with like, mining, professional, such as yourself.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0104}
{"question": "Don't forget to subscribe to the channel.", "answer": "I can then help you progress throughout your career. I can help you pass every job interview you ever attend. And also help you to negotiate the right salary that you deserve. And don't forget to give the video a like. It's a small ask, but it really does motivate me to create more content for you. Thank you so much. For watching and for paying attention, and I wish you all the best for passing your Amazon interview. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0235}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Here we go. Thank you for this opportunity to become an area manager with Amazon. Before I applied, I studied the job description to ensure I have the skills, leadership qualities and experience to meet the roles demands. I am a strong communicator, can motivate people to achieve important deadlines and will take the lead during challenges to ensure Amazon's commercial and strategic goals are achieved. I am a high achiever. In my last job, I was prayed for completing all projects on time and suggesting ideas to help streamline processes and systems to improve efficiency. I have taken a keen interest in Amazon's leadership principles and will ensure these are the foundation of all my decisions in this role. My relevant experience in people management, building relationships with stakeholders and using data to make informed decisions will ensure I am a productive and effective area manager for Amazon. And I look forward to sharing additional details regarding my suitability for this position in the interview. So that is a really good example answer to that first Amazon area manager interview question tell me about yourself. Now you can either pause the video if you want to and write down the questions, tips and answers as we work through them together or if you wait, I will soon tell you where you can instantly download my full set of 24 brilliant exam palancers to difficult Amazon area manager interview questions. Now here is the next question that I strongly recommend you prepare for. My Amazon or they might say why do you want to work for Amazon. Here's two really important tips. Tip number one. So this next common interview question is assessing your motivations for wanting to work for this brilliant organization. My opinion is that Amazon is the greatest organization in the world. That is why area manager positions are sought after. Make sure you give a genuine response to this question. So you must demonstrate a genuine desire for wanting to work at Amazon in your answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0087}
{"question": "But how do you do that?", "answer": "Well good things to include in your response are, Amazon's impressive track record of success, then this means you will be working for a higher achieving organization. Amazon's 16 leadership principles and how these will be the foundation of your work as an area manager and the fact that Amazon is a company that takes calculated risks. Now in my opinion the best organizations in the world take calculated risks to be successful. And that is one of the appealing reasons why I would want to work for Amazon. So here is a brilliant top scoring example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0097}
{"question": "Why Amazon?", "answer": "I want to work for Amazon because of its track record of success, leadership principles and calculated risk taking. Amazon's impressive track record and growth trajectory give me the confidence. I will be working for a senior management team that will support me to achieve great things in my work. I believe in Amazon's 16 leadership principles. They will make my work more enjoyable while giving me structure and the set of standards for myself are my team to adhere to. Finally, organizations like Amazon can only succeed by taking calculated risks. Because Amazon invests in new ideas, embraces opportunities and puts its customers at the core of its work, I am confident this is a place I can build along and successful career. So that is another brilliant confident answer that will help you pass your Amazon area manager interview. Now don't go anywhere because I still have many more tips, questions and sample answers to give you. But when you're ready, you can click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, pass my interview.com, and instantly download my 24 brilliant answers to difficult Amazon area manager interview questions. But here is the next question that I strongly recommend you prepare for. That question is, tell me about a time you improved a process or made a customer focused decision. Tip number one. Now the majority of your Amazon area manager interview will be focused on answering behavioral interview questions that are centered on the 16 leadership principles. Tip number two, now when answering these challenging behavioral interview questions, I strongly recommend you use the star method. Let me quickly explain what the star method is before I give you my brilliant example answer. The star method stands for situation, task, action and result. So you begin your answer and you outline the situation you were faced with. Next, you will give brief details about the task that needed your attention. You will then give in-depth details about the action you took to complete the task before finally finishing your answer with the results following your actions and you should always make sure the results are positive. So let's now move on and have a look at a brilliant example answer to this question that uses the star method, situation, task, action and result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.01}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you improved a process or made a customer focused decision.", "answer": "In my last job, I closely monitored customer reviews, a noticed several negative comments citing a delay in order delivery. My task was to investigate this problem to ensure customer service standards did not deteriorate further. I contacted the customers who had left negative comments to first apologize and ask them questions about their experience with the company. They all informed me they had placed orders through our website, but there had been an unacceptable delay in receiving their orders. After investigating the problem further, I established that one of the company's suppliers was experiencing supply chain issues resulting in delivery delays. I decided to quickly source an alternative supplier who could offer improved terms for the company. After deciding to switch suppliers, excellent service standards resumed and all orders were delivered promptly. So that is another really good answer that uses that star method of situation, task, action and result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0066}
{"question": "The next question I recommend you prepare for in advance of your Amazon area manager interview is what's your leadership style?", "answer": "Tip number one. Now as an Amazon area manager, you will be a leader who must direct control and motivate a team of people. So be sure to know what your leadership style is before your interview and tip number two, there are several leadership styles including Democratic or to-cratic where you tell people what you want doing and by when. Lacer Fair Leadership which is a relaxed leadership style, I personally do not think Lacer Fair is a good leadership style for working at Amazon. A transformational leadership style where you and your team embrace change and also a coaching style of leadership. So here is my example answer. This is exactly how I would answer this difficult but common Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.016}
{"question": "What's your leadership style?", "answer": "My leadership style is a combination of or to-cratic transformational and coaching. When my team and I are up against tight deadlines, I will be or to-cratic and provide clear and confident instructions on what needs doing and by when. I am a transformational leader who believes in the importance of change. I will encourage my team to embrace change positively and explain its benefits and finally I am a leader who provides regular training and coaching to ensure my team members reach their full potential. So you can see how these answers will help you prepare fully for your Amazon area manager interview that is a really good confident answer. Here is the next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0085}
{"question": "Describe a situation when you had to act quickly under pressure.", "answer": "Tip number one. Now this next difficult Amazon area manager interview question is assessing the leadership principles of bias for action and ownership. And tip number two, I recommend you give a specific situation in which you took decisive action to achieve a positive outcome despite being under pressure. Again, make sure you use the star method situation, task action and result to structure your answer. So here is another brilliant top scoring example answer to help you pass your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0123}
{"question": "Describe a situation when you had to act quickly under pressure.", "answer": "Here we go. In my last job and important client contacted me to say they were not renewing their contract with they had received a better offer from one of our direct competitors. My task was to act quickly to determine the best offer we could make to the client to retain their business. I asked the client to meet me that day to which they agreed. On the way to the meeting, I assessed the terms of their current contract and created a list of questions I wanted to ask them. And anticipating what their answers might be, I drafted two improved contract offers that I felt were in the best interests of the client and my employer. During the meeting, I asked the client questions about their needs and listened carefully to their answers. At the end of the meeting, I presented the client with a new and improved contract offer that met their needs. After considering the new contract offer, they contacted me to say they would accept it which was a great result for the company. So that is a really good example situation where you are under pressure and you have to act quickly. You have prepared alternative contract offers and you have drafted up a set of questions you will ask the client at the meeting. So you are taking decisive action to retain the client's business. Here is the next question. This is another behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0082}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you found a simple solution to a complex problem.", "answer": "This question comes up all the time during Amazon area manager interviews. Tip number one. So as an area manager for Amazon, you will have to overcome challenging situations on a regular basis. So this next behavioral question assesses your ability to act quickly to create solutions that ensure Amazon's operations can continue successfully. And tip number two, give a specific situation where you assess the situation that was causing problems for your employer before creating a simple solution. Here is another brilliant example answer. Again, the use is the star method. Situation, task action and result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0204}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you found a simple solution to a complex problem.", "answer": "Here we go. In my previous job, we had an ongoing problem with communication. Updates on projects and task delegation were becoming increasingly difficult as the company expanded. I decided to find a simple solution to this issue. After researching online for the best workplace communication and productivity tools, I put together a short presentation on a tool called Evernote. Evernote would empower managers and team members to keep everyone updated on task and project progression. After watching my presentation, my manager agreed to its implementation and within several weeks Evernote became a fundamental part of our workplace productivity scheduling and task management. So that is another great answer that shows you take decisive action to find a simple solution to a difficult problem. It's a really good example answer. Okay, now the next thing to do to accelerate your learning even further and make sure you are fully prepared for your Amazon area manager interview is click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintoview.com where you can instantly download these slides plus my full set of 24 brilliant answers to Amazon area manager interview questions. This guide comes as a PDF document which means you can have everything in your inbox within two minutes from now. Make sure you go through to that website, passmaintoview by clicking that link because on the page, I have also given you three questions. I recommend you ask at the end of your area manager interview. Also, please make sure you hit that subscribe button, give the video alike and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an honor and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professional such as yourself. Thank you very much for watching and for supporting my channel. I wish you all the very best for passing your Amazon area manager interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0059}
{"question": "Don't forget, Amazon will be assessing your communication skills at the interview.", "answer": "So if you give structured answers, it definitely helps you to be successful. Now when you answer, tell me about yourself at an Amazon interview. I recommend you talk about the skills you have that align with the job description. The experience you can bring to Amazon details of any significant accomplishment you have attained in your career. And then finally, the type of person you are and what you will do in your work to help Amazon continue to be successful. You will notice that those four things stand for seat SEAT and you can easily remember my seat structure for tell me about yourself because you will be sat down on a seat at your Amazon interview. And this structure works for all Amazon interviews, whether it's an in person face to face interview, a telephone interview or an online interview. Just remember you are sat down on a seat and they will say to you, tell me about yourself, remember S E A T. Let me now give you a brilliant example, seat structure answer to this first Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0054}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Here we go. Thank you for this opportunity to work at Amazon. My top skills which include taking ownership, customer focus, collaboration, innovative problem solving and data driven decision making are a great match for the Amazon job description. I have experienced working on small and large teams, multitasking, launching company products and delivering outstanding customer service. I am a high achiever. In my last position, I helped create a standardized training program for new company highers and I was praised by my manager for how I always asked customers for feedback so we could improve. In addition to being competent in the use of Microsoft Office applications and job-specific software tools, I have completed training courses in health and safety awareness, customer service and artificial intelligence. If you hire me, I will demonstrate the 16 leadership principles in my work, obsess about customers to ensure Amazon remains the industry leader and take on feedback to ensure I add value to my team and I look forward to sharing additional details in the interview, regarding my suitability for Amazon and this position. That is a fantastic structure answer to that first Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0051}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself and you can see how effective my seat structure is.", "answer": "Now don't go anywhere because I still have lots more tips, questions and sample answers to give you, but when you are ready, you can download my brilliant Amazon interview success pack by clicking that link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Let's move on to the second generic motivational Amazon interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why Amazon? Or they might say to you, why do you want to work at Amazon?", "answer": "You must give genuine reasons why you want to work for this fantastic organization. In my opinion, it's the greatest company in the world. Lots of people want to work there, but not necessarily for the right reasons. Good things to say in your answer include the following right these down. The fact that you genuinely believe in their 16 leadership principles. Now earlier on in the video, I said to you that at some stage during your Amazon interview, you will have to answer leadership principles, questions, Amazon has 16 leadership principles. They are core to the organization's success. You need to learn them and understand them before you attend your interview. Later on in this video, I will explain what they are. So you can say you want to work at Amazon because you genuinely believe in their 16 leadership principles. Other good things to say in your answer include the training opportunities Amazon provides employees are fantastic. They really want to help you progress in your career and gain new skills. Finally, you can say how you will get to collaborate on innovative and cutting edge projects while working at Amazon. So that means you will get to utilize your best skills, learn new ones and collaborate with other ambitious and motivated people because don't forget Amazon are always pushing the boundaries to meet the needs of their customers.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0085}
{"question": "So let me now give you another brilliant example answer this time to the common Amazon interview question, why Amazon?", "answer": "Here we go. I want to work at Amazon for three reasons. First, you have been the industry leader for several decades and I put that down to your leadership principles. The principles are ones that I believe in and the fact that you push the boundaries of innovation means I will have the opportunity to collaborate on challenging and exciting projects that enhance customers' lives. I will find that aspect of working at Amazon to be very rewarding. Second, you value your employees' ideas. I have a lot to offer the right employer and I'm eager to contribute to a business's success when my ideas are encouraged and trialed, I feel valued in my work. And finally, I want to work at Amazon because you provide excellent skills training opportunities. I am hungry to learn and diversify my skills and my research tells me, Amazon will help me to achieve my professional development goals. That is a very strong answer because you are not just giving one reason why you want to work for this brilliant organization you are giving three.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget to give your answer with passion.", "answer": "Now the second type of question that features in and Amazon interview, these ones are very difficult to answer. They are called leadership principles. Now Amazon, as I previously stated, has a set of 16 leadership principles that are designed to guide decision making, behaviour and company culture at every level of the organization. Now these principles are used to drive consistency across Amazon, influence hiring and promotion decisions and also support customer centric thinking. Let me quickly explain what these leadership principles are and I will then give you some sample questions, a structure to use and some unique responses. So the 16 Amazon leadership principles are as follows. Invent and simplify. This means create new products and services and also make things simple. They are and develop the best people and they also want employees of Amazon to coach a motivate their coworkers. If you can help train a coworker, you should do it. Insist on the highest standards. That principle speaks for itself. You always must aim for the highest standards achievable. All right, a lot. This means you make the right decisions in the best interests of Amazon. I've to be the Earth's best employer. That speaks for itself. Ownership, this is an important leadership principle. It means you take ownership for things. You don't leave problems for other people to deal with. You take ownership of them. Deliver results. Again, that speaks for itself. You always focus on delivering results. You don't put things off. You get things done. Think big. Think bigger than your competitors. Have a big vision. Regality, which means cost consciousness. You look ways not just to increase sales, but to help Amazon save money. Dive deep. This means you analyze information, facts, and evidence to create better decisions. Success and scale bring broad responsibility because Amazon is so big. It has lots of responsibilities and they take those seriously. Learn and be curious. This means that you are always looking to improve. There is always something you to learn. Buyers for action. This means you take action. You take calculated risks. You get things done. Have backbone, disagree, and commit. This means that you are not afraid to challenge people in a calm and professional manner if you think something can be done in an alternative way. You also earn trust. You need to earn the trust of your managers and coworkers. Now you will notice that I have given you 15 leadership principles. There is another one. I believe personally that this next leadership principle is the most important. Now of course everyone who works at Amazon will say all of the leadership principles are just as important as each other. They are correct. But there is one that I believe is absolutely vital. The 16th leadership principle is customer obsession. Amazon obsesses over its customers. For example, I don't work at Amazon. But I love the company. In fact, in the last 12 months alone, I have ordered more than 400 goods and products from Amazon. I think they are brilliant. The reason why I think Amazon are so good is because they make things simple. Their website is easy to use. But more importantly, their delivery is outstanding. I can get things either the same day or the next day. They understand how important customers are to the success of their organization. And that is why they are the market leader, the industry leader because they obsess about their customers. Now when you answer any of the Amazon leadership principles into few questions, I recommend you use the following structure. To begin with, tell the interviewer the situation you were in. You will then move on and explain the task, then you need your attention, then give in-depth details of the action you took to achieve the task and then finish off your answer by telling the Amazon hiring manager the result following your actions. You will notice that that structure stands for star, STAR, CIT, AR, situation, task, action and result. So whenever you answer any of the Amazon leadership principles into few questions, use the star method. Okay, let's start working through some of these leadership principles into few questions. Let's have a look at earn trust. A simple question would be, tell me about your time. You had to influence without authority. This is a difficult question, but it comes up all the time.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0053}
{"question": "Tell me about your time.", "answer": "You had to influence someone in your company without authority. This is the leadership principle, earn trust. Let me give you a star method answer and then you will understand how earning trust is vital at Amazon. Here we go. We have to tell you about your time. You had to influence without authority. I attended a team meeting in my previous role to discuss the progress of a project for an important company client. During the meeting, a long-serving team member made the recommendation that we cut corners on the project to save time and money. They argued that the client wouldn't be aware we had cut corners and we could make considerable savings. Several people in the meeting agreed this was a good idea.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, I disagreed.", "answer": "My task was to ask appropriate questions to persuade the meeting that this was a terrible idea with significant risks. I asked the meeting two questions. The first question was, how would we feel if we were the client who had paid good money for a specific service, but later found out that the company had cut corners without consulting us. The second question was, if the client found out that we had not delivered the project as contractually agreed, what damage could be done to our company. My two questions had the desired impact. Everyone quickly agreed it was not a good idea to alter the project specification or timeline, but to find alternative and legitimate ways to reduce costs. That is a really good in-depth answer. You are telling a story about it time. You were able to influence other people without authority. You are not the manager, but you are cleverly asking the meeting questions to change their minds about a course of action. That meets the Amazon leadership principle of earned trust. We have now covered earned trust. Let's take a look at our right a lot. A question will be, tell me about a time when you noted something was off and you fixed it.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you noticed something was off and you fixed it.", "answer": "Even though this question aligns with the leadership principle of our right a lot, so you make the right decision, you notice something is not right and you do something about it. So meets other leadership principles of again bias fraction, but also ownership. You notice something is wrong and you take ownership to fix it. Let me give you a star method answer. Situation task action and result. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0278}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you noticed something was off and you fixed it.", "answer": "In my previous job, I noticed the company had received several negative online reviews via trust pilot. I read the reviews and both customers cited late delivery of their products. Now because I understood how important excellent customer service is to the success of a company, especially in a highly competitive industry, I decided to investigate. I called each customer to apologize and to ask several questions about their experience.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "The questions I asked were, what delivery time we have promised and how did the experience make you feel about the company?", "answer": "Both customers stated that they had paid for premium fast track delivery, but they had received standard delivery service instead. They also said that they would not use our company again due to a lack of trust. I thank them for their honest feedback, apologize once more and promised to refund their delivery fees. Then started to investigate the issue around premium delivery. I placed an order through our website for premium delivery, but like the customers who complained, I received the standard service. I immediately contacted our career company to request that they investigate the issue. I provided them with three examples of premium delivery failures. After 24 hours, they admitted that a member of their dispatch team had been incorrectly placing premium delivery products in standard delivery dispatch lines. After informing my manager about my findings, we agreed that trust had been lost with the career company. Following the sourcing of a new one on improved terms, customer service improved. As a gesture of goodwill, I contacted the two customers again to explain how the issue had happened and I offered them a 25% discount on their next order. That is another brilliant example answer. You can see our effective, the star method really is for answering leadership principles into view questions. I've still got more questions and answers to give you, but I also have another brilliant product and service that will help you share your Amazon interview. It's called my advanced AI coach for Amazon interviews. This is a fantastic software tool. You access it directly from your phone, laptop or computer and you can ask it any questions you want about your Amazon interview and get an instant answer direct from me. This is a brilliant resource. You can try it free for seven days by clicking that link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Back to the training. We have now looked at, earned trust and all right, a lot. Let's now take a look at the next Amazon leadership principles interview question, bias for action. Getting things done. The question is, describe a time you made the right decision despite having limited information. This question features all the time at Amazon interviews, bias for action. Let me give you a brilliant sample answer using the star method. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0025}
{"question": "Describe a time you made the right decision despite having limited information.", "answer": "In my previous role, I was part of a team, tasked with launching a new company product. A significant amount of time effort and resources, sorry, resources had gone into creating the product and it was our duty to launch it using relevant marketing campaigns that attracted our target audience. We needed to spend time conducting market research to ensure our campaigns would be effective. We'd allocated two weeks for market research. Now unfortunately, we received news that a competitor was about to launch a similar product which resulted in a decision having to be made, whether to stick with our market research strategy or launch immediately. After careful consideration, and understanding the power of being first to market, we decided to bring forward the launch date. We held an emergency team meeting to discuss the best marketing strategies despite having limited information. I suggested we use chatGPT to establish our target audience. The platforms they most frequently use and the different types of adverse we could test for the highest return on investment. Other team members recommended that we use offline marketing methods to boost exposure and also generate free PR. We launched the product 48 hours before our competitor. After seven days, we had exceeded the previous company's best product launch by 17% which was a testament to the team taking a calculated risk to beat our competitors' launch. Another great example answer that will help you pass your Amazon leadership principles interview. You will notice that these answers are in depth. If I were attending an Amazon interview, I would want to give lots of stories about situations I have been in where I meet the leadership principles. Now the next thing to do, if you want more great answers, sample answers to Amazon leadership principles is click that link in the top right-end corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passmaintube.com, and you can download my Amazon interview success pack. You will get my sample Amazon interview score sheet. I have created a score sheet based on how I believe you will be assessed at your Amazon interview. I have 30 years experience as a recruitment expert and hiring manager. This sheet is how I believe you will be assessed. It's a great preparation tool. You will also get 21 Amazon interview questions and answers that cover lots of different motivational and generic Amazon questions and you will also get 16 Amazon leadership principles into view answers. The answers that I've given you in this training video plus a whole lot more to get all of this. Click that link. Thank you very much for watching my name is Richard McMunn. I am one of the world's leading job interview coaches. Thousands of you are getting hired. You can connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below to video. Give the video a thumbs up and most importantly please subscribe. It's a very small ask. I am on a mission to help as many people get hired as possible. I can only help you if you are subscribed. I am here to help you throughout your career. Thank you for listening and I wish you the very best for passing your Amazon interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "I don't make mistakes, so that situation would never happen. That is the worst possible answer to the interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0476}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake and don't use this answer either to be honest working for my previous employer was a mistake.", "answer": "There was a toxic environment in the office and I couldn't wait to leave. So there's two really bad answers to that difficult behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0357}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake. But how do you answer it without failing your job interview?", "answer": "Well, if you have an interview coming up soon for any role-all company, please make sure you stay tuned because I promise to help you be the standout candidates. And just for equally, if you're on you to the channel, please make sure you hit that subscribe button. I can then help you not just pass every job interview you ever attend. I can help you tune negotiate to salary and progress throughout your career. And please give the video a like because that tells me you find these tutorials useful. Thank you very much. Let's jump straight into the presentation. So to help you pass your job interview, I will cover the following three things during this tutorial. Number one, I will explain why the interviewer is asking you the behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0146}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake.", "answer": "Now, if you understand why the question is being asked, it enables you to give the perfect answer. Number two, I will then tell you how to structure your answer to this interview question to get the highest scores possible. And then finally, number three, I will give you a brilliant example answer in a live interview. To the question, tell me about a time when you made a mistake that is guaranteed to impress the hiring manager. So why is the interviewer asking you the question, tell me about a time when you made a mistake. Well, they are asking you this question for two reasons. Reason number one is because they want to assess whether you are honest about any mistakes you have made. If you say that you have never made a mistake in your life, you are not being honest. We all make mistakes, but it is how you respond to the mistakes you make that is important. And reason number two, why they are asking you the question, tell me about a time when you made a mistake. It's because they want to hear that you took ownership of your mistake. You are apologise to for it if necessary and you then took positive steps to learn from the experience. So let me now tell you how to structure your answer to the interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0087}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you made a mistake and I will then give you a brilliant example answer in a live interview.", "answer": "So I strongly recommend you structure your answer to this and any other behavioral interview question by using the star technique. The star technique stands for situation, task, action and result. So first you start off your answer and you tell the interview at the situation you were faced with. You then briefly outline the task that needed doing. You then move on and give details about the action you took to achieve the task before finally telling the interviewer the results following your actions. So let me now give you a brilliant example answer in a live interview. To the question tell me about a time when you made a mistake. Here we go. Okay Richard, tell me about a time when you made a mistake. When I first started work in my previous role, my manager asked for a volunteer to complete an important time at sensitive task and I agreed to be that person. Now the task involved collecting 12 months worth of company sales figures which my manager needed for an important presentation she was going to give to the senior management team. When I started work on the task, I soon realized I had underestimated how long it was going to take me to complete it. Now because of my mistake, I had to stay behind late after working, chaining and commit extra hours to get the job finished on time. Moving forward, I made sure I never made the same mistake again. I considered carefully each task I was responsible for and I took the time to determine the exact amount of hours and resources it would take me to finish it. So the next thing to do, if you want to accelerate your learning even further and pass your interview, click that link in the top right-hand corner of the video, head through to my website passmaintivue.com and you can download instantly my full set of 27.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0123}
{"question": "Tell me about a time, behavioral interview questions and top scoring answers.", "answer": "It's a fantastic resource and it's guaranteed to put you ahead of the competition at your fourth coming interview. Finally, don't forget to hit that subscribe button. I can then help you pass every job interview you ever attend and also progress throughout your career. Please give the video a like and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video and it is always an honour and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and I wish you all the best. For passing your job interview, have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0261}
{"question": "Tell me about the time you worked under pressure. Tell me about the time you had to overcome a challenging problem. Tell me about the time you made a mistake and tell me about the time you had a conflict with a coworker.", "answer": "When you answer these and other difficult behavioral interview questions you must give a specific situation you have previously been in where you demonstrate the competency that is being assessed in the question. Now there is a recognized structure you must use when answering behavioral interview questions. Let me tell you what that structure is. The best structure to use when answering behavioral interview questions is called the star method. S T A R. The star method is recognized by all hiring managers as the best way to answer difficult behavioral interview questions. So whenever you are answering one of these questions you must start your answer by telling the hiring manager the situation you were faced with. You will then move on and give brief details about the task that needed your attention. You will then give in depth details about the action you took to complete the task before finishing your answer by revealing the results following your actions and it is important to make sure the results are always positive. So let's now start working through my brilliant star method answers to the most common interview questions. Here we go. Behavioral interview question number one is tell me about a time you worked on a team give a specific situation where you collaborated closely with your coworkers to achieve the team's goal. Here is a brilliant star method answer for you to write down and practice.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0083}
{"question": "Tell me about your time you worked on a team.", "answer": "During an online sales event our four person team faced a challenge when a supplier ran out of stock for a popular product that had already sold over 100 units. This created an urgent need to find a solution to fulfill orders and manage customer expectations. Our team was responsible for quickly sourcing a new supplier, communicating with affected customers and preventing similar issues in the future. We divided the tasks strategically. I took the lead in researching and contacting alternative suppliers while another team member negotiated pricing and delivery terms. The third team member drafted a clear and empathetic message for customers explaining the slight delay while the fourth team member updated order timelines in our system. We collaborated closely checking progress regularly to ensure alignment and swift action. We secured a new supplier within 24 hours maintained customer trust with proactive communication and established backup suppliers for future events preventing similar issues. That was a brilliant answer and you can see how effective the star method is. Let's move on to behavioral interview question number two which is tell me about a time you worked on the pressure. This question is being asked to assess how you prioritize and organize your work when you are under pressure. Here is my brilliant star method answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you worked on the pressure.", "answer": "At my previous company, I stepped in to cover a co-workers duties from another department who was off-sick. This doubled my workload and required me to manage responsibilities across two roles to ensure all tasks and projects were completed on time. My primary challenge was to maintain the same high standards in both roles while meeting deadlines avoiding disruptions to the team and delivering value to the company. To handle the pressure, I prioritised my tasks into urgent, important and non-eurogent categories. I blocked out distractions by setting specific time blocks for focused work, informed colleagues of my availability and worked additional hours in the evenings when necessary. Despite the increased workload, I successfully completed all projects on schedule, maintain quality standards and received praise from my manager for ensuring smooth operations during the co-workers absence. This experience strengthened my time management and problem-solving skills. Behavioral interview question number three we need to cover is tell me about the time you had to overcome a challenging problem. This question assesses two things resilience and problem solving capabilities. Here is my star method answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about the time you had to overcome a challenging problem.", "answer": "In my previous role, I noticed that some customers were receiving inconsistent and unprofessional responses from our team which led to a drop in customer satisfaction and occasional negative reviews. It became clear that the team lacked formal customer service training which was causing these issues. I felt it was crucial to address this challenge to ensure our communication met professional standards and helped retain customers. My goal was to find a solution that would improve the team's customer service skills and positively impact the business. I researched various online customer service training courses focusing on those with strong reviews and relevant content. After shortlisting a few, I prepared a proposal for my manager, detailing the benefits of each course and highlighting how improved skills would lead to better customer retention and positive reviews. The training was approved and implemented leading to a noticeable improvement in the team's communication consistency and professionalism. Within a month, customer satisfaction scores rose by 20% and we received significantly more positive feedback from clients. Behavioral interview question number four is a really difficult one to answer. That question is tell me about a time you made a mistake.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Do not make the mistake of saying to the hiring manager, I never make mistakes.", "answer": "I have not been in this situation because I am a perfectionist. If you say that, you will fail your interview. The truth is we all make mistakes from time to time, but it is how we react to the mistake that is being assessed with this question. Here is my brilliant star method answer for you to write down and practice.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a mistake.", "answer": "In my first job, I was enrolled in an internal training course that was essential for my role. I had some prior knowledge of the subject and, over confidently, assumed I didn't need to study as much as I should have. My goal was to pass the course and demonstrate my competence in the area.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, my lack of preparation led me to just failing the assessment.", "answer": "I immediately took responsibility and apologized to my manager explaining where I went wrong. I asked for the opportunity to retake the course and committed to studying diligently. Over the next few weeks, I made a comprehensive study plan, reviewed the material thoroughly, and sought advice from colleagues who had passed the course. I passed the reset with the high score and gained a much deeper understanding of the subject. This experience taught me the critical importance of preparation which I now apply to every situation at work. Behavioral interview question number five is, tell me about a time you had a conflict with a coworker. Conflict happens in the workplace all the time, but this question is assessing whether you are professional in resolving the conflict and you take responsibility for it to help the team progress. Here is my brilliant star method answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had a conflict with a coworker.", "answer": "In a previous role, a coworker made inappropriate comments about a new team member which I found unprofessional and concerning for the team's dynamic. I felt it was important to address the behavior promptly to ensure our work place remained respectful and inclusive. My goal was to handle the situation professionally while helping my coworker understand the impact of their words. I approached the coworker privately and expressed my concerns calmly and respectfully. I explained why their comments were inappropriate and emphasise the importance of maintaining professionalism and respect in the workplace. When they became defensive, I stood firm, but empathetic, focusing on educating them rather than criticising. After our conversation, the coworker reflected on their behavior, a apologise to me and made efforts to improve. This not only strengthened our team's respect, but also reinforced a positive and professional work environment. Okay, so there you have it brilliant example answers to difficult behavioral interview questions that use the star method. The next thing to do to accelerate your learning even further is watch me pass a behavioral interview. You can watch me pass this real interview by clicking the link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. And if you want to accelerate your learning even further, you can download my 27 brilliant answers to difficult behavioral interview questions that use the star method. You can have this guide in your inbox within two minutes from now by clicking that link in the top right hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website to passmainerveu.com and you can have this guide literally within two minutes from now. It will help you pass every job interview you ever attend. Also, please make sure you hit that subscribe button, give the video make sure you connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an honour and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professional such as yourself. Thank you very much for watching and I wish you the very best for passing your interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0056}
{"question": "Describe a time when you made a mistake. What did you learn from that experience?", "answer": "That's a behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "But what's the best way to answer?", "answer": "Welcome to the interview game, by indeed.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Where we show you how and how not to answer interview questions.", "answer": "The hiring manager is dialing in. Yes! Hi Bill. I understand you need to hire a new bartender. I sure do. I run a bart downtown and I need someone who's experienced in a real problem solve. Got it. So I'll ask some behavioral based questions. Then I can see how each candidate's past experience relates to the role you're hiring for. Strong answers should follow this star format.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0137}
{"question": "Candidates! Are you ready?", "answer": "Yes! Jessica, you're up first. Tell us about a time when you made a mistake and what you learned from it. In my last job, I was responsible for processing returns. One customer ordered the same outfit in a bunch of different sizes. She kept one and returned the rest. But I credited too much money back into her account. My manager was pretty frustrated. The whole situation really turned me off from working in online sales. Which is one of the reasons I want to work here. Thanks Jessica. Next, we have Carlos. Look, I bartended seven years. I really don't make mistakes anymore. I mean, I did way back when I was younger. I've owned up a few cags. I feel for a couple of counterfeit 20s but it's ancient history. Look, if I'm your new bartender, you can be confident that you're going to have a professional back there, someone who's seen it all. Who doesn't make mistakes. Thank you, Carlos. Hi, Sandra. You're up. Well, I went on my first catering jobs. I encorched all the wine before we started serving. But then most people drink fear. Okay. You know, this is an expense in the steak. So before the next party, I asked if I could shout on my boss that she set up. And I made a checklist so I would know what tasks to do in the right order. I still use that task. It probably would have played here. Thank you, Sandra. Jessica shared an honest mistake.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0152}
{"question": "But then what?", "answer": "Her answer fell flat because she didn't share what she learned. Carlos named two mistakes. But then he dismissed them. Maybe he could have shared how we mastered correctly tapping a keg or spying a fake 20. That would have been more effective. I thought Sandra's answer was great. She quickly explained the mistake, but spent most of her response talking about the stuff she took to overcome it. She even connect what she learned to this new role. Next up, round two. If you want to take your job search to the next level, click the link below and download the Indeed Mobile app.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you dealt with a difficult or tough situation at work.", "answer": "I think the toughest situation is when you don't know how to do something. See, I'm the type of person who likes to be in control. So I want to make sure that I know how to do every single task. When I first started at my sales job, I had to ask a million questions. For some people, that's hard, but not me. I'm not afraid to ask for help. Carlos, you're up. Just last month, one of my regulars had too much to drink. Now, if I serve in the toxicated patron who gets into an accident, I'm liable. But I had to stop serving him in a way that wouldn't escalate the situation. So I closed his tab. I got him a glass of water. And then I privately told him that he could stick around while he sobered up. Eventually I called a cab. I maintained his dignity. And I kept everyone safe because when you work at a bar, customer safety is a big part of customer service. I like what I'm hearing. Last but not least, Sandra. My first catering boss told me to keep serving drinks no matter how intoxicated someone gets. But I just didn't sit right with me. I once told this woman that she had enough to drink, but she just got her friend and to get her a drink instead. So since then, I figure the mangle to keep the customer happy. I mean, so if someone gets out of hand at your bar, I would ask the balancer to throw them out.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.022}
{"question": "There's the balancer, right? Right?", "answer": "That's a problem. I love Jessica's confidence. But she should share a specific example. The star method would help. Sandra shared a specific story, but her action didn't improve the situation. It just didn't seem like she was taking ownership. Carlos's answer had all four elements of the star method. When he said, I maintained his dignity and kept everyone safe, I understood exactly how he made a difficult situation better. It's time for the last round. Final question, we'll start off with Jessica.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.011}
{"question": "Explain a time when you had to multitask and how you handled it.", "answer": "So when I'm out with my friends, I'm always the person taking all our drink orders, just like a bartender. I go over everything at everyone once and I repeat it out loud to myself at least three times. When I get to the bar, I order draft beers first, then the mixed drinks. It gets confusing when people change their minds, though. Then you have to fix mistake and still keep track of everything. Okay, very cool. Carlos, you're up. Just last month, I had two of my barbex and a way to call out sick. I was taking orders. I was getting ice, making drinks, stocking. It was impossible. Multitasking, it can be really tough in in those situations. No one wins. Thanks Carlos. Sandra. Well, when you bartend at weddings, everyone wants to get a drink at the same time. During my first few gigs, I came up with three rules, number one. Always finish every order before taking the next one. Number two, to reduce the flow of new orders, I only make eye contact when I'm ready to take new orders. And three. I trust my system. So I'm polite, but firm if I'm getting counted. Since I started putting them into practice, I'm more calm. I make fear mistakes and have more fun catering weddings. Well done. Jessica's answer could have had all the star elements, but her action wasn't clear. And since she didn't share a clear action, she couldn't share its results.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0115}
{"question": "Carlos was specific and he did explain how we jumped in to save the day, but did the situation improve?", "answer": "Sandra gave context and clearly explained the challenge.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Bill?", "answer": "I think we're ready for your decision. These behavioral questions really help me get a sense of each candidate's past experiences. One contestant, consistently set the scene, told us the challenge, shared what they tried and explained what happened as a result. Sandra is the strongest candidate. That means Sandra moves forward in the interview process. Remember, if you're asked to behave your whole question at your next interview, apply the star method. It helps connect your past experience to the role you're applying for it. To those of you watching at home, don't forget to like and subscribe for more videos like this on our channel.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0179}
{"question": "Interview question number one is, how would you describe something technical to a non technical person?", "answer": "Let me give you two great tips for giving the perfect answer. Tip number one. Now this question is assessing your communication skills, your ability to communicate complex concepts to people who don't have the same level of knowledge as you. So in your answer, be sure to focus on describing how you would simplify your explanation to help the person better understand. Now in your answer, I strongly recommend you use a practical explanation of how you would describe something technical to someone who does not have the same level of knowledge as you. Here is my brilliant example answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0098}
{"question": "How would you describe something technical to a non technical person?", "answer": "When explaining something technical to someone who may not have the same background knowledge, I focus on simplifying the concept without oversimplifying it. For example, if I were explaining how the cloud works to a non technical person, I might say think of the cloud like a virtual storage room that you can access from anywhere as long as you have the key. Instead of storing your files on your computer, they're kept in this secure room on the internet. This way, if your computer breaks, your files are safe because they're stored in the cloud. This analogy helps convey the main idea without using complex jargon. I would also make sure to check if the person has any questions to clarify further. So that is a brilliant answer. It's such a good example answer because you are giving an example of how you would explain something technical to a non technical person so they fully understand. Let's move on to technical interview question number two.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0176}
{"question": "What problem solving process do you use when encountering bugs and issues?", "answer": "Let me give you two great tips. Tip number one. Problem solving will be a core assessment area in your technical job interview. So I recommend you utilize a five step process whenever solving technical problems. Here is that five step process. Number one, you should always identify and reproduce the issue or problem. Step number two, you then analyze the root cause step number three. You develop a solution step number four. You test the fix and finally step number five. You document the process so people can learn from it and also to make sure it doesn't happen again. So here is my brilliant example answer to technical job interview question number two.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0259}
{"question": "What problem solving process do you use when encountering bugs and issues?", "answer": "When encountering bugs or issues, I follow a five step structured problem solving process to identify and resolve them efficiently. In step one, I will identify and reproduce the will gather as much information as possible about the bug. I replicate the issue in a controlled environment to understand its behavior and ensure consistency in its occurrence. Step two, I analyze the root cause. I use debugging tools like logs, breakpoints or error messages to pinpoint where the problem originates. By tracing the code or reviewing system configurations, I narrow down potential causes. Step three, I develop a solution. Once I identify the root cause, I brainstorm and evaluate potential fixes ensuring the solution addresses the issue without introducing new bugs. Step four, I test the fix. After implementing the solution, I rigorously tested in different scenarios to confirm that the bug is resolved and that the system functions correctly. Finally, in step five, I document the process. I document the issue, it's cause, and the resolution steps for future reference, ensuring that the team can learn from the experience. This systematic approach allows me to tackle bugs effectively while minimizing downtime and maintaining system integrity. That is a brilliant answer and if you gave that level of response to me in a technical interview, I would be serious about offering you the position. Now, don't go anywhere because I still have many more tips, questions and sample answers to work through with you, but when you are ready, click the link in the top right hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website to passmaintovie.com and you can instantly download these slides plus my full set of 35 great answers to difficult technical job interview questions. But here is the next question that comes up all the time during technical interviews, but it catches lots of people out.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0032}
{"question": "And that question is, how many golf balls can you fit into a school bus?", "answer": "Now, upon the first examination, this seems like a really silly interview question, but there is a reason why lots of hiring managers like asking this question in technical interviews. Here are two important tips. Tip number one, this question assesses your logical thinking and problem solving capabilities. Now, to answer this question, you must make assumptions about the size of the golf ball and the size of the school bus. And tip number two, in your response, describe how you would calculate the volume of the golf ball and the capacity of the school bus before telling the interview at your estimated answer. Always remember, these type of technical difficult interview questions are not requiring you to give the perfect answer. It's about how you approached the problem that is being assessed here. So here is the perfect answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0213}
{"question": "How many golf balls can you fit into a school bus?", "answer": "I will assume a golf ball is about four centimeters in diameter, which gives it a volume of roughly 40 cubic centimeters. A standard school bus is approximately 10 meters long, two and a half meters wide and two meters tall, giving it a volume of about 50 cubic meters or 50 million cubic centimeters. Since golf balls don't pack perfectly, I'll estimate that only about 70% of the bus's space can be filled with them. So, the usable volume is 50 million times 70% which equals 35 million cubic centimeters. Dividing this by the volume of one golf ball, 35 million divided by 40 equals 875,000. Therefore, you could fit approximately 875,000 golf balls in a school bus. So that is a great answer because you are assuming the size of the golf ball and the size of a typical school bus. So you are approaching the problem in a logical way. Now, if you want to accelerate your learning even further and fully understand how to calculate the volume of a sphere which is a golf ball, you can watch that related video by clicking the link in the top right hand corner at any time during this tutorial. But here is an next technical interview question. I strongly recommend you prepare for.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0136}
{"question": "How would you collaborate with a difficult coworker?", "answer": "Again, this question comes up all the time during technical job interviews tip number one. Now, it is common to have disagreements with coworkers in technical job roles, especially when approaching technical based solutions. People who working tech are highly intelligent people. So sometimes there is a clash of personalities and a clash in the decision-making process. Now, in your answer, you must demonstrate an ability to respect your co-workers ideas to help achieve the team's objectives and tip number two. In your answer, demonstrate an ability to resolve conflicts amicably through calm, solution-based discussions that empower the team to achieve its technical goals. Here is the perfect answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0088}
{"question": "How would you collaborate with a difficult coworker?", "answer": "When collaborating with a difficult coworker, I focus on maintaining professionalism and finding common ground to work effectively. First, I make an effort to understand their perspective by listening carefully to their concerns or preferences. For example, if a coworker prefers a different approach to a task, I would ask questions to understand their reasoning and look for ways to align our goals. If disagreements arise, I keep the discussion, solution, focused, and avoid personal judgments. For instance, I might say, let's focus on the best way to achieve the team's objective, rather than debating who is right. I also ensure clear communication and set boundaries to keep the relationship respectful. Ultimately, my priority is a success of the project and the team, so I aim to foster collaboration through understanding patience and mutual respect. That is a great answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.007}
{"question": "Technical interview question number five is, why are manhole covers round?", "answer": "This is another silly question, but again, it is being asked for a specific reason. So manhole covers are often found in the road and they are round. They are round for several reasons.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0294}
{"question": "But what are those reasons?", "answer": "Let me give you two tips for giving the perfect answer. Tip number one, this technical interview question is common during technical interviews and these assesses your understanding of technical and engineering concepts. Manhole covers are round predominantly because they give greater structural integrity. Tip number two, in your answer, I also recommend you explain how round manhole covers do not fall into the hole, whereas rectangle or square ones can, which can cause dangerous situations. So here is the perfect answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0122}
{"question": "Why are manhole covers round?", "answer": "Manhole covers are round for several practical and engineering reasons. First, around shape ensures that the cover cannot fall through the opening regardless of how it is positioned. This is because a circle has a constant diameter on like a square or rectangular cover that could call through it if inserted diagonally. Second, around shape is easier to roll, which makes it more practical for transportation and handling by workers. Additionally, circles distribute weight evenly, which enhances their structural integrity when supporting heavy loads like vehicles. And lastly, manufacturing a circular cover is often simpler and requires less precise alignment when placing it back on the opening saving time and reducing potential errors in maintenance. That is the perfect answer to that common technical interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0159}
{"question": "Why are manhole covers round? Technical interview question number six, what are the essential skills and qualities needed to work in tech job roles?", "answer": "Tip number one. Now before your technical interview, I strongly recommend, you read the job description. And in your answer, you should talk about technical skills and soft skills. In technical roles to be successful, you must have good, soft and interpersonal skills. Tip number two, in your answer, be sure to include critical thinking, adaptability, collaboration and communication. Here is the perfect answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What are the essential skills and qualities needed to work in tech roles?", "answer": "Here we go. To work in tech roles effectively, both technical and soft skills are crucial. On the technical side, a strong foundation in problem solving and programming languages like Python, Java or C++ is essential. For mediarity with databases, algorithms and software development tools is also important, depending on the role. On the soft skills side, critical thinking and adaptability are vital, because the tech industry is constantly evolving. Collaboration is key, as most tech projects involve teamwork across different departments. Strong communication skills help explain technical ideas to non-technical stakeholders. And lastly, a willingness to learn and stay updated with emerging technologies is critical to staying relevant and contributing effectively to team projects. Again, that is a brilliant answer. You can see how all of these responses are going to help you post your technical job interview. Technical question number seven, tell me about a time you have to deal with an ethical dilemma. This is a tricky question. Tip number one, ethical dilemmas are common placing technical teams. Now, this question assesses honesty, professionalism and integrity. In your answer, demonstrate your understanding of how important it is to do the right thing. That is what this question is assessing. Your desire to do the right thing in your work. Tip number two, I also strongly advise you use the star method to structure your answer. So, begin your response and outline the situation you were in. You will then talk about the task that needed your attention. You will then give in depth details about the action you took before finally telling the interview at the result following your actions. Here is my brilliant example answer that uses the star method.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.007}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had to deal with an ethical dilemma.", "answer": "Here we go. In a previous role, I was working on a team where I discovered that a colleague had overlooked a crucial step in testing before deploying an update to a live system. Although the colleague assured me it was a minor issue, I knew it had the potential to call significant problems for our clients. I faced an ethical dilemma, whether to report the issue and potentially create conflict with my colleague or let it slide to avoid confrontation. I decided to approach the situation professionally and transparently. I discussed my concerns with the colleague privately, explaining the potential risks and suggesting that we review the deployment together. After our conversation, they agreed to revisit the testing process and we found a bug that could have led to significant downtime. This experience reinforced my belief in the importance of integrity and clear communication in the workplace. Addressing the issue not only prevented a potential problem, but also strengthened our working relationship. That is a brilliant example answer that uses the star method of situation task, action and result is a brilliant response. Technical interview question number eight.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How do you handle tight deadlines while working on a technical based project?", "answer": "Tip number one. As you are already aware, you will be expected to manage your workload independently in your tech role. So this question assesses organizing, prioritising and time management capabilities. So in your answer, focus on the following three key areas. Planning, prioritisation and communication. Here is the perfect answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0392}
{"question": "How do you handle tight deadlines while working on a technical based project?", "answer": "When faced with tight deadlines on a technical project, I focus on planning, prioritisation and communication to ensure successful delivery. First, I break the project down into smaller, manageable tasks and prioritise them based on their impact and dependencies. I often use a traffic light system for prioritisation, red tasks, our urgent and come first. Orange tasks are second and green tasks can be left for later in the working day. This helps me stay organized and focus on what matters most. Second, I utilize project management tools like Jira or Trello to track progress and ensure deadlines are met. Time management is key. So I allocate dedicated time blocks for deep work, minimizing distractions during critical phases of the project. I also ensure clear communication with the team and stakeholders. For instance, if a potential roadblock arises, I inform the relevant parties early to collaboratively find solutions. Finally, I stay flexible and adapt quickly if priority shift or unexpected challenges arise. This approach has consistently helped me deliver high quality work even under tight deadlines. That is a professional brilliant answer that demonstrates your ability to plan, prioritize and complete your work on time while communicating properly. The next question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.01}
{"question": "How do you keep your technical knowledge up to date?", "answer": "Tip number one. Now all technical job roles require a commitment to take ownership of continuous professional development. Now because tech is constantly evolving, make sure you have a plan for how you are going to maintain competence in your work. So here's a different number of things you can do to maintain technical competence. You can subscribe to technical blogs and newsletters, complete online training courses, attend networking events and also participate in online tech communities. Here is the perfect answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.012}
{"question": "How do you keep your technical knowledge up to date?", "answer": "The tech industry evolves rapidly so I make a conscious effort to stay current. I regularly follow industry news and trends by subscribing to blogs, podcasts and newsletters from reputable sources like TechCrunch, Stack Overflow and GitHub updates. I also take online courses on platforms like Coursera, Udemy and LinkedIn Learning to learn about emerging technologies or enhance my existing skills. For example, I recently completed a course on cloud computing to better understand AWS services. Additionally, I participate in online tech communities and forums such as redits, tech subredits and specialized communities on discord to engage in discussions and learn from other professionals. I also enjoy attending webinars, conferences and meet-ups to network, amgain insights into the latest innovations. This approach helps me stay ahead of changes ensuring I can effectively contribute to projects and bring value to my team. That's a great answer. Technical interview question number 10 that needs a confident answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0191}
{"question": "What are your salary expectations in this tech role?", "answer": "Let me give you two important tips. Tip number one, it is vital. You research the salary range for your tech role before the interview. Now I recommend you research technical salaries on glassdoor.com. Make sure also you practice your answer several times before the interview so you are confident in the salary negotiation. Now the answer I am about to give you includes several salary figures all you have to do is conduct your own research on glassdoor.com and then alter the figures for your tech job role and industry. Here it is.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0104}
{"question": "What are your salary expectations in this tech role?", "answer": "Based on my research and understanding of the role, I believe the salary range for this position typically falls between $65,000 and $75,000 per year. Given my qualifications, experience, proficiency in and then insert any areas of expertise you have, and the value I can bring to your team, I would be comfortable with a salary of $72,000 and the opportunity to have an annual review based on my contribution to the company's commercial objectives for $72,000, I will ensure you receive an excellent return. So that is a really good answer. You have found out, you have researched the salary range and you are then asking for a salary that is just below the higher end of that range and you are justifying why they should give it to you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0074}
{"question": "Don't forget to include in your response the areas of expertise or proficiency you can bring to their team. Now at the end of your technical job interview, you will have the opportunity to ask some questions of your own but which questions should you ask?", "answer": "So the hiring manager will say that's the end of your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0769}
{"question": "Do you have any questions for us?", "answer": "Here are the questions I recommend you write down on a sheet of paper, take them with you to the interview and ask them. Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "How is the technical team structured and how does this role fit within it? How does the company approach innovation and staying ahead of new technology trends and how does the company support professional development such as training, certifications or attending conferences?", "answer": "That is a great selection of three brilliant questions I recommend you ask at the end of your technical interview. Now the next thing to do is click the link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website to passmaintevue.com and you can instantly download my full set of 35 great answers to difficult technical interview questions. You can have this guide in your inbox literally within two minutes from now, make sure you check out my website.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget to hit the subscribe button.", "answer": "Please give the video a like and make sure you connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an absolute pleasure and an honor to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you for watching and I wish you all the very best for passing your interview. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0308}
{"question": "Why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "It is highly valued and building a long-term career at Amazon has always been my number one goal. Amazon has long been the market leader in numerous industries. This tells me Amazon is an organisation that is continually progressing delivers world-class products and services and provides customer service that outperforms its competitors. I will be pushed and challenged in my work at Amazon and my ideas will be valued and listened to. I want to work for Amazon because the leadership principles are a set of values and standards I genuinely believe in, and the inclusive workplace culture means there is opportunity for everyone.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a tie you demonstrated, one of Amazon's leadership principles at work.", "answer": "The following example is based on the leadership principle of customer obsession. A team member had failed to contact a customer when they had contacted the company to complain about a faulty product. The customer was understandably annoyed and they had left a negative review online. It was my task to turn around their experience, result the complaint fully and retain their customer. I contacted the customer immediately, apologized sincerely, and told them I would feel the same as them if the situation had happened to me. I gave the customer time to speak about their experience. I then explained what I was going to do to put things right after I had asked them questions to gain full clarity of the issue. I told the customer I would contact them within the next 24 hours after I had concluded my investigation. After I had resolved the customers complaint and issued them with a new product, I informed my manager about the situation so they could provide remedial training to the staff member who had let the customer down.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0056}
{"question": "Tell me about a tie when you found a simple solution to a challenging problem.", "answer": "In my previous job, we had an ongoing problem with communication. Update some projects and task delegation were becoming increasingly difficult as the company expanded. So I decided to find a simple solution to this difficult problem. After researching online for the best workplace communication and productivity tools, I put together a short presentation on a software tool called Evernote. Evernote would empower managers and team members to keep everyone updated on task and project progression. After watching my presentation, my manager agreed to its implementation. Within several weeks, Evernote became a fundamental part of our workplace productivity, virtual and task management and communication improved significantly as a result.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0092}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you were able to influence change in an organisation by only asking questions.", "answer": "In my last job, I attended a meeting to discuss the environmental impact our company was having. I had several ideas for making improvements. It was my task to influence a positive change by asking three specific questions which I had already prepared.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "The questions I asked were, have we considered how much waste we were generating? Do we think we could be more environmentally friendly in our office practices and have we ever considered implementing a recycling program?", "answer": "The three questions resulted in a healthy debate. I then presented a recycling idea to my manager and she agreed it was a really positive step forward. After my idea was implemented, we reduced company waste by 75% and everyone in the company adopted a more responsible approach to waste.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Why should we hire you to work at Amazon?", "answer": "You should hire me because I am deeply committed to the principle of customer obsession. Throughout my career, I have prioritised customer centricity consistently striving to meet their needs. Additionally, you should hire me because of my unwavering commitment to ownership, which means I take full responsibility for my work and difficult challenges. I will embrace Amazon's culture of innovation and simplification through a proactive approach to my work and actively seek ways to improve processes. My insistence on the highest standards and my ability to think big align perfectly with Amazon's pursuit of excellence. Finally, you should hire me because my deep alignment with Amazon's 16 leadership principles makes me an ideal candidate to contribute to the organisations on going growth and success. OK, in this next section of the training video, I will give you those brilliant top scoring answers to write down to help you prepare for your own Amazon interview. If at any point you want to simply download all of the answers, you can click that link at any time. Here we go. OK, so the first question I was asked during my practice Amazon interview was, tell me about yourself. Here is that brilliant example answer I gave.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0048}
{"question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answer": "Thank you for this opportunity. I have always been passionate about combining innovation with customer centricity and that's why I'm excited about the prospect of working for Amazon. My skills, qualities and work ethic are a great match for your leadership principles. In my previous role, I worked on a team that successfully launched a game-changing product by embodying the think big principle. We identified emerging market trends and then created a brilliant product that gave the company an excellent return on their investment. Throughout my career, I've consistently exhibited ownership by taking responsibility for both successes and setbacks. For example, when we lost two team members during a critical deadline project, I stepped up, rallied the team, and redistributed tasks to ensure we delivered the project with uncompromising quality. I'm genuinely excited about the opportunity to contribute to Amazon's relentless pursuit of satisfaction and innovation and believe my commitment to your leadership principles will enable me to thrive in this dynamic environment. I look forward to sharing further details in the interview as to my suitability for this position. That is a brilliant answer that you can use when preparing for your own Amazon interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget, at any stage, you can click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video, head straight through to my website, pastmaintevue.com, and download all of the answers. So the second question I was asked at my practice Amazon interview was, why do you want to work for Amazon?", "answer": "Here is that brilliant example answer I gave. Getting hired and building a long-term career at Amazon has always been my number one goal. Amazon has long been the market leader in numerous industries. This tells me Amazon is an organisation that is continually progressing, delivers world-class products and services and provides customer service that outperforms its competitors. I will be pushed and challenged in my work at Amazon and my ideas will be valued and listened to. I want to work for Amazon because the leadership principles are a set of values and standards I genuinely believe in and the inclusive workplace culture means there is opportunity for everyone. I love that answer because you are talking about how great Amazon is in respect of customer service that means it outperforms its competitors and you are also saying at the start that you want to build a long-term career at Amazon. That's a really strong answer. Again you can use it when preparing for your own Amazon interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "The next question was, what is called a behavioral interview question?", "answer": "That question was, tell me about a time you demonstrated one of Amazon's leadership principles at work. Therefore you have to learn and understand Amazon's 16 leadership principles in order to answer this correctly. Now here is that great answer I gave. The following example is based on the leadership principle of customer obsession. The team member had failed to respond to a customer when they had contacted the company to complain about a faulty product. The customer was understandably annoyed and they had left a negative review online. It was my task to turn around their experience, resolve the complaint fully and then retain their custom. I contacted the customer immediately, apologized sincerely and told them I would feel the same as them if the situation had happened to me. I gave the customer time to speak about their experience. Then explained what I was going to do to put things right after I had asked them questions to gain full clarity of the issue. I told the customer I would contact them within the next 24 hours after I had concluded my investigation. After I'd resolved the customers complaint and issued them with a new product, I informed my manager about the situation so they could provide remedial training to the staff member who had let the customer down. That is a really good example answer where I am talking about a specific situation I had previously been in where I demonstrated the leadership principle of customer obsession. Another really good tip for answering the Amazon leadership principles, behavioral questions, is to make sure you use a start technique when responding to those questions. So start stands for situation task action and result. You give details of the situation you were in. You then tell the interviewer the task that needed doing. You then give in depth details about the action you took to achieve the task. And then finally, you tell the interviewer the results following your actions. I'll make sure you use a start technique when answering the Amazon behavioral interview questions. Now the next question I had to answer in my Amazon practice interview was, tell me about a time when you found a simple solution to a challenging problem. Here is that brilliant example answer I gave. In my previous job we had an ongoing problem with communication. I ate some projects and task delegation were becoming increasingly difficult as the company expanded. So I decided to find a simple solution to this difficult problem. After researching online for the best workplace communication and productivity tools, I put together a short presentation on a software tool called Evernote. Evernote would empower managers and team members to keep everyone updated on task and project progression. After watching my presentation, my manager agreed to its implementation. Within several weeks, Evernote became a fundamental part of our workplace productivity schedule and task management and communication improved significantly as a result. So that is another really good answer that's going to help you prepare fully for your Amazon interview. Now the next question is another Amazon behavioral interview question that is focused on how you have previously demonstrated the leadership principles. This question was, tell me about a time when you were able to influence change in an organisation by only asking questions. This is a really difficult one. But here's that brilliant answer I gave. In my last job, I attended a meeting to discuss the environmental impact our company was having. I had several ideas for making improvements. It was my task to influence a positive change by asking three specific questions which I had already prepared.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0065}
{"question": "The questions I asked were, have we considered how much waste we were generating? Do we think we could be more environmentally friendly in our office practices and have we ever considered implementing a recycling program?", "answer": "The three questions resulted in a healthy debate. I then presented a recycling idea to my manager and she agreed it was a positive step forward. Now after my idea was implemented, we reduced company waste by 75% and everyone in the company adopted a more responsible approach to waste. That's a great example situation where I was in a team meeting asked three specific situations which then resulted in a healthy conversation and positive changes to the organisation's working practices.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Now the next question was, why should we hire you to work at Amazon?", "answer": "Here is that great in-depth answer I gave. You should hire me because I am deeply committed to the principle of customer obsession. Throughout my career, I have prioritised customer centricity consistently striving to meet their needs. Additionally, you should hire me because of my unwavering commitment to ownership, which means I take full responsibility for my work and difficult challenges. I will embrace Amazon's culture of innovation and simplification through a proactive approach to my work and actively seek ways to improve your processes. My insistence on the highest standards and my ability to think big align perfectly with Amazon's pursuit of excellence. Finally, you should hire me because my deep alignment with Amazon's 16 leadership principles makes me an ideal candidate to contribute to the organisation's ongoing growth and success. That's a great answer because it's in-depth. You are also talking about the leadership principles which you are going to have to learn and understand before you attend your Amazon interview. In the description below the video, I have provided you with more links to great training videos right here on YouTube that will help you understand those 16 leadership principles and answer more types of questions that you will encounter during your Amazon interview. So don't forget to check out that links. The next thing to do to accelerate your learning even further is make sure you click that link right now in the top right-hand corner of the video. Head straight through to my website, passwayinterview.com and you can download all of my top 21 brilliant exam palancers to difficult Amazon interview questions. You will get all of the answers I have provided you today in that practice interview and the slides. Plus more, example responses that will help you prepare fully for your Amazon interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0032}
{"question": "Don't forget, Amazon is probably the greatest organisation in the world.", "answer": "In my opinion, they are one of the best companies to work for. With his worth putting in that extra effort to make sure you pass your interview. Amazon interviews are different from other types of interviews because you have to give in-depth answers to convince them you have what it takes to succeed. So make sure you check out that link in the top right-hand corner of the video. Go through to my website and you can download all of my resources that will help you pass your Amazon interview. Go for get to hit the subscribe button as you can probably tell thousands of people. I mean thousands are passing their interviews and Amazon interviews at the first attempt. I can only help you if you are subscribed. Please hit the like button because that really does motivate me to create more great content for you. And don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always a pleasure and an honour to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you so much for watching and for supporting my channel. I wish you all the best, the very best for passing your Amazon interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0229}
{"question": "Describe your most difficult customer and how you handle them.", "answer": "A customer contacted me one day to ask for a refund because they were not happy with their purchase. Now unfortunately they informed me they did not have a receipt and because they had paid cash for the product. There was no way I could track their order. I apologized but explained that I was not able to refund their order as this was against company policy. Now the customer started to become angry and they threatened to leave a negative review online. It was my task to remain calm and find a solution for the customer they were happy with. I maintained my stance relating to the fact I could not refund their order.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "However, I suggested to the customer that they could either have a replacement product or they could receive a credit note against a future purchase.", "answer": "I then asked several questions about the type of product they wanted before suggesting alternative products we had available that would be more suited to their needs. Eventually the customer calmed down and agreed to exchange their purchase for a product they really wanted. The customer then went online and left a glowing five-star review, citing my professionalism and attentiveness whilst dealing with their situation. That's a really good example answer. It's a specific situation I was in when dealing with a difficult customer. I explained how I handled them. That uses a star technique and you can see there how effective the starting technique is Now don't go anywhere because I still have more questions and answers to give you that are brilliant preparation for your Amazon interview. But when you're ready you can click the link in the top right hand corner of the video head through to my website pastmaintv.com and you can download my full set of Amazon leadership principles interview questions and brilliant example answers including the ones we are working through together today. But here's an next question. Given example of a time when you went above and beyond to meet a deadline now this is focused on the leadership principle of deliver results. Remember deliver results is a simple leadership principle but very important nonetheless always deliver on time and to the right standard. Here's my example answer that utilizes the star technique. Given example of a time when you went above and beyond to meet a deadline here we go. In my last role I was working on an important project for a company client. Now the project team consisted of six people however, two thirds of the way through the project two team members went off sick with COVID. This situation had the potential to delay the project by several weeks but this was something I wasn't prepared to allow happen. It was my task to come up with a solution to the problem. I re-evaluated the project goals and determined that some of the work could be outsourced to online contractors. This proved to be a shrewd move because the contractors I ended up hiring had exceptional skills and they were able to improve the quality of project work that was being delivered. For the remainder of the project I also agreed to commit to extra working hours each evening to ensure it was completed on time. I ended up working an additional 17 hours in the evenings leading up to the project deadline to make sure it was finished on time until they expected standard. Now because of this experience I also learned the skill of hiring outsourcers which we utilized in the company on future projects. As a number really good answer it shows that you make sure you deliver results as per the leadership principle and you also learn a new skill along the way which is a great one because it shows that you are always learning another really important leadership principle at Amazon. The next Amazon leadership principle interview question I want to work through is tell me about a time when you helped a team or company to save money. So this is about through Galatie. Remember Amazon wants its employees to not just help grow the business but help it to save money too. This is a difficult question but here's my example answer to help you.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0017}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you helped a team or company to save money.", "answer": "Here's my response that uses that star technique here we go. In my previous role I was concerned about how much we were spending on delivery costs. Every day we were sending out hundreds of orders to customers but our delivery company did not appear to be providing value for money. It was my task to evaluate our delivery expenses to see if I could save the company money. I spent the next three hours conducting an analysis of the past 12 months delivery costs and I was staggered at how expensive they were. Now even though the number of orders we were sending out via our delivery company had literally doubled their prices had increased by a third. So I decided to call the delivery company area manager to explain my concerns and to negotiate a fairer price. After a half hour on the telephone outlining my concerns he agreed to reduce the delivery fees back to their previous price for the next 12 months which ended up saving the company more than $5,000 in total. That's a great example answer. It shows that you take ownership another leadership principle. It shows that you care about the company because you are finding ways to help save money and increase company profits. Great answer. Here's the next question. Give an example of a time when you didn't see I2I with a work calling. This is a trick you want. So this is based on the leadership principle of a backbone, disagree and commit. So remember, Amazon is fine to disagree and have an opinion and if you think something's wrong you should speak up but you must commit to the agreed way of working. Here's my example answer to help you. Give an example of a time when you didn't see I2I with a work colleague. Here we go. I was in a team meeting discussing the launch of a new company product. Now a colleague of mine was adamant the best way for us to promote the product was through local newspaper adverts. I disagreed. It was my task to explain using facts and evidence why the best way to promote the new product would be through online advertising. After listening to his arguments for promoting the product in local newspapers I explained that we had a better chance of converting sales by targeting people online by age, gender, demographics and interests. I showed him an example of how a company had been able to surpass all previous company launches by shifting their advertising online. I also explained that we could track the return on advertising investment if we advertised online. Something that was not possible using newspaper adverts. After listening to my reason argument he agreed my suggestion was more beneficial to the new product launch you did a 37% increase in sales compared with previous launches. As a great example of that Amazon leadership principle have backbone, disagree and then commit. So you are saying that you disagree with him and you are explaining why you think that's not the best way to proceed using facts and evidence and you are then persuading the person to choose your way forward. You are all then committing and there is a brilliant outcome for the company in terms of that 37% increase in sales. It's a great example. Now this is another Amazon leadership principle interview question that comes up a lot. It's a difficult one to answer.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0068}
{"question": "What is your favorite Amazon leadership principle?", "answer": "Well you have 16 to choose from. Here's how I would personally answer this question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "What is your favorite Amazon leadership principle?", "answer": "Here we go. My favorite leadership principle is customer obsession. I decided I wanted to work for Amazon after buying many products from your website. Your levels of customer service were always outstanding and I was hugely impressed with your speed of delivery. This made me realise that so many companies out there have it wrong when it comes to customer service. They appear to focus too much on their competitors instead of focusing on their customers. If a company focuses on their customers they won't need to worry about competitors because customers will stay with them for the long term. Now whilst all of the leadership principles are very important, Amazon would be nothing without the customer and that's the reason why it is my first choice. That's a great answer and you are explaining the reasons why you have chosen your particular Amazon leadership principle. So the next thing to do don't forget to click the link in the top right-hand corner of the video right now. Head through to my website, passmaintv.com and you can instantly download my full set of Amazon leadership principles, interview questions and example answers. It's a fantastic resource you can have it in your inbox literally within two minutes from now. I'm actually going to check that out.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0134}
{"question": "Don't forget to tell me in the comments section below the video which job you are applying for at Amazon.", "answer": "I will also give you another video to watch and learn from.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Don't forget to subscribe to the channel.", "answer": "We'll see you all the best for passing your Amazon job interview. Have a great day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time when you had to manage conflicting priorities.", "answer": "Now this is undoubtedly one of the hardest interview questions to answer correctly but if you have a job interview coming up for any role or any organisation stay tuned because I will give you the perfect answer. And just very quickly if you are new to the channel please do make sure you hit the subscribe button because I can then keep you updated. We've all the latest interview tips and top scoring answers and please give the video a like. That tells me you find these tutorials useful. Thank you very much for your support. Let's jump straight into the presentation. So to help you pass your interview I will cover three things during this tutorial. Number one I will explain why the hiring manager is asking you the interview question tell me about a time when you had to manage conflicting priorities. Number two I will explain how to structure your answer to gain the highest scores possible and number three I will give you two example outstanding responses. So to begin with why is the interview are asking you the question tell me about a time when you had to manage conflicting priorities. Well number one the role you are applying for will require you to manage multiple important tasks and priorities. Now if you already have experience of managing conflicting priorities you are definitely going to be a good fit for the role. And number two if you are able to manage conflicting priorities it tells the interviewer you are organized resilient and you are the type of person who will never crumble under pressure. Now before I give you two top scoring answers let me tell you how to structure your response to the difficult interview question tell me about a time when you had to manage conflicting priorities. Now my advice is to use the start technique to structure your answer. So you start off a new telly interviewer the situation you were faced with. You then move on and explain the task that needed doing. You then give specific details about the action you took before finishing off with the results of your actions. So let me now give you two example answers to the interview question tell me about a time when you had to manage conflicting priorities. Please tell me in the comments section below the video which answer option you think is the strongest. Here's example number one answer option number one tell me about a time when you had to manage conflicting priorities here we go. In my previous role I volunteered to help out on a project that was in danger of failing. Now in addition to this work I also had my regular duties to complete. It was my task to successfully manage all conflicting priorities to ensure everything was finished on time. I started out by speaking to the team members who were working on the failing project. I assessed the priorities of this project and suggested ways I could contribute to the team's objectives. I also analyzed my own workload and I drew up a list of which tasks were urgent and how long they would take me to complete. This gave me a perfect picture of the work I needed to do for both the project and my own responsibilities. Now to manage the conflicting priorities I stayed behind late for an hour each day after work and I met up regularly with the project team members to ensure progress was being made and that we had the necessary resources to get everything finished. Now after two weeks of working on the project and by prioritising my own task I was able to effectively manage all conflicting priorities much to the satisfaction of my manager. Example answer number two tell me about a time when you had to manage conflicting priorities here we go. In my previous job my manager asked for a volunteer to do the work of a team member who was going to be off sick for several weeks. I volunteered to be that person. It was my responsibility to manage both my own workload and the workload of my coworker to ensure all conflicting priorities were managed effectively. I started out by drawing up a list of the responsibilities I would have for both roles putting each task in order of priority. I then calculated how much time each task would take to complete and I set to work. I dealt with all customer service responsibilities first as I felt these were the priority before taking care of administrative duties answering internal queries, responding to emails and maintaining stock levels. To prevent deadlines from getting missed I stayed behind late after work as and when required. By using a structured approach to all tasks and responsibilities I'm by being flexible with my working hours I was able to successfully manage all conflicting priorities. So there is two brilliant example answers to that really difficult interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0071}
{"question": "Don't forget to tell me in the comment section below which answer option you think is the strongest thank you very much.", "answer": "If you want to accelerate your learning even further make sure you click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. Head through to my website passmaintovue.com and you can download my full set of 50 top scoring answers to difficult interview questions. It comes as a PDF guide which means you can have it within your inbox within two minutes from now and it's going to help make you be the standout candidate at your job Finally don't forget to subscribe and please do hit the like button because that motivates me to create more videos for you and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It's always great to connect with like minded professionals. Thank you very much for your support and I wish you all the best for passing your interview have a brilliant day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0124}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you faced a challenging situation at work.", "answer": "In my previous role I was responsible for coordinating the launch of a new product. One week before the launch a key supplier in founders they could not deliver the products packaging due to unforeseen circumstances. My task was to ensure the product launch proceeded on schedule despite the setback as the delay would have impacted our marketing campaign and customer expectations. I immediately convened a team meeting to brainstorm solutions and identify potential alternative suppliers. I reached out to alternative suppliers and chose the one that could deliver the required packaging on time. And simultaneously I communicate to transparently with stakeholders about the issue and our contingency plan. As a result of my swift actions we secured a new supplier who delivered the packaging on time. The product launch went ahead as scheduled and it turned out to be one of the most successful launches of the year exceeding sales targets by 15%. The behavioral interview question number two again comes up all the time in job interviews and that is tell me about a time when you had to work with a difficult coworker. Now this is a really tricky question to answer correctly. The question itself evaluates two things. Number one, your interpersonal skills. That is your ability to get on with anyone in your team and the question also evaluates your conflict resolution skills. That is why it is vital in your answer you demonstrate how you overcome the conflict with your coworker for the team's benefit. So here is my brilliant star method example answer right this down and practice it before your interview.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0037}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had to work with a difficult team member.", "answer": "While working on a team project to design a new company website one of the team members consistently missed deadlines and resisted adopting the collaborative tools we had agreed to use. My responsibility was to ensure the project stayed on track while fostering a positive team dynamic and addressing the issues with this team member. I scheduled a one-on-one conversation with the team member to understand their concerns. During our discussion I discovered they were unfamiliar with the tools and they felt overwhelmed. I offered to provide a quick training session and created a step-by-step guide to help navigate the tools more easily. Additionally, I checked regularly to offer support and ensure they stayed aligned with the project goals. Over time the team member became more comfortable with the tools and began contributing on time. The project was completed ahead of schedule and the improved collaboration strengthened our team's overall performance and the functionality of the new website. Avaloral interview question number three that comes up all the time is tell me about a time when you had to work as a team. This is one of the most common behavioral interview questions. The reason why the hiring manager is asking you this question is because you will have to work as part of a team in your job role. If you can't work as a team, they will not hire you. That is why you have to give a brilliant power for answer. Now these behavioral questions are value-wate two things. Number one, your ability to collaborate with anybody. Number two, it evaluates your communication skills because if you are going to work as part of a team successfully, you must be a good communicator. So here is my brilliant example answer to that question that uses the star method.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0032}
{"question": "Tell me about your time you had to work as a team.", "answer": "In my previous role, our team was tasked with organizing an annual company event that involved over 200 attendees. Each member was assigned different responsibilities from logistics to guest coordination. My role was to oversee the venue arrangements and then show smooth communication among all team members to avoid any overlaps or gaps in planning. I created a shared project timeline and facilitated weekly check-ins to track progress. I also encouraged open communication so team members could voice challenges early. Additionally, I collaborated with another team member to resolve a last-minute issue with the catering service. The event went off without a hitch, receiving excellent feedback from attendees and senior management. Our teamwork and coordination were specifically highlighted as key factors in its success. Behavioral interview question number four is, tell me about a time when you made a mistake. Now, the majority of candidates respond to this question by saying, I have never made a mistake because I am a perfectionist. That is not the way to answer this question. This question is assessing two things. Number one, honesty. Because we all make mistakes but you have to be honest about them. So give the hiring manager an example of when you made a mistake and you owned up to it. This question also evaluates your desire for self-improvement. So in your answer, tell the hiring manager what the mistake was, say that you took ownership of it and you then worked hard to self-improve. Here is my brilliant example response.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0117}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you made a mistake.", "answer": "Early in my career, I accidentally sent an email with incorrect pricing information to several key clients. It was my responsibility to correct the error and ensure it did not damage client relationships or the company's reputation. As soon as I realised the mistake, I immediately informed my manager and drafted a follow-up email to apologise and clarify the correct pricing. I also personally called the client to explain the situation and answer any questions. Additionally, I reviewed our email approval process and suggested improvements to prevent similar errors in the future. The clients appreciated my prompt and transparent communication. None of them decided to withdraw their business and the updated approval process I implemented significantly reduced errors in subsequent communications. The behavioral interview question at number five is, tell me about a time when you had to work under pressure. This is another difficult interview question to answer correctly. These questions evaluate two things. Number one, your speed of work. That is your ability to get your task responsibilities and projects completed in a timely manner even when you are under pressure. The question also evaluates resilience and calmness. Because if you are going to be able to work under pressure, you have to work diligently and calmly while working at speed. So let me now give you a brilliant example answer to this behavioral interview question.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0043}
{"question": "Tell me about your time when you had to work under pressure that uses the star method.", "answer": "Here we go.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0}
{"question": "Tell me about a time you had to work under pressure.", "answer": "During the holiday season in my previous retail role, our store experienced an unexpected surge in foot traffic resulting in long cues and a shortage of staff. My task was to manage the situation efficiently ensuring customers had a positive experience despite the challenges. I quickly prioritised tasks, delegating responsibilities to available staff members and stepping in to assist with customer service. I also communicated with customers in the queue, offering updates and providing small gestures like complementary refreshments to ease their frustration. Until, tangiously, I contacted part-time employees to see if they could come in on short notice. The situation was managed effectively and several customers complimented our team's professionalism despite the pressure. Sales for the day exceeded expectations and customer satisfaction remained high. Okay, now in this next section of the training video, I'm going to tell you how you can instantly download my brilliant answers to behavioral interview questions that use the star method. Here we go. The next thing to do if you wanted download my brilliant star method answers to difficult behavioral interview questions is click that link right now in the top right hand corner of the video. And straight through to my website, pass my interview.com and you can instantly download these slides plus my full set of 27 brilliant answers to tell me about a time behavioral interview questions. These sample answers are structured using the star method and they are guaranteed to impress in any job interview. If you want the guide, click that link right now.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.0038}
{"question": "Don't forget to hit the subscribe button.", "answer": "I am here to help you pass every job interview and progress throughout your career. I can only do those things if you are subscribed, please hit the like button and don't forget to connect with me on LinkedIn. I have put my LinkedIn link in the description below the video. It is always an honour and a pleasure to connect with like-minded professionals such as yourself. Thank you very much for watching and I wish you the very best for passing your job interview. Have a wonderful day.", "situation": "", "task": "", "action": "", "result": "", "quality": null, "clarity": 0.022}
